<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="49"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[1  EXTENSION



                                                  Table of Contents

               INTRODUCTION ........................................................................................................................2
               WELL DEFINED OBJECTIVES ...................................................................................................3
                  EXTENSION ACTIVITIES TO ACHIEVE OBJECTIVES ..........................................................4

               SYSTEMATIC AND EFFECTIVE PROCEDURES ..................................................................... 36
               REASONABLE BUDGET .......................................................................................................... 42
               PROVISIONS OF MATERIALS AND OTHER RESOURCES .................................................... 44
               PARTICIPATION OF STAKEHOLDERS .................................................................................... 45
               RECOGNITION AND BEST PRACTICES ................................................................................. 47



























































                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[2  EXTENSION



               INTRODUCTION


                       Statement of vision illustrates the bigger future of what an organization want to achieve,


               while the mission statement serves as a roadmap on how an organization will achieve its purpose

               and  identity  its  core  values,  and  its  reason  for  existence. The  goals,  on  the  other  hand,  are

               particular statements toward achieving what it wants within a timeframe. It is a milestone in the

               process  of  implementing  a  strategy.  These  are  critical  statements  for  the  organization  to

               strategically attain its mandate.


                       Service is one of the three tenets by which Cavite State University (CvSU) stands. In

               response to the mandate stipulated in Section 90 of Republic Act 8425, CvSU through UGNAYAN

               2.0 (Appendix A) commits its self to deliver extension services to elevate the standard of living of

               the economically and socially disadvantaged sectors and to sustain the development of a self-

               reliant communities. Having considered the national, regional and provincial agenda, resulted to

               the involvement of the University in the improvement of the lives of farmers, women, out-of-school

               youths, local government employees and other clients through the conduct of relevant education


               and  training;  farm  and  business  advisory  services;  demonstration  services;  and  information,

               communication and technology services.






























                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[3  EXTENSION



               WELL DEFINED OBJECTIVES


                       The College of Engineering and Information Technology (CEIT) commits itself to provide


               technological, economical, and social development in the lives of the people in the surrounding

               communities, especially to the people of its adopted barangay through its quality and relevant

               extension  programs  under  the  CEIT  Ugnayan  2.0:  Kaalaman,  Kabuhayan  at  Kapaligiran  sa

               Barangay  (Appendix  B). The  program  is  aligned  to  the  thematic  areas  of  smart  engineering,

               information  and  communications  technology  (ICT)  and  industrial  competitiveness,  social


               development and equality, biodiversity and environmental conservation, and agri-fisheries and

               food security covering the 13 course offerings of the College.    The CEIT Ugnayan 2.0 is divided

               into  three  major  components:  capability  building  through  seminars  and  trainings;  technology

               transfer;  and  technical  services.  It  aims  to  provide  hands-on  learning  opportunities,  provide

               relevant  basic  education,  and  develop  transferable  skills  and  competencies  to  the  interested

               stakeholders  of  the  adopted  barangay  and  nearby  communities:  an  in-depth  display  of  the

               College’s  commitment  in  extending  its  developed  technologies  and  resources  to  address  the


               community needs and priorities.

                       Likewise, it also established communication, cooperation, coordination, collaboration and

               convergence among the different colleges within the University, campuses and units, public and

               private  industries  and  other  stakeholders  in  providing  the  necessary  knowledge,  technical

               assistance and opportunities to the target communities.

                       In the Department of Information Technology (DIT), the extension activities revolve around


               in the four curricular programs, namely: BS Information Technology (BSIT), BS Computer Science

               (BSCS),  BS  Office Administration  (BSOA),  and  Master  of  Science  in  Information Technology

               (MSIT).    Using the Ugnayan 2.0, REFORM (Appendix C), and CEIT-IRDEAP (Appendix D) as a

               guide, the following extension programs were identified for the programs under the Department:

               ICT Literacy Program for LGU, Education and Health Sector, Bookkeeping Review; Geographical



                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[4  EXTENSION



               and Tracking System; Management Information Systems of Different Barangays in Indang, Cavite;

               and technical assistance on the development of automated systems for University use.

                       Finally,  the  Department  is  also  involved  in  the  development  of  information  systems  to

               streamline the operations of the University, and conduct basic and applied researches responsive


               to the needs of other agencies.



               EXTENSION ACTIVITIES TO ACHIEVE OBJECTIVES


                       In 2006, the University was included in the project of the then Commission of Information

               and  Communication  Technology  (CICT)  which  is  now,  the  Department  of  Information  and


               Communication  Technology  (DICT).    Faculty  members  of  the  Department  of  Information

               Technology were selected to be the resource speakers and laboratory assistants in the iSchools

               Project and module developer in eSkwela Project. The iSchools Project trained public elementary

               schools in Computer and Internet Literacy in Cavite, Rizal, Quezon, Marinduque and other nearby


               provinces, while eSkwela produced the learning modules for Alternative Learning System.   The
               CICT appointed Cavite State University as the Regional ICT Center.




















                                            Figure 1. Computer and Internet Literacy Course











                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[5  EXTENSION






















                                             Figure 2. Sample eSkwela module screenshot


                         In  2010  and  2011,  both  the  ICT  Coordinators  of  Mendez,  Cavite  and Tagaytay  City,


               requested the College to conduct an ICT Literacy for public elementary teachers. After a series of

               consultation,  trainings  were  organized  for  59  participants  from  7  schools  in  Mendez  which

               happened in 4 days using the facilities of the University. While the simultaneous 4-day training of

               60 teachers from 15 schools in the entire District of Tagaytay was conducted in Mendez Crossing

               Elementary School, San Francisco Elementary School and Maitim II Elementary School. Topics

               included were Office Productivity, Adobe Photoshop and Basic Troubleshooting.















                                          Figure 3. District of Tagaytay City ICT Literacy Training


                       In the year 2012, the College formally entered into a memorandum of agreement with


               Barangay Alulod, Indang, Cavite by offering responsive extension activities through the Ugnayan:

               Kaalaman,  Kabuhayan  at  Kapaligiran  sa  Barangay.    Local  Government  Unit  (LGU)  and

               barangay  officials  were  consulted  in  planning  the  extension  activities  of  the  barangay.




                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[6  EXTENSION



               Stakeholders’ meeting and community needs assessment (CNA) were conducted by faculty, staff,

               students,  and  community  representatives.    Barangay  officials  and  other  representatives

               participated in the Extension Project Formulation and Write shop held at the Research Center last

               July  12,  2012.    These  activities  resulted  to  the  extension  program  of  the  college,  the  “CEIT


               Ugnayan:  Kaalaman,  Kabuhayan,  at  Kapaligiran  Sa  Barangay Alulod,  Indang  Cavite”  as  per

               Board Resolution Number 80, series of 2014.




































                                   Figure 4. Adopted barangay: Barangay Alulod, Indang, Cavite























                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[7  EXTENSION















































                                Figure 5. Formulation of extension agenda and calendar of activities












                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[8  EXTENSION














































                    Figure 6. CEIT officials during the consultative meeting with the honorable members of the local
                          government unit of the Municipality of Indang, Cavite held at Indang Municipal Hall
                                   on April 23, 2012. The meeting resulted to the identification of
                                     Barangay Alulod as the adopted barangay of the College.

























                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[9  EXTENSION




































































                                   Figure 7. Consultative meeting with Barangay Alulod officials















                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[10  EXTENSION






































































                               Figure 8. Extension Formulation and Writeshop held last July 12, 2012
                                                  at the Research Training Center









                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[11  EXTENSION














































                Figure 9. The CEIT faculty members with the Barangay Alulod officials during the Extension Formulation
                               and Writeshop held last July 12, 2012 at the Research Training Center.































                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[12  EXTENSION
















































                Figure 10. CEIT faculty members, staff, and students during the house-to-house interview for Community
                                          Needs Assessment (CNA) last June 9, 2012.












                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[13  EXTENSION
















































                     Figure 10b. CEIT faculty members, staff, and students during the house-to-house interview for
                                     Community Needs Assessment (CNA) last June 9, 2012.











                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[14  EXTENSION

















































                     Figure 10c. CEIT faculty members, staff, and students during the house-to-house interview for
                                     Community Needs Assessment (CNA) last June 9, 2012.











                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[15  EXTENSION

















































                   Figure 10d. The CEIT faculty members, staff, and students during the house-to-house interview for
                                     Community Needs Assessment (CNA) last June 9, 2012.



                       The included extension activities of the Department of Information Technology are based

               on the knowledge and competencies indicated in the curriculum of BS Information Technology

               program,  expertise  of  the  faculty  members,  and  most  especially  the  needs,  problems  and


                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[16  EXTENSION



               resources of the extension partners and beneficiaries.

                       The extension activities are applications of the courses covered in the curriculum such as

               Information  Management,  Web  System  and  Technologies,  Software  Engineering,  Networks

               Management, Software Engineering, Networks Management, Platform Technologies, Multimedia


               System, and Application Development and Emerging Technologies.

                       The  results  of  the  CNA  (Appendix  E)  show  that  the  adopted  barangay  needs  to  be

               capacitated in the field of ICT. Thus, the Department conducted training titled “Information and

               Communication Technology Literacy”. It was held last May 11-14, 2015 and participated by 40

               out-of-school youths and public elementary teachers.


               ICT Literacy Training













































                 Figure 11. Hon. Norberto Ersando, the Captain of Barangay Alulod, Indang, Cavite during the Opening
                       Program of the IT Literacy Training held on May 11 2015 at the CEIT Conference Room.



                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[17  EXTENSION



               Actual Training































                 Figure 12. Prof. Galdys G. Perey, faculty member of Information Technology Unit, with the participants
                                           during the office productivity training session
























                    Figure 13. Prof. John Misael Villanueva, faculty member of Information Technology Unit, with the
                                        participants during the Photoshop training session








                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[18  EXTENSION































                                     Figure 14. The participants during the hands-on activities
































                                Figure 15. The participants giving their impression about the training













                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[19  EXTENSION























































                 Figure 16. Dr. Rhodora V. Nuestro, the dean of the College of Engineering and Information Technology
                    during the Closing Program of the IT Literacy Training Course held on May 14, 2015 at the CEIT
                                                      Conference Room.


                       With the result of 2018 barangay election, the College went to Barangay Alulod on June

               20, 2018 to have a courtesy call and present the conducted extension activities to the new set of

               barangay officials.   Community needs assessment (Appendix F) was conducted last June 20,


               2018  and  October  2018  respectively.  The  needs  assessment  was  participated  by  5,250

               individuals (2,654 females and 2,596 males) from the six purok or sitio of the barangay. In terms

               of  trainings  and  seminars  needed,  computer  literacy  ranks  4th  among  17  sets  of  areas  for

                                                                                                    nd
               selections, while in transfer of technology, the information system development ranks 2 .

                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[20  EXTENSION










































                     Figure 17. Consultative meeting between CEIT faculty members and Barangay Alulod officials
                                                      on June 20, 2018



































                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[21  EXTENSION




















































                         Figure 18. The College of Engineering and Information Technology faculty and students
                                (undergraduate and graduate) together with barangay officials conducted
                                  Community Needs Assessment on October 17 and 20, 2018 as part
                                            of the CEIT Ugnayan 2.0 extension activity in
                                                 Barangay Alulod, Indang, Cavite.


                       In  response  to  the  10-point  socio  economic  agenda  of  the  national  government,  the

               University Extension Services updated the first version of Ugnayan Project and come up with


               CvSU Ugnayan 2.0 with Board Resolution Number 80, s. 2015.    The entire CvSU system follows

               the  revision  of  their  corresponding  extension  programs  to  align  with  the  updated  version  of

               Ugnayan, this is where the development of CEIT Ugnayan 2.0 program started. Suggestions from

               the consultative meeting with the new officials of the barangay were incorporated in the program.

               Evaluation  of  the  extension  activities  of  the  different  department  were  done  to  finalize  the


                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[22  EXTENSION



               extension  program  proposal. The  CEIT  Ugnayan  2.0  was  presented  during  the  Research  In-

               House  Review. All  the  extension  programs  of  the  University  were  anchored  to  the  approved

               Ugnayan 2.0.






















                  Figure 19. Evaluation of the extension activity proposal of the different department of the College of
                                            Engineering and Information Technology

















                             Figure 20. CEIT Extension Proposal Presentation held at Hostel Tropicana
                                                     last January 31, 2019


                       On  July  15,  2019,  College  faculty  members  and  students  together  with  the  Barangay

               Alulod Officials met to discuss the preparation for the implementation of the extension activities.

               The updated CEIT Ugnayan 2.0 was presented and part of it was the ICT Literacy and Transfer


               of Technology by the Department of Information Technology.





                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[23  EXTENSION



























                                  Figure 21. Presentation of CEIT Ugnayan 2.0 at Barangay Alulod



                       The first set of training was conducted last December 14, 2019 at CCL 9, Department of

               Information Technology Building with 10 officials of Barangay Alulod, Indang, Cavite. The focus of

               the training was the basic operations of word processing using Microsoft Word (MS Word). Prof.


               Aiza E. Bihis served as the resource speaker. The participants actively participated during the

               demonstration.


























                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[24  EXTENSION

































                   Figure 22. The participants, Barangay Alulod Officials, of Word Processing Fundamentals Training


                       As for the workshop output, participants were given a hands-on activity to apply what they

               have learned from the demonstration. They were task to create new word document and follow

               the formatting style and method given by the facilitator. Participants were assisted by BSIT and

               BSCS faculty and students.














                Figure 23. Dr. David L. Cero, College dean and Prof. Charlotte B. Carandang, College extension services
                             coordinator consecutively gave their messages during the opening program












                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[25  EXTENSION




















                              Figure 24. Prof. Aiza E. Bihis, the resource speaker of the training












































                      Figure 25. BSIT and BSCS faculty and students assists the participants during the training











                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[26  EXTENSION



















                 Figure                                                                                26.
                Awarding                                                                                of

                                                         certificates



                         Moreover, the undergraduate thesis E-Locate was developed to offer a Geographical
               Information and Tracking System for Brgy. Alulod, Indang, Cavite. It aimed to provide an accurate
               mapping and tracking system for the officials and residents of the said barangay. This would help

               them manage their data and implement their processes systematically (Figure 27). In 2019, the
               system  was  introduced  to  Barangay  Alulod  for  further  evaluation,  however  because  of  the

               pandemic, the system was not fully deployed.
















                                            Figure 27.    Screenshot for E-Locate


                       In addition, the undergraduate study, Coin-Operated Test Booklet Vending Machine was

               deployed in the Department of Information Technology in 2018. The machine became an



                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[27  EXTENSION



               alternative way of selling the test booklet in the department (Figure 28).































                                   Figure 28. Coin-Operated Test Booklet Vending Machine




                       For the continuation of the ICT Literacy, the DIT extension services team requested to

               conduct an ICT assessment for the teachers of Alulod Elementary School. The assessment will

               determine  the  needed  trainings  of  the  teachers.  The  ICT  assessment  was  completed  last

               February 2020. The school requested to have a computer logic and programming workshop on

               their selected junior high school students. However, both extension services were suspended due

               to COVID-19 pandemic.


                       On  the  other  hand,  the  Office  of  the  Vice  President  for  Academic  Affairs  (OVPAA)

               designated the College to be part of the webinar series on Flexible Learning. This is in response

               to  the  changes  happened  in  the  education  system  brought  by  the  COVID-19  pandemic. The

               Department of Information Technology trained the faculty members in migrating the modality of

               learning from face to face to the use of CvSU eLearning System. The webinar series and face to

               face learning was conducted on July 6, 15-16, 27 and Sept. 8, 2020.





                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[28  EXTENSION



                       The activity has two parts, namely: Overview and Use of the CvSU eLearning System;

               and  E-Mentoring/F2F  Mentoring  on  the  Use  of  CvSU  eLearning  System. The  following  were

               highlighted  in the  webinar  and mentoring  sessions:    reminders  on  how  to  use  the  eLearning

               system; key terms; things to be prepared on the training; general features, and to completely


               attain the objectives the participants are encouraged to cooperate; and perform the task on the

               eLearning site.

                       During the webinar and online mentoring, actual demonstration of the activity/task was

               performed. Supplementary videos and textual procedures were played during each task to assist

               the participants. In the course of face to face sessions, some  DIT faculty members acted as


               training assistant.



















                          Figure 29. The DIT faculty members as the main resource speakers in the webinar series




















                   Figure 30. Prof. Julie Ann C. Lontoc and Prof. Ezra Marie F. Ramos, resource speakers, during the
                                                        webinar series
                                                  During webinar




                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[29  EXTENSION





























                            Figure 31. Participants during the face-to-face mentoring of the webinar series
































                                Figure 32. Participants during the e-mentoring of the webinar series


                       Aside from technical expertise provided by faculty members and students, there are some




                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[30  EXTENSION



               research outputs that served as inputs to the extension projects. These generated technologies

               were transferred to the community and in the University. Table 1 shows the system developed

               and maintained by the faculty members of the Department. Table 2 shows the system developed

               by  the  students  and  finally, Table  3  presents  the  list  of  extension  services  conducted  by  the


               program.


               Table 1. Systems developed by the faculty members (collaboration between BSIT and BSCS
                    faculty members)
                                SYSTEM                    YEAR DEVELOPED         FACULTY MEMBER
                Online Admission System                           2019          Sy, Mark Philip M.
                CvSU Student Portal (enhanced)                    2018          Aves, James Angelo V.
                                                                                Sy, Mark Philip M.
                                                                                Villacarlos, Russel L.
                Student Internship Management System              2018          Almarez, Anabelle J.
                                                                                Aves, James Angelo V
                                                                                Bihis, Aiza E.
                                                                                Cruzate, Marlon F.
                E-learning System                                 2015          Lontoc, Julie C.
                                                                                Pereña, Marlon R.
                                                                                Ramos, Ezra Marie
                                                                                Villacarlos, Russel L.
                Research Information System                       2014          Aves, James Angelo V.
                                                                                Ersando, Jake R.
                                                                                Mojica, Ria Clarisse L.
                                                                                Sy, Mark Philip M.
                                                                                Villacarlos, Russel L.
                CvSU Official Website (enhanced)                  2010          Aves, James Angelo V.
                                                                                Sy, Mark Philip M.
                                                                                Villacarlos, Russel L.


























                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[31  EXTENSION































                                   Figure 33. Screenshot of CvSU Research Information System

                                      Link - (http://119.92.116.147/cvsuResearch/index.php)































                                   Figure 34. Screenshot of CvSU E-learning System via Moodle

                                               Link (https://elearning.cvsu.edu.ph)









                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[32  EXTENSION































                                          Figure 35. Screenshot of CvSU Official Website

                                                  Link ( https://cvsu.edu.ph/ )




























                                          Figure 36. Screenshot of CvSU Student Portal

                                               Link (https://myportal.cvsu.edu.ph/)













                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[33  EXTENSION































                                     Figure 37. Screenshot of CvSU Online Admission System

                                         Link (https://registrar.cvsu.edu.ph/osas/sign-in/)


               Table 2.    Systems/application for community utilization
                             SYSTEM                       YEAR                       STATUS
                                                      DEVELOPED

                E-Locate: Geographical                    2019         On-going evaluation in Barangay
                Information and Tracking System                        Alulod
                for Brgy. Alulod, Indang, Cavite
                Coin-Operated Test Booklet                2020         Deployed in the Department of
                Vending Machine                                        Information Technology



               Table 3. Extension activities of the BS Computer Science program

                  PROGRAM          PROJECT /           OBJECTIVES           DURATION            NO. OF
                                    ACTIVITY                                                PARTICIPANTS
                CEIT Ugnayan  Capacity               Empower both         December 14,     10 participants
                2.0:             Building             men and women        2019             (Barangay
                Kaalaman,                             in the community                      Alulod Officials)
                Kabuhayan at     ICT Literacy         through trainings
                Kapaligiran sa   Training             in the field of IT in
                Barangay         Program on           terms of word
                                 Fundamentals         processing
                                 of Word              fundamentals;
                                 Processing          Provide relevant
                                 Document             training in word
                                                      processing using
                                                      Microsoft Word


                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[34  EXTENSION



                  PROGRAM          PROJECT /           OBJECTIVES           DURATION            NO. OF
                                    ACTIVITY                                                PARTICIPANTS
                                                     Develop the skills
                                                      of men and
                                                      women in creating
                                                      and editing word
                                                      document
                                 Capacity            To use cvsu e-       July 6, 2020     782 faculty
                                 Building             learning system                       members
                                 Overview and         with reference to
                                 Use of the           the user manual.
                                 CvSU E-             To manage
                                 Learning             course (subject
                                 System               taught) by
                                                      enrolling students,  July 8 -24,
                                                      checking and         2020
                                                      downloading
                                                      grades
                                                     To create online
                                                      activities such as
                                                      assignments,
                                                      quizzes, forum,
                                                      creating/uploading
                                                      modules using
                                                      CvSU e-learning
                                                      system
                CEIT             ICT Literacy for    Apply the            May 11-13,       13 OSY
                Ugnayan:         Barangay              acquired            2015             27 Teachers
                Kaalaman,        Alulod,  Indang,      technical skills in
                Kabuhayan at     Cavite                ICT specifically in
                Kapaligiran sa                         Office
                Barangay                               Productivity and
                                                       Picture and Video
                                                       Editing
                Request-         ICT Literacy for                                           Office
                Driven           Tagaytay City                             May 2-5, 2011    Productivity – 41
                                 Public
                                 Elementary                                                 Adobe
                                                                                            Photoshop – 30
                                 School
                                 Teachers –
                                 District of
                                 Tagaytay
                Request-         ICT Literacy
                Driven           Course for                                Sept 4, 11;
                                 Public                                    Oct. 27-30,
                                 Elementary                                2010
                                 School
                                 Teachers –
                                 District of
                                 Mendez



                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[35  EXTENSION





                       In the past years, the Department has facilitated the conduct of the following extension

               activities via training:

                            2010 – ICT Literacy Course (District of Mendez)


                            2011 – IT Literacy for (District of Tagaytay)

                            2015 – IT Literacy (Barangay Alulod, Indang, Cavite)

                            2019 – IT Literacy (Officials of Barangay Alulod, Indang, Cavite)

                            2020 – Technology Transfer


























































                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[36  EXTENSION



               SYSTEMATIC AND EFFECTIVE PROCEDURES



                       The  University  formulates  a  unified  Research  and  Extension  Agenda  and  Programs

               (RDEAP) which serves as a guide for the whole institution in conducting research and extension.

               To cope up with technological changes in society, the Office of the Vice President for Research

               and Extension (OVPRE) conducted workshop to craft the Research and Extension Agenda last


               June 14 – 15, 2017 at the Hostel Tropicana. It was then approved by the BOR through Resolution

               No. 58 s. 2017 (Attachment B), comprising of five thematic areas (Figure 37).


















































                                             Figure 38. CvSU R&E Agenda (Thematic Areas)





                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[37  EXTENSION



                       The Extension Services under the OVPRE is the prime unit of the University that manages

               the extension activities of the entire University system. The CvSU Ugnayan 2.0 Poverty Alleviation

               Program is guided by the Conceptual Framework crafted by the Research and Extension Office

               of the University (Figure 38).





















                         Figure 39. Conceptual Framework of CvSU Poverty Alleviation Program through Ugnayan 2.0
                                                              Approach


                       As  part  of  the  Institutions’  mandate  to  provide  responsive  extension  endeavor,  the

               College of Engineering and Information Technology (CEIT) via CEIT Ugnayan 2.0 commitment is

               manifested in the extension activities designed by the five departments of the College including


               the Department of Information Technology.    The activities are guided by the approved Research

               Development  and  Extension  agendas,  RD&E  and  institutional  policies.  Figure  39  shows  the

               outcome-based  extension  and  community  involvement  framework  for  BS  Computer  Science

               program.














                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[38  EXTENSION

































































                                                                Figure 40.    Outcomes-Based Extension and Community Involvement for BSCS Program CvSU RD & E Agenda













                                         BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                                             LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[38  EXTENSION

































































 Figure 40.    Outcomes-Based Extension and Community Involvement for BSCS Program CvSU RD & E Agenda













 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE   LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[39  EXTENSION



                        In conducting the extension activities, Figure 40 (excerpt from CEIT-IRDEAP) serves as

               the general guide. All research/extension activities shall be properly endorsed by the concerned

               office  to  the  University  Research  and  Extension  (RDE)  Council  for  recommendation  to  the

               President  for  approval.  Memorandum  of  Agreement  or  Memorandum  of  Understanding


               (MOA/MOU)  shall  be  executed  for  projects  involving  external  partners.    Research/extension

               projects are to be presented during the agency in-house review and evaluation.








































                           Figure 41. General process flow of research/extension program implementation



                       To  make  the  extension  activities  sustainable  and  continuing,  the  College  adopted  the

               following strategies: Stakeholders meetings; Needs Assessment Survey; Planning of Extension

               Projects and Activities; Needs Verification and MOA Signing; Extension Project Implementation;

               Monitoring and Evaluation of Extension Activities; and Impact Assessment of the Program.


                       Likewise,  a  standard  monitoring  and  assessment  forms  from  the  University  Extension

                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[40  EXTENSION



               Services  such  as Training  Evaluation, Technical Advisory,  MFO  Form,  Narrative  Report,  and

               Monitoring forms (Appendix G) are to be used for the conducted extension activity.

                       The College follows a framework from which the extension activities are implemented

               (Figure 46). The framework was designed based on the Community Needs Assessment (CNA)


               conducted last 2012, 2015, and 2018 and the availability of resources.




















































                                        Figure 42. CEIT framework for extension activities


                       Assessment of impact from the programs and activities conducted are measured based

               on the estimated duration of each objective to be achieved. First, is the attainment of increased

               level of awareness and propagation of knowledge in modern technology to the target beneficiaries.


                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[41  EXTENSION



               The next level is the actual use and increased skill in harnessing these technologies. One of its

               indicators  is  the  increased  interest  of  participants  to  pursue  information  technology  courses.

               Finally,  the  ultimate  impact  to  be  observed  with  the  target  clienteles  are  increased

               income/productivity and employment opportunities gained from their exposure to the programs


               and activities conducted by the Department. It is also expected that there is an increasing trend

               of  people  engaging  in  technology-based  businesses.  The  progress  during  each  stage  is

               monitored and evaluated to gauge and recalibrate the procedures of each activity to arrive to

               achieve the objectives of the program.

























































                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[42  EXTENSION



               REASONABLE BUDGET



                       The College and the Office of Extension Services provides supplies and other resources

               from its MOOE for extension activities.    From 2020, budget allocation is given to the College to

               manage the utilization of the extension programs and activities. T a ble 3 lists the agency/unit/office

               and participants providing materials and other resources in order to implement the extension


               program of the department. Table 4 shows the budget allocation for the last 4 years.



               Table 4. List of Agency/Unit/Office and Participants that provides materials and resources in the
                    implementation of extension programs of the department
                   AGENCY / UNIT /                NATURE OF              PROVISION OF MATERIALS
                        OFFICE                  PARTICIPATION             AND OTHER RESOURCES
                1. CvSU-CEIT-DIT          Proponent                        Developed projects by
                                                                           faculty and students
                                                                           Faculty member, staff and
                                                                           students during planning
                                                                           and actual training activity.
                                                                           Teaching/training materials
                                                                           Venue for planning and
                                                                           training activity
                2.CvSU-Extension          Co-Proponent                    Provides funds for the
                Center                                                     conduct of extension
                                                                           activities
                3. LGU - Indang           Cooperating Agency              Venue for pre-planning
                                            Pre-planning activities       activity
                                                                          Provide some office
                                                                           supplies/training kits
                                                                           supplies
                4. LGU – Barangay         Adopted Barangay                 Identification of participants
                Alulod, Indang, Cavite      Pre-planning activity         to the training programs
                                            Finalization of Plan          Venue during pre-planning
                                            Implementation of Plans       and finalization of plans
                                                                           Provide some office
                                                                           supplies/training kits
                                                                           supplies
                5. DepED Division           Pre-planning activities      Venue during pre-planning
                Office: Tagaytay City       Finalization of Plan          and finalization activities
                                            Implementation of Plans      Venue for the extension
                                                                           activities
                6. DepED Division              Pre-planning activity     Identification of participants
                Office: Mendez, Cavite         Finalization of Plan        to training program



                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[43  EXTENSION



                   AGENCY / UNIT /                NATURE OF              PROVISION OF MATERIALS
                        OFFICE                  PARTICIPATION             AND OTHER RESOURCES
                                               Implementation of
                                                 Plans


               Table 4. Budget allocation

                                   YEAR           APPROVED BUDGET ALLOCATION (PHP)
                                    2018                          450,000.00

                                    2019                          450,000.00
                                    2020                         2,953,292.56

                                    2021                         1,190,691.20






















































                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[44  EXTENSION



               PROVISIONS OF MATERIALS AND OTHER RESOURCES



                       Upgrading of existing laboratories are given priorities as well as materials and resources

               needed  for  the  smooth  implementation  of  the  extension  activities.  Appendix  H  presents  the

               approved upgrading of laboratories. Appendix I presents the acquired equipment for extension.


































































                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[45  EXTENSION



               PARTICIPATION OF STAKEHOLDERS



                       The College, through its faculty members, non-teaching personnel, students, and CvSU

               administrators are involve in the extension activities. Similarly, concerned units and agencies,

               individuals,  in  and  outside  the  University  become  involved  in  the  organization,  supervision,

               monitoring and evaluation of extension activities. The implementation of extension activities of the


               College is widely supported by the LGU, the adopted barangay, the establishments within in the

               barangay and every household in the community. Each extension activity is widely disseminated

               through  letters,  bulletins,  posters,  blogs,  and  any  other  medium.    This  resulted  to  wide

               participation and involvement of all concerned stakeholders.

                       Activities are planned to ensure that appropriate technology is being transferred to the

               community and an effective delivery system is implemented.    Extension activities of the College

               use various strategies such as skills demonstration and training, face to face mentoring, facility


               enhancement,  community  organizing,  distribution  of  IEC materials,  and technical  consultancy

               services.

                       The  extension  projects  conducted  by  DIT  the  last  10  years  were  participated  in  by  a

               number of faculty members, staff, students, and other members of the community. They were

               engaged in the activities particularly during meetings, collection of secondary data, outlining of


               the  memorandum  of  agreement  and  in  the  implementation,  evaluation  and  monitoring  of  the

               conducted extension activities.

                       Table 5 lists the technical expertise provided by the department (faculty members and

               students) during the conduct of extension activities.

               Table 5. Technical expertise adopted/utilized as inputs for extension activities

                                                  EXTENSION PROJECT/ACTIVITY                 MODE OF
                  TECHNICAL EXPERTISE
                                                          WHERE APPLIED                      DELIVERY
                Computer Literacy               ICT Literacy Course for Public          Seminar/Training
                                                Elementary Teachers: Division of



                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[46  EXTENSION



                                                  EXTENSION PROJECT/ACTIVITY                 MODE OF
                  TECHNICAL EXPERTISE
                                                          WHERE APPLIED                      DELIVERY
                                                Tagaytay City

                                                ICT Literacy Course for Public High
                                                School Teachers: Division of Mendez,
                                                Cavite

                                                Project Ugnayan: Kabuhayan,
                                                Kaalaman at Kapaligiran sa Barangay
                                                Alulod : ICT Literacy for Public School
                                                Teachers and    Out-of-School Youth
                                                (OSY) of Indang, Cavite

                Capability Webinar              Migrating to Online Learning: Overview  Skills Training
                                                and Use of CvSU eLearning System
                                                for CvSU Faculty

                                                E-mentoring and F2F Mentoring on the
                                                Use of CvSU eLearning System

                Computer Literacy               CvSU-CICT Projects                      Resource Speaker
                                                                                        Laboratory Assistant

                System Development              Management Information System of        Deployment of
                                                Different Barangays in Indang, Cavite   System
                                                                                        Training of Users

                System Development              Technical assistance on the             Deployment of
                                                development of automated systems for  System
                                                University use                          Training of Users
                                                      Enrollment System
                                                      Admission System
                                                      Student Advising


















                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[47  EXTENSION



               RECOGNITION AND BEST PRACTICES



                       The Barangay Alulod headed by their Barangay Captain, Hon. Norberto Ersando awarded

               the College a certificate of appreciation for all the extension activities given to the barangay during

               his term.




               Best Practices:

                         One comprehensive extension program: CEIT Ugnayan 2.0;

                         Involvement of the local government unit in the extension endeavor;

                         Some  research  output  of  the  students  is  deployed  in  the  community  and  in  the

                          University; and


                         Starting 2020, the budget for extension activities are solely managed by the College










































                 BS COMPUTER SCIENCE                                                      LEVEL III – PHASE II]]></page></pages></Search>