<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="78"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[1]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[TABLE OF CONTENTS




                      1. LINKAGES


                      1.1 WELL DEFINED OBJECTIVES ………………………………………………..  3

                      1.2 ADEQUATE AND RELEVANT PROJECTS /ACTIVITIES TO


                               ACHIEVE OBJECTIVES ……………………………………………………... 7

                             1.2.1. Academic .……………………………………………………………. 22


                             1.2.2 Research ……………………………………………………………… 30

                                    1.2.3. Extension Services  ………………………………………………… 37




                      1.3 SYSTEMATIC AND EFFECTIVE PROCEDURES ………………………….. 70


                             1.3.1 Academic …………………………………………………………….. 71


                             1.3.2. Research ………………………………….……………………….... 72

                             1.3.3. Extension Services ………………………………………………..  73


                      1. 4 REASONABLE BUDGET …………………………………………………….. 74


                      1.5   LINKAGES FUTURE DIRECTIONS ………………………………………..  76




















                      2]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Introduction


                             The College of Nursing offers degree programs  of Bachelor of Science in
                      Nursing, this is a four-year program duly accredited by the Commission on Higher

                      Education (CHED) that aims to specify  the "core competencies" expected to  BS
                      Nursing  graduates  regardless  of  the  type  of  HEI  they  graduated  from.  The

                      recognition  of  the  spirit  of  outcomes-based  education  and  the  typology  of  HEIs
                      outcomes-based  education  is  an  approach  that  focuses  and  organizes  the
                      educational system around what is essential for all learners to know, the values to

                      develop and skills to practice in order to achieve the desired level of competence.
                      The College was recognized by the Professional Regulation Commission (PRC),

                      Office  of  the  Cavite  Provincial  Capitol  and  the  Local  Government  Unit  (LGU)  of
                      Indang.  Graduates of BSN program are expected to develop the personality  and
                      honed their skills based on the following attributes.
                             C-Commitment                       C- Compassionate

                             O-Organized                        A- Assertive

                             N- Nurturer                        R- Resilient
                                                                E- Excellent professionals

                                                                S- Service oriented


                      WELL-DEFINED OBJECTIVES


                               The University  Vision  is  to  be  “The  premier  University  in  historic  Cavite

                      recognized for excellence  in the  development of globally  competitive and  morally
                      upright  individuals.”  Its  mission  is  to  “provide  excellent,  equitable  and  relevant

                      educational  opportunities  in  the  arts,  sciences,  and  technology  through  quality
                      instruction  and  responsive  research  and  development  activities  to  produce
                      professional, skilled and morally upright individuals for global competitiveness.”


                               The College of Nursing set the following goals:  First, produce technically

                      and scientifically oriented graduate imbued with a deep sense of professionalism;
                      possess strong social consciousness and guided by positive values and high ethical
                      standard.  Second,  conduct  evidence-based  research  and  extension  services

                      towards the provision of safe, holistic, and quality  nursing care. Third,  implement
                      effective training and outreach programs that emphasize self-help, critical thinking,
                      and  lifelong  learning.  Lastly,  establish  strong  linkage  with  non-  governmental


                      3]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[organization, other government entities and the community at large for the realization
                      of the common goals.



                               Based on  the four  goals  of the  College of  Nursing,  two goals  can  be
                      anchored  on  the  conduct  of  evidenced  based  research  and  establish  strong
                      linkages. These objectives could be possibly executed and strengthened through

                      the implementation of the college strategic plan. The College have target activities
                      per semester that is aligned to the college and university’s vision and mission. Most

                      of the programs are purposively planned to meet the objectives in the curriculum,
                      research, and extension for global competitiveness.

                                Hence, this Area: Linkages will be presented based on the partnerships,

                      relationships,  collaboration  and  the  established  connections  of  the  College  of
                      Nursing in terms of academic, research and extension linkages.



































                      4]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[1.2 ADEQUATE AND RELEVANT PROJECTS /ACTIVITIES TO ACHIEVE
                             OBJECTIVES

                                1.2.1  ACADEMIC LINKAGES


                               Over the last  fourteen (14)  years the  Cavite State  University, College  of
                      Nursing  was  able  to  establish  linkages  in  various  hospital  for  students’  clinical

                      practicum/related learning experiences. The general guidelines for the affiliation of
                      nursing students are provided in the Joint Administrative Order of DOH No. 2013-
                      0034  and  CHED  CMO  No.  35  s.  2013  entitled  “Policies  and  Guidelines  on  the

                      affiliation of Higher Education Institutions with Hospitals and Other Health facilities
                      for the training of students in Health Profession Educations. In CHED CMO No. 14

                      s. 2009 and CMO No. 15 s. 2017, the students shall be given opportunities to be
                      exposed to the various levels of health care with various client groups (individual,
                      family,  population  groups  and  community)  in  various  delivery  settings  (hospital,

                      community).

                               The  Related  Learning  Experiences  (RLEs)  are  teaching  learning

                      opportunities designed to develop the competencies of students utilizing processes
                      in  various  health  situations,  such  as  lying-in  clinics,  industrial  establishments,
                      community,  outpatient  clinics,  and  general  and  specialty  hospitals.  Furthermore,

                      adequate and appropriate base hospital shall  be required to be the prime  clinical
                      learning  resources.  A  base  hospital  is  a  health  facility  utilized  by  Cavite  State

                      University, College of Nursing  in accordance with an  effective and duly  notarized
                      memorandum of agreement (MOA)  between the institution  and the base  hospital
                      which clearly specifies the responsibilities of each party.


                               On the other hand, affiliation hospital is an accredited health facility being

                      utilized  for  supplementary  clinical  learning  of  students  bounded  by  contract  of
                      affiliation (COA) duly notarized that shows the terms and conditions between CvSU
                      and the health facility. Both MOA and COA focus specifically on the clinical skills of

                      students in the specialized areas, research, and other related educational activities.

                               Creating  effective  and  sustainable  linkages  between  the  clinical  and

                      community  settings  can  improve  the  competencies  of  nursing  students  utilizing
                      processes  in  various  health  situations,  such  as  lying-in  clinics,  industrial
                      establishments,  community,  outpatient  clinics,  and  general  as  well  as  specialty

                      hospitals. Recognizing the value of strong and beneficial partnerships, the College

                      5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[of Nursing maintains linkages with partner institutions in the healthcare industry and

                      with the respected professional organizations such as:

                       Table 1. List of Affiliating Institutions and Hospitals.

                                                                        MOA/MOU
                                                        INCLUSIVE                      AFFILIATION
                         INSTITUTION/HOSPITAL                           VALIDITY
                                                          DATES                           STATUS
                                                                         PERIOD

                        A. Local / Province
                        General  Emilio  Aguinaldo                                    RLE/Clinical

                        Memorial Hospital                                             duties
                        Korean-Philippines             2005        to  June 2021      RLE/Clinical

                        Friendship Hospital            present                        duties
                        Indang Rural Health Unit       October 2018  October 2022  RLE/Clinical
                                                                                      duties

                        Naic Rural Health Unit         March 2019      November       RLE/Clinical
                                                                       2021           duties

                        Tanza Rural Health Unit        October 2019   October 2022  RLE/Clinical
                                                                                      duties
                        Ternate Rural Health Unit      October 2018  October 2022  RLE/Clinical

                                                                                      duties
                        M.V.     Santiago    Medical  August 2019      August 2021    RLE/Clinical

                        Center                                                        duties
                        City of General Trias Doctors   August 2019    August 2020    RLE/Clinical
                        Medical Center                                 (renewal on    duties
                                                                       the process)
                        E.R.S.    Maternity      and  March 2019       March 2020     RLE/Clinical
                        Pediatric Care Clinic                          (renewal on    duties
                                                                       the process)
                        R.S. Punzalan Multispecialty  August 2017      August 2020    RLE/Clinical

                        and Pediatric Care  Clinic                     (renewal on    duties
                                                                       the process)
                        B. Regional
                        Cavite Center for Mental       June 2021       June 2022      RLE/Clinical

                        Health                                                        duties
                        Batangas Medical Center        March 2019      March 2021     RLE/Clinical
                                                                       (renewal on    duties
                                                                       the process)
                        C. National




                      6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[San Lazaro Hospital            June 2019       June 2020      RLE/Clinical
                                                                       (renewal  on
                                                                       the process)   duties

                        Philippine Orthopedic Center  June 2019        June 2020      RLE/Clinical
                                                                       (renewal  on
                                                                       the process)   duties


                      A. Local/ Province


                      A.1. General Emilio Aguinaldo Memorial Hospital (GEAMH)
                              The General Emilio Aguinaldo Memorial Hospital is situated in a six- hectare
                      land in Trece Martires City. GEAMH was the first public hospital established in the

                      province of Cavite. On January 2014, the hospital received its ISO certification (ISO
                      9001:2008) from  AJA  for  its two  major  (2)  services, Emergency  Room  and  Out
                      Patient Department. In which the Gen. Emilio Aguinaldo Memorial Hospital was the

                      first provincial government hospital in the country to receive such accreditation.



























                      Figure 1. The. General. Emilio Aguinaldo Memorial Hospital serves as the base
                            hospital of CvSU-College of Nursing since it offered the program. This hospital
                            has 284 bed capacity and counting, they offer various in-patient and out-patient
                            clinical teaching opportunities for the nursing students



















                      7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[Figure 2   The  BS Nursing students during  their clinical exposure at  General
                            Emilio  Aguinaldo  Memorial  Hospital,  Medical  Ward  with  their  Clinical
                            Instructor. Mr. Ivan Derek V. Wycoco. is presenting instructions in utilizing
                            Hospital Information System (HIS).






























                      Figure 3. The  Memorandum of  Understanding between Cavite  State University  -
                            College of Nursing and General Emilio Aguinaldo Memorial Hospital.











                      8]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[A.2. Korea-Philippines Friendship Hospital


                               Korea-Philippines  Friendship  Hospital,  is  also  known  as  “K.P.”,  a  multi-
                      specialty  hospital  in  Trece  Martires,  Cavite  and  established  as  a  symbol  of

                      everlasting friendship of Korea and Philippines. This is also the extension services
                      of GEAMH as pay ward institution where the students were also able to practice and
                      apply their nursing knowledge and skills with actual patients in the clinical setting.


























                      Figure 4.  The Korea-Philippines Friendship Hospital and the Medical Arts
                             Laboratory Building
































                      Figure  5. The Level II nursing students together with their Clinical Instructors and
                            Ms. Ruthie Armijo, Nurse Training Officer of the Nursing Service Department
                            of    General  Emilio  Aguinaldo  Memorial  Hospital  (GEAMH)  and  Korean
                            Philippine  Friendship Hospital (KPFH)  during the  clinical orientation.


                      9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[Figure 6.  The Level IV nursing students while joining and paying attention to the
                             nurse’s endorsement during their clinical exposure at KPFH  Medical Ward
                             together with their Clinical Instructor Professor Nenita B. Panaligan.


                      A.3. Indang Rural Health Unit


                               A  primary  health  unit  in  the  municipality  of  Indang  headed  by  Municipal
                      Health Officer Dr. Rosa Alegre. It offers general health care services to the people

                      of Indang such as maternal and child care, dental, and different DOH programs. It is
                      located at Brgy. Poblacion IV, Indang, Cavite.






























                      Figure  7.  Students’  orientation  at  Indang  Rural  Health  Unit  with  BSN  Level  2
                            students together with their Instructors Mr. Ivan Wycoco, Mr. Sunny Rose
                            Ferrera, Ms. Phaebi Romen,  Mr.  Mario  De La Cruz  and Ms. Jocelyn  B.
                            Dimayuga.
                      10]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Figure 8. The copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU-College of
                             Nursing and Municipality  of Indang RHU



                      A.4.Naic Rural Health Unit


                               A primary health unit in the municipality of Naic headed by Municipal Health
                      Officer, Dr. Susan Anselmo Se. It offers general health care services to the people

                      of Naic such as maternal and child care, dental, and different DOH programs.




























                      Figure 9. The Rural Health Unit of Naic is located at Brgy. Bancaan, I, Cavite.



                      11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[Figure 10.  The Nursing students and their Clinical Instructor Ms. Maribel L. Chua
                               together with the nursing staff of Naic RHU during their Maternal and Child
                               Nursing Clinical exposure.































                      Figure 11. The copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU College of
                             Nursing and the RHU Municipality of  Naic.












                      12]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[A.5. Tanza Rural Health Unit



                               A  primary  health  unit  in  the  municipality  of  Tanza  headed  by  Municipal
                      Health Officer Dr. Ruth Punzalan. It offers general health care services to the people

                      of Tanza such as maternal and child care, dental, and different DOH programs.

























                      Figure  12.  The  Municipal  Health  Center  and  Rural  Health  Unit  of  Tanza  is
                             located at Brgy. Amaya, Tanza, Cavite.
































                      Figure 13.  The Level II Nursing students during their clinical exposure at Tanza
                               RHU together with Clinical instructor Ms. Maribel L. Chua with the Brgy
                               Health Worker who assisted them during the entire exposure.




                      13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Figure 14. The copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU College
                               of Nursing and the RHU of the Municipality of  Tanza.

                      A.6.Ternate Rural Health Unit


                               A  primary  health  unit  in  the  municipality  of  Ternate,  Cavite  headed  by
                      Municipal Health Officer Dr. Gina Lynn Arandia. It offers general health care services

                      to the people of Ternate such as maternal and child care, dental, and different DOH
                      programs.



























                      Figure 15.  The Ternate Rural Health Unit is located at Brgy. Governor’s Drive,
                               Ternate, Cavite





                      14]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Figure 16. Tour and orientation of BSN Level II students at San Juan 1 Ternate
                               Cavite with  their  respective  Clinical  Instructors  and  Ternate  Municipal
                               Health Officer (MHO)  Dr. Gina-lynn  Y.  Arandia .































                      Figure 17. The copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU
                            College of Nursing and the RHU of the Municipality  of   Ternate.











                      15]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[A.7. Manuel V. Santiago Medical Center


                             MVSMC, an 83-bed capacity secondary  hospital that envisions itself to  be
                      one of the best medical centers in Cavite that delivers continuously improving quality

                      health care services to its patients. It features quality health care facilities, medical,
                      and support staff in its years of service by living to their noble mission.




























                      Figure 18. The Manuel V. Santiago Medical Center provides an Out-patient
                            department, Dialysis Center, and other special unit/ areas where the
                            students are being exposed in their clinical rotation.





























                      Figure 19. The BSN Level IV students are having their Related Learning
                               Experiences in the special areas like Operating Room and different
                               wards in the hospital.
                      16]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[Figure  20.  The  Memorandum  of  Agreement  between  CvSU  College  of
                            Nursing  and  MV  Santiago  Medical  Center,  Brgy  De  campo,  Trece
                            Martires City, Cavite



                      A.8. City of General Trias Doctors Medical Center

                               City of General Trias Doctors Medical Center former Gentri Doctors Medical

                      Center is a 100-bed capacity hospital that serves as an affiliating hospital of CvSU-
                      CON. Nursing students are rotated to different special and non-special areas such
                      as Medical Ward, Intensive Care Unit,  Surgical and obstetrics ward, Dialysis Unit,

                      Operating Room, Neonatal Intensive Care Unit and Emergency Department.






















                      17]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Figure 21.  The City of General Trias Doctors Medical Center is located at Barangay
                               Manggahan,  General Trias, Cavite































                      Figure 22. Filipino and international nursing students are experiencing real life
                            situation and techno-intelligent systems in the clinical setting  in terms of
                            machine  and  equipment  in  the  hospital,  under  the  supervision  of  their
                            Clinical Instructor Mr. Ivan Derek V. Wycoco. The students were able to
                            apply theories, principles and practices taught in the school,











                      18]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Figure 23.  The copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU-College
                             of Nursing and City of General Trias Doctors Medical Center at Gen. Trias
                             City, Cavite.


                      A.9. E.R.S. Maternity  and Pediatric Care  Clinic

                               A primary health care   unit located in the heart   of Trece Martires City  ,
                      Cavite owned  by an OB GYNE  Dr. Fhe R. Sierra-Sepacio. It offers primary health
                      care and diagnostic services  as well as maternal and child care.






























                      Figure 24. ERS Maternity & Pediatric Care Clinic is located at Barangay Luciano ,
                               Trece Martires City, Cavite


                      19]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[Figure  25.  The  BSN  Level  II  students  are  having  their  Related  Learning
                               Experiences in the ERS Maternity and Pediatric clinic.  The photo shows
                               students delivered health education among  post partum mothers about
                               newborn care.

                      A.10. R.S. Punzalan and Pediatric Care Clinic


                      A primary health care  unit located also in  Trece Martires City , Cavite owned  by
                      Dr. Ruth Punzalan . It offers primary health care and diagnostic services  as well as
                      maternal and child care.




























                      Figure 26. RS  Punzalan Multispecialty  & Diagnostic Care Clinic is located at the
                      Barangay  De Ocampo , Trece Martires City, Cavite

                      20]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Figure 27 The BSN Level II students are having their Related Learning
                                    Experiences in the Multispecialty and  Diagnostic Clinic.  The photo shows
                                    students delivered health education among   mothers about newborn  and
                                    pediatric care.


                      B. Regional


                      B.1. Cavite Center for Mental Health (CCMH)
                               CCMH is a mental hospital located in Trece Martires, Cavite which consist

                      of  psychiatric  wards,  treatment,  and  rehabilitation  centers  for  drugs  and  alcohol
                      dependency and other mental  disorders. This regional  institution serves as  CON

                      affiliating hospital for Psychiatric Nursing.

























                      Figure 28.  The Level III Nursing students during their clinical exposure in the Cavite
                                Center  for  Mental  Health.  Grand  socialization  activity  is  one  of  their
                                culminating event  for their client.

                      21]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Figure 29.  The copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU-College of
                             Nursing and Cavite Center for Mental Health


                      B.2. Batangas Medical Center formerly known as Batangas Regional Hospital


                               Batangas Medical Center formerly known as Batangas Regional Hospital is

                      a 500-bed capacity  tertiary hospital that  serves as an  affiliating hospital of  CvSU
                      CON. Nursing students are rotated to different special and non-special areas such
                      as  Medical  Ward,  Intensive  Care  Unit,  Operating  Room,  Delivery  Room  and

                      Emergency Room.


























                      Figure  30.  Batangas  Medical  Center  is  one  of  the  biggest  DOH  Training
                            Hospitals in the Region.




                      22]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Figure 31. The copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU-College
                                  of Nursing and Batangas Medical Center



                      C. National


                      C.1.San Lazaro Hospital
                               A Special National Hospital Medical Center for Infectious Diseases with a
                      500-bed capacity. It is involved in health care delivery service, especially for the poor

                      suffering from infectious diseases. Some of its short- and long-term programs are
                      infrastructure improvement and strengthening of its frontline services.
































                         Figure 32. Isan Lazaro Hospital, Manila has a continuous medical training
                               and research program for medical and paramedical personnel.

                      23]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[Figure 33.  Group of Level IV Nursing students with Ms. Phaebi B. Romen as
                                their preceptor during  the entire  exposure at  San Lazaro  Hospital
                                OPD unit and Medical ward.







































                      Figure 34. The copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU -College of
                             Nursing and San Lazaro Hospital, Manila.






                      24]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Figure 35. The University Vice President for Academic Affairs Dr. Camilo A. Polinga
                            and  College  of  Nursing  ,Dean  Evelyn  M.  Del  Mundo  with  Prof.  Jocelyn  B.
                            Dimayuga – CON Overall Clinical Coordinator were present during the signing
                            ceremony of the Contract of Agreement relating to Nursing students’ affiliation
                            for the A.Y. 2019-2020, together with Dr. Edmundo B. Lopez, Medical Center
                            Chief  II  and  Dr.  Virginia  O.  Dimapilis,  the  Hospital  Chief  Training  Officer
                            assisted by Nursing Service Training Office headed by Ms. Rose Mendoza,
                            Training Officer for the student’s affiliation.



                      C.2.Philippine Orthopedic Center


                               A 700-bed tertiary special hospital under the Department of Health of the
                      Philippines, specializing in the treatment of musculoskeletal disorders and serves as

                      a center for trauma and orthopedics. Philippine Orthopedic Center is ISO 9001:2015
                      certified.
























                         Figure 36.  The Philippine Orthopedic Center is located in Banawe, Quezon City.




                      25]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Figure  37.  The  College  of  Nursing  Faculty  Mr.  Ivan  Derek  V.  Wycoco  have
                             undergone  Preceptorship  Training  of  Instructor  for  2  weeks  at  Philippine
                             Orthopedic Center. This is one of the requirements prior to clinical orientation
                             and actual exposure to the area for handling affiliate students.


                               For the overall improvement of instruction, the clinical orientation program

                      is an important  part of  the nursing  students RLE  to hospitals  and other  affiliated
                      institutions.  To  prepare  the  students  for  a  successful  clinical  placement  and  to

                      maximize  learning  experience,  the  hospitals  have  developed  a  nursing  student
                      orientation program. This program is usually done by the Training Officer, but in some
                      hospitals by the Infection Control Nurse who will introduce to students the important

                      principles  of  clinical  care  and  specific  policies  and  procedures  followed  in  the
                      institution. This program  is required  prior to the  start of  nursing student’s  clinical
                      duties. It is one of the best practices of the College of Nursing to conduct a general

                      orientation in the classroom followed by an orientation on the unit, department, and
                      special areas in the hospitals where they will be exposed in a semester. The students
                      will be grouped according to their sections based on the schedule of RLE duties.




















                      26]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[Figure 38. The level IV Nursing students during their clinical exposure at Philippine
                            Orthopedic Center (POC). They performed balanced skeletal traction (BST)
                            with their Clinical Instructor, Mr. Ivan  Derek V. Wycoco. They are also given
                            the privileged to assist the Orthopedic Surgeon in applying long arm posterior
                            cast to one of their patient.


































                     Figure 39. The copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU -College of
                            Nursing and Philippine Orthopedic Center in Quezon City.




                      27]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[D. Other Partner Institutions


                       D.1.  Cavite  State  University,  College  of  Nursing  has  joined  efforts  and
                      partnerships with the Asian Hospital Medical Center.  The College of Nursing is

                      facing some challenging experiences in this COVID 19 pandemic. It has also already
                      disrupted universities and academic institutions. The schools of nursing were bracing
                      for unique challenges related to our role in helping develop the next generation of

                      care providers. We question how we will continue to educate nurses in a society
                      facing social distancing, isolation, and quarantine measures while needing nurses at
                      the frontline. Academic programs would provide the workforce with the necessary

                      skills and  the  best  way to  make  a  positive and  significant  contribution.  Thru  the
                      implementation of simulation activities in a  virtual platform by this institution,  they

                      have  caught  the  interest  of  both  faculty  members  and  nursing  students.  We
                      conducted  a  one-day  webinar  session  last  April  29,  2021  regarding  the  nursing
                      virtual platform training, which was solely on the application of Nursing Leadership

                      and Management skills both in academic and clinical settings. Moreover, this activity
                      will  serve  as  the  initial  step  in  the  process  of  our  Memorandum  of  Agreement

                      (MOU).


































                      Figure 40. The approved letter of the College of Nursing webinar in collaboration
                                        with the Asian Hospital Medical Center nursing virtual platform training
                                        merely focused on the application of Nursing Leadership and
                                        Management skills both in academic and clinical settings.


                      28]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[Figure 41. A Virtual tour was held last April 30, 2021, in partnership with the Asian
                                    Hospital and Medical Center attended by 149 participants from Level III and
                                    Level IV nursing students, together with the faculty, and staff of the College
                                    of Nursing. The focus of the virtual tour is all about Nursing Leadership and
                                    Management.


































                      Figure 42. Photo showing the participants’ who attended the webinar and Dr. Evelyn
                                       Del Mundo, Dean of the College of Nursing rendered the closing remarks.
                                       Also a certificate of appreciation from Asian Hospital Medical Center was
                                       given to the dean of the college of nursing.




                      29]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[D.2. College of Nursing received donations from partners institution.































                      Figure 43.  Showing the books received from De La Salle Medical and Health
                                           Sciences Institutes (DLSU) College of Nursing as donations to the
                                           College intended for nursing students from  low income family  .































                      Figure 44.  Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo, Dean of the College of Nursing together with
                                   the Over All Coordinator Prof. Jocelyn B. Dimayuga received the human
                                   torso anatomy model which will be used for teaching student. The model
                                   was donated by the administration of Tagaytay Medical Center (TMC).





                      30]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[1.2.2.  RESEARCH LINKAGES


                               Establish linkages with public/private institutions to generate more funds for
                      research and Instruction, the initial activity of the college is to build partnerships and
                      linkages (MOA/ MOU) with different hospitals, Lying  -ins owners and other  health

                      institutions to determine their needs for health education, research and services
                               The College of Nursing looks  beyond traditional sources of funds, along

                      the vision  and  mission  of the  University,  the  college   takes  it  mandate  from  the
                      strategic plan which states that the University shall provide opportunities for faculty
                      research to be shared with students and the community alike, establish international

                      linkages  for  research  collaboration  and  student-teaching  exchange  programs,
                      organize  and  co-organize  international  conferences,  trainings  and  seminars,
                      facilitate and manage the completion of  research outputs utilized by the industry and

                      other beneficiaries, and increase the percentage of research outputs published in
                      internationally  refereed and CHED recognized journal.
                               As one of the outcomes of the BS Nursing program is the development of a

                      beginning nurse researcher, the College of Nursing faculty and students regularly
                      attend  the  university’s  research  activities  and  continuously  collaborates  with  the

                      various research health care experts and research agencies for capacity building,
                      funding, resource generation and to enhance creative thinking and innovation. This
                      will mold researchers to make meaningful contributions as citizens of a  complex

                      world such activities are as follow:


                      A. Local

                               The mandate of the University does not only revolve on instruction but also

                      includes services through research and extension. As it provides quality education
                      to students, it also innovates and discovers new knowledge addressing the needs of

                      the changing times and the demands of the society. Such knowledge also needs to
                      be enhanced and packaged to be shared to the community and other clientele.


                               The primary  goal  of Research  and  Extension Department  is  to  conduct
                     relevant  research  and  extension  activities  as  it  strengthens  partnership  or
                     collaboration/linkages.  Innovation  and  learning  are  also  emphasized,  hence,  the

                     college also generates resources considering efficient asset utilization and improving
                     obligation rate. In its commitment to innovate processes, systems and mechanisms,


                      31]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[it  continuously  provides  relevant  opportunities  in  increasing  engagement  and

                     satisfaction of clients and empowering stakeholders. The impact of all these functions
                     are aimed at improving the quality of lives of the community members.
                               However, to continue creating and providing opportunities for educational

                     and professional growth, another strategy that faculty members are aiming to write
                     researches in Public Health and Welfare Journal (IJEBMP) and Journal in Bioethics
                     in collaboration  with other  colleges in  the university  such as  College of  Veterinary

                     Medicine and Biological Sciences (CVMBS), College of Arts and Sciences (CAS) and
                     with the College of Medicine (COM).


                      A.1. CvSU Research Center and Development OVPAA, CON as co-host


                               As part of the strategy of the college on strengthening Academe-Industry
                      Linkages both local and international, the Cavite State University, College of Nursing
                      co- hosted the 3   International Conference on Medical  Pluralism with  the  theme,
                                       rd
                      “Complementary Medicine in Asia: Status, Issues and Challenges.”  held last March
                      11-14,  2019  at  Rolle  Hall,  Cavite  State  University  Main  Campus,  Indang  Cavite,

                      Philippines.  This  international  conference  includes  plenary  talks  of  diverse  and
                      experts who will speak about  their current practices in complementary  medicine,
                      including the issues and  challenges in its practice  in the Asian Regions.  Various

                      speakers delivered current updates on complementary medicine practices and able
                      to  participate  in  exchanging  ideas,  knowledge  and  experience  in  the  practice  of
                      complementary  medicine.  Furthermore,  encompassing  the  indigenous  healing

                      practices, naturopathy and Green medicine.

























                      Figure 45. Program Invitation  of 3rd international Conference on Medical Pluralism



                      32]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[An international conference on Medical Pluralism held last March 11-14,

                      2019.It was hosted by the Cavite State University and was jointly facilitated by the
                      College of  Nursing.  It  was  attended  by  participants  from  institutions  local  and
                      abroad























                      Figure 46.    The  University President  Dr.  Hernando  D. Robles  and  the  Guest
                            speakers,  with  CoN  Dean  Dr.  Evelyn  del  Mundo,  Dept.  of  Midwifery
                            Principal, Prof. Jane Rona, CON Overall Clinical Coordinator Ms. Jocelyn
                            Dimayuga, SC Adviser Louis Carlos O. Roderos and the dean of the CAS
                            Prof Bettina Joyce Ilagan.


                      A.2. Philippine Nursing Research Society, Inc. Webinar, Cavite Cell and


                            College of Nursing faculty members elected as Board of Directors

                               The partnership with the Philippine Nursing Research Society, Inc. (PNRSI)

                      is  one  big  step  of  the  College  of  Nursing  to  achieve  assistance  for  faculty
                      development and involvement in doing researches. Way forward, PNRSI envisions

                      that  research  in  nursing  will  be  considered  by  nurses  as  a  process  to  ensure
                      continuous quality  improvement of  the  practice and  expand the  nursing  science.
                      There are two faculty members from the CoN who were elected as Interim Officers,
                      namely: Professor Nenita B. Panaligan as President and Ms Karen Louela R.  Rint

                      as the treasurer (Figure 39) After the online election and tabulation of the nominees
                      for  the  PNRSI  Cavite  Cell,  Prof.  Nenita  B.  Panaligan,  retained  her  position  as

                      President, while   Ms. Karen Loula R. Rint as Auditor  and Mr. Ivan Derek V. Wycoco
                      was elected as Treasurer who are all college’s faculty members.

                               PNRSI in collaboration with PNRSI-Cavite Cell and Cavite State University,

                      College  of  Nursing  held  its  1   General  Assembly  and  Conference  via  Zoom
                                                     st
                      Conferencing with a theme, “Cavite Nurses Setting off Towards a Healthy Society




                      33]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[through Nursing Research”.(Figure 36). It was attended by faculty members, staff,
                      students and other stakeholders as part of research activities during the pandemic.


                               Prof. Nenita Panaligan, MAN, RN delivered opening remarks and formally
                      opened the general assembly as Interim President, PNRSI Cavite Cell. Dr. Teresita

                      Irigo-Barcelo shared a bit of PNRSI history in which sometime in October 2007, a
                      group of same minded nurses came together to discuss the need to help our nurses
                      pursue their research interest.


                               . Dr. Maria Cynthia Leigh shared effortlessly her life story and professional
                      experiences as a Nurse Researcher wherein she has been recognized as one of the
                      pillars  of  Nursing  Research  here  and  abroad.  She  also  encouraged  the  nurse

                      researchers to continue to pursue PhD program and Post PhD wherein it opens more
                      opportunities for the innovators.  Dr. Irma Bustamante, PNRSI National President

                      also shared inspirational message  to the participants as  also to the launching  of
                      PNRSI-Cavite Cell.  The general assembly and launching, attended by more than
                      300 attendees,  also  increases the  number  of  membership to  local,  national  and

                      international organizations by the faculty members of the college.





























                      Figure 47.  The Philippine Nursing Research Society, Inc. (PNRSI) in collaboration
                          with  PNRSI-Cavite  Cell  and  Cavite  State  University,  College  of  Nursing,
                          conducted the 1st General Assembly and Conference via Zoom Conferencing
                          with the theme “Cavite Nurses Setting off Towards a Healthy Society through
                          Nursing Research.










                      34]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[Figure 48. The Philippine Nursing Research Society, Inc. (PNRSI) Cavite Cell set of
                          Interim  Officers,  Professor  Nenita  B.  Panaligan  as  President  and  Ms  Karen
                          Louela  R.    Rint  as  the  Treasurer.  They  are  both  faculty  from  the  College  of
                          Nursing.



                      B. Regional


                               B.1.   Another regional partnership with Philippine Nurses Association
                      (PNA) for skills development of faculty members.

                               A webinar series: Sharing Best Practices and Lessons Learned… Aftermath
                      of COVID 19  Pandemic: Resetting  the Roles  of Nurses  in the  New Normal  was
                      conducted  on  August  8,  2020  at  9:00  AM  -12  Noon.  This  in  collaboration  with

                      Philippine Nurses Association Cavite Chapter and PNA Region IV-A, Cavite State
                      University,  College  of  Nursing  and  DOST-  Philippine  Council  for  Health  and

                      Research Consortium Region IV-A (Figure 40)..
                               In regional level, the college also aims to continue the conduct of personal
                      enhancement program to develop sense of teamwork and inclusivity. The college is
                      developing  a  collaborative  partnership  with  PNA  for  the  conduct  of

                      seminars/webinars,  trainings,  workshops  and  teambuilding  activities  for  self-
                      enhancement, teamwork and inclusive growth.















                      35]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Figure  49.  The  webinar  series  is  in  collaboration  with  Philippine  Nurses
                               Association- Region  IV-A, Cavite State University, College of Nursing and
                               DOST- Philippine Council for Health and Research Consortium Region IV-
                               A.

                             This collaboration was initiated and hosted by the PNA Cavite Chapter with

                      its  President,  Professor  Nenita  B.  Panaligan,  a  faculty  member  in  the  college,
                      together  with  co-faculty  as  Chapter  Board  of  Directors,  Dr.  Evelyn  del  Mundo
                      (Treasurer), Ms. Jocelyn Dimayuga (BOD) and Mr. Rolando Antonio (BOD) with the

                      CvSU College of Nursing. Two of the invited speakers are alumni of the this college
                      namely,  Mr.  Jay  Louie  Madlangbayan  who  is  also  the  current  President  of  the
                      Operating Room Nurses Association of the Philippines Cavite Chapter and Mr. Ralph

                      Laurence Figueroa who is a Provincial Supervising Nurse Educator in the Provincial
                      Health Office of Cavite. The sense of leadership in the Nursing profession at  the
                      provincial level can be empowering that through linkages with college’s alumni who

                      are now gaining leadership in their selected fields, signifies distinct illumination of
                      achieving the  College’s  vision and  objectives  as developer  of  nurse  professional

                      known for leadership, excellence and service (Figure 42).








                      36]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Figure  50.The  approved  communication  letter  of  the  Cavite  State  University  –
                            College  of  Nursing  in  collaboration  with  Philippine  Nurses  Association  Inc.
                            Region IV  -Cavite Chapter  and  Philippine Council  for Health  Research  and
                            Development  (PCHRD)  Consortium  Region  IV  –A  in  hosting  the  Fortitude,
                            Opportunities, Unity and Resiliency in Actions (FOUR – A) Amidst Covid – 19
                            Pandemic Webinar Series.





























                       Figure 51. The Resource Speaker, PRC Board of Nursing (BON) Chairman Hon.
                             Dr. Glenda Arquiza shared her experiences and best practices in the various
                             field of nursing. She accentuated the nurse’s important role and resiliency in
                             fighting COVID 19 pandemic  and resetting the roles  of nurses in  the  new
                             normal after pandemic.






                      37]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[B.2. Department of Interior and Local Government (Citizen Satisfaction Index
                            System Survey Study)


                               In  looking  beyond  traditional  sources  of  funds,  the  College  of  Nursing

                      explores some ways of getting some aids and provisions from colleagues, friends,
                      people  and  institutions  who  are  sharing  their  resources  for  some  humanitarian
                      purposes .and collaboration.

                               The faculty and staff have target activities per semester that is aligned to
                      the college and university’s vision and mission. The College of Nursing was involved
                      for two times with the Citizen Satisfaction Index System Survey. Initially, with  the

                      Municipality of Magallanes (2018) and in the Municipality of Rosario (2019).  This is
                      a funded research activities conducted annually in partnership with Department of

                      Interior and Local Government (DILG).
                               Linkages  between  the  DILG-Cavite  and  the  Cavite  State  University  was
                      established  since  June  13,  2016.    There  was  an  approved  Memorandum  of

                      Agreement  (MOA)  between  the  Local  Resource  Institute  (LRI),  the  Cavite  State
                      University, Research Center   and DILG Regional Director. The CSIS data can also

                      be  a  starting  point  for  academic  institutions  in  providing  research,  learning,  and
                      extension services.











































                      38]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Figure 52.  The CSIS Team headed by Dean Evelyn M. Del Mundo  as the  Project
                            Manager and Ms. Jocelyn Dimayuga, a faculty member from the College of
                            Nursing  as  Field Supervisor of the said  project.























                       Figure 53. The  copy of  Memorandum of  Agreement between  DILG and  CvSU,
                               signed by DILG Regional Director Manuel Gotis, CESO III and Cavite State
                               University President Dr. Hernando D. Robles, CEO VI..









                      39]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[Figure 54. CSIS training conducted by the Region IV-A DILG office   at  Puerto
                             Princesa  Palawan.  Dean  Evelyn  M.  Del  Mundo  serves  as  the  Project
                             Manager and Ms. Jocelyn Dimayuga  as  the Field Supervisor of the project.
                             They participated in the three days field training.


























                       Figure 55. Delegates from different HEI ‘s  in south cluster area of Region  IV-A
                             during the three days training in Puerto Princesa, Palawan..






















                       Figure 56. The Cavite State University CSIS team during the actual face to face
                               survey and interview at Brgy. Silangan 1, Rosario, Cavite.

                      40]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[B.3. Cavite State University partnership with the Philippine Council for Health

                      Research and Development Region IV-A Consortium through a Memorandum
                      of Agreement (MOU) signed in CY 2015.


                               Since 2015, the college have supported the objective of the University on
                      research engagement and capacity building for all faculty members in all campuses

                      (collaborative  effort  with  the  other  research  partners  and  agencies).  The  former
                      CvSU President, Dr. Divinia C. Chavez signed a memorandum of agreement with
                      the PCHRD Region IV Consortium, as one of the member institution among the 16

                      member institutions in Region IV-A. In 2016, Dr. Hernando D. Robles continue the
                      strong partnership with PCHRD covering the colleges with health and allied health

                      programs.
                               There  was  a  signed  Memorandum  of  Agreement  between  Philippine
                      Council  for  Health  Research  Development  and  other  affiliating  universities  and

                      institutions including Cavite State University (Figure 48).



































                      Figure 57. The copy of the signed Memorandum of Agreement between PCHRD
                            and  other  affiliating  universities  and  colleges  including  Cavite  State
                            University.






                      41]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[B.3. 1   2019 Representative to different committees to the Health Research

                      Consortium Region IV


                               Two  of  our  faculty  members  namely:    Professor  Nenita  B.  Panaligan,
                      College  QUAC,  as  the  member  representative  for  Committee  on  Research  and
                      Development Management of PCHRD  since 2015 and re-designated in 2019, and

                      Dr.  Bernadette  A.  Sapinoso,    College  Guidance  Counselor,  as  member
                      representative on Committee on Ethics were recommended by Dr. Yolanda Ilagan,
                      Director of Research and Development of the University to be the representative of

                      the CvSU to different committees of Health Research Consortium Region IV (Figure
                      49).



































                      Figure  58.  An  approved  letter  recommending  the  faculty  members  from  the
                          College of Nursing, Professor Nenita B. Panaligan as member representative
                          for Committee on Research and Development Management of PCHRD and
                          the College Guidance Counselor and  currently as the Officer in Charge of
                          the Midwifery Department  ,Professor Bernadette A.  Sapinoso as  member
                          representative on Committee on Ethics









                      42]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Figure 59.  CvSU  participated  in  the formulation  of  the  DOST  PCHRD  Regional
                      Health Research Agenda represented by Prof. Nenita B. Panaligan held in August,
                      2017 at Tagaytay Lake Hotel, Tagaytay City.


                      B.3.2     2018 Attendance  to  Various Training  -  Workshop on  Research  and
                      Research –related Activities


                               In line  with the  objective  of developing  the  capacities of  researchers  for

                      conducting, managing and utilizing health research, the College of Nursing pursued
                      the activity  to Capacitate  senior and  budding researchers  to conduct  community
                      based sustainable projects and create funding sources.  The partnership of CvSU

                      with the consortium provides opportunity for capacity building and support through
                      free  attendance  and  sponsorship  of  registration  fees  from  the  DOST-  PCHRD
                      consortium for proposal development, project funding and utilization of researches.

                      In November  13-15, 2018,  PCHRD  conducted of  Training  – Workshop  on  Basic
                      Research Methods by the Committee on Capacity Building of the Health Research
                      and Development Consortium Region IV – A (HRDCR IV-A), the college sent two

                      faculty participants at Lake Hotel Tagaytay City namely: Ms/ Jocelyn B. Dimayuga,
                      College Overall Clinical Coordinator and Phaebi B. Romen, the College secretary

                      (Figure 51). It  was joined by  different colleges, Universities,  Health Institutions  all
                      over the Region IV – A. These two faculty members from the college have benefited
                      on the training sponsored by DOST-PCHRD Consortium for free on basic research


                      43]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[method.  They  met  respectable  PCHRD  speakers  from  the  University  of  the

                      Philippines, Manila. Dr. Ophelia Mendoza, Dr. Ofelia Saniel and Dr. Rommel Salazar
                      form the De La Salle University, Dasmarinas, Cavite (Figure 51).
                               This training –workshop  was echoed  to other faculty  members after  the

                      event in one of the college faculty development activity last November 27, 2021.

























                      Figure 60.  CvSU, CoN was represented by Ms. Jocelyn B. Dimayuga,the College
                            Overall Clinical Coordinator and the College Secretary Phaebi B. Romen.
                            during the Basic  Research Method  Training Workshop  at Tagaytay Lake,
                            Tagaytay City last November 13-15, 2018.















                       Figure  52.  The  CvSU-  College  of  Nursing  participants  together  with  the
                               facilitator  and  respectable  speakers  from  the  University  of  the
                               Philippines,  Manila.  (middle)  Dr.  Ophelia  Mendoza,  (right)  Dr.  Ofelia
                               Saniel. and (Left) Dr. Rommel Salazar from DLSU,Dasmarinas, Cavite.







                      44]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Figure 61. Faculty researchers from CvSU are continuously invited to participate
                             in  the  different  training  and  workshops  for  the  research  development
                             mentored by the DOST-PCHRD scientist and experts for capacity building as
                             member institution. This training is on Regional Disaster Research Training
                             held at Alabang in July 2018 hosted by Regional Consortium with speakers
                             from DOH Disaster Unit and DOST.



                      B.3.3. Fifth Multidisciplinary Research Forum


                               To continue with the college objective of supporting the CvSU goal of being
                      Research  University  in  2020,  the  faculty  members  have  submitted  research
                      proposals, the presented faculty and students researches and extension papers in

                      local and international conferences.
                               Hence, in May 17, 2019, Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo along with the nursing

                      alumni, Mr. Laurence Castro and Ms. Marielle Gaitan have presented their research
                      paper  entitled  “Lived  Experiences  of  Individuals  Living  with  Human
                      Immunodeficiency Virus Ages 18-30 in City of Dasmariñas, Cavite” during the 5
                                                                                                      th
                      Multidisciplinary  Research  forum  hosted  by  PCHRD  at  De  la  Salle  University,
                      Dasmarinas City.

















                      45]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Figure 62. Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo, the College Dean and   Faculty  Mr. Rolando
                               P. Antonio, Ms. Jocelyn B. Dimayuga,Ms. Charmaine Rosales, Ms Hazel
                               Guiao    and  College  Alumni  Mr  .Louie  Castro  and  Ms.    Mariel    Gaitan
                               participated on the 5  Multidisciplinary Research forum hosted by PCHRD
                                                  th
                               at De la Salle University, Dasmarinas City, Cavite. They have received a
                               certificate of participation during the event.

                      B.  3.  4.  Participation  in  the  Philippine  National  Health  Research  System
                      (PNHRS) conferences and events


































                      Figure 63. CvSU College of Nursing faculty, Prof Panaligan as one of the

                      representative of the PCHRD Region IV-A Consortium to the PNHRS Conference.


                      46]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[B. 3. 5   Training of Trainers for Regional Research Development and
                      Capacity Building


                             With the ongoing partnership, CvSU through the college helps in region-wide
                      development and capacity building of human resources for research. Recently held

                      last  March  9-13,  2021,  through  the  invitation  of  the  consortium,  Prof.  Nenita  B.
                      Panaligan  attended  the  Basic  Research  Method  Training  of  Trainers  via  virtual
                      conferencing  which  will  help  to  capacitate  budding  researchers  from  various

                      member’s institutions including CvSU to be more knowledgeable on the application
                      and basic skills in writing a research proposal or project proposal in order to achieve

                      Region IV Unified Health Research Agenda.


































                      Figure 64.  Virtual Training of DOST Trainers on Basic Research Methods with Prof.
                      Panaligan as representative of Region IV-A CALABARZON  held March 9-13, 2021.



                      C. International


                               The  College  of  Nursing  has  its  goal  of  establishing  linkages  with
                      public/private  institutions  to  generate  more  funds  for  research  and  Instruction

                      Exploring some ways of getting some aids and provisions from colleagues, friends,
                      47]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[and people who are sharing their wealth for some humanitarian purposes. The CoN

                      faculty   members take every chances to benchmark in every opportunity they have
                      while  doing  their  international  paper  presentation,  trainings  or  seminars,  For  the
                      same global vision of the university and the college, to be one of the nation’s leading

                      nursing institution in providing excellent instruction and opportunities for research,
                      practice and service.


                      C.1.  The  research  paper  Adventure  Relaxation  and  Theatrical  Therapy
                      Among Older Persons with Depression in Selected Barangays of Dasmariñas

                      City, Cavite
                               Dr. Evelyn Del Mundo (adviser) presented their research paper Adventure

                      Relaxation  and  Theatrical  Therapy  Among  Older  Persons  with  Depression  in
                      Selected  Barangays  of  Dasmariñas  City,  Cavite  in  SEAAIR  2016,  Suan  Dusit
                      Rajabhat  University,  Bangkok,  Thailand  (Figure  55).  This  research  paper  was

                      authored by Andrea Mariz Baliguat, Kimberly Cyrelle Anne Enage and Allysa Toni
                      Marie Salud


                             The chance of sharing of experiences, knowledge, or possible partnership
                      was taken into consideration. (Figure 57). The College of Nursing is seeing this

                      opportunity of meeting people from conferences like the President, Director, and
                      Guest  speaker  of  SEAAIR2016  in  Suan  Dusit  Rajabhat  University,  Bangkok,
                      Thailand (Figure 58).

























                       Figure 65. Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo, take her chances to benchmark in Suan
                               Dusit Rajabhat University, Bangkok, Thailand.






                      48]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Figure 66. Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo was able to meet the President,  Director,
                               and Guest speaker of SEAAIR2016 in Suan Dusit Rajabhat University,
                               Bangkok, Thailand.










































                      Figure 67.  Dr.  Evelyn  M.  Del Mundo  presented  their  research  paper  entittled
                               “Adventure  Relaxation  and  Theatrical  Therapy  Among  Older  Persons
                               With Depression In Selected Barangays Of Dasmariñas City, Cavite” in
                               SEAAIR 2016, Suan Dusit Rajabhat University, Bangkok, Thailand.

                      C.2. The College of Nursing takes every opportunity they can get by sending

                      faculty  members  to  different  parts  of  the  country  and  abroad  in  order  to
                      establish linkages and collaboration.



                      49]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo, Prof. Nenita B. Panaligan,, Ms. Caridad Lintao

                      and  Mr.  Jay  Louie  S.  Madlangbayan  and  other  faculty  members  were  able  to
                      participate in conferences in the country and abroad to determine the best practices
                      of different universities that can be adopted for the betterment of CON. It shows the

                      relevance of international travel of, the faculty member of the college, to some places
                      they visited and the people they met. The further enhancement of skills in attending
                      international research presentation and seminars will give new ideas for innovations

                      and improvement.

































                      Figure 68. Associate Professor Nenita B. Panaligan during her oral presentation
                            entitled “Lived Experiences of Mangyan Mothers on Infant Care at Home:
                            Phenomenological Study”. The presentation was held at the APRU Global
                            Health Workshop, New South Wales Australia in 2016.



















                      Figure 69. The new faculty members from the College of Nursing are also given
                            the opportunity to attend workshops, seminars and conferences in different
                            parts of the country and abroad to determine the best practices of different
                            universities that can be adopted for the betterment of CON.
                      50]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[C.3.  In collaboration with UP Open University, Manila, Philippines, a research
                      study entitled: “It Takes Two to Learn: Self-Regulated Learning and Clinical

                      Learning Environment using a mixed design” was conducted and presented.
                               This  research  paper  used  mixed  design  at  the  Clinical  Learning

                      Environment and Supervision (CLES) and was presented in a symposium held in
                      Chieti,  Italy  on  September  24-25,  2018  (Figure  61).    This  research  paper  is  a
                      collaborative effort  of  all  the  authors  and co-authors  namely:  Asst.  Prof.  Rita  C.

                      Ramos,  Jolly  Balila,  PhD,  Mary  Joanne  Therese  V.  Kourdache,  Ma.Elma  L.
                      Mirandilla,  Associate Prof. Nenita B. Panaligan and Lenila A. de Vera, RN, MAN











































                       Figure 70. Assoc. Prof. Nenita B. Panaligan is a co-author of the research paper
                          presented by Asst.Prof. Aldin Gaspar in a Symposium held in Chieti, Italy  on
                          September  24-25,  2018.  entitled:    It  Takes  Two  to  Learn:  Self-Regulated
                          Learning  and  Clinical  Learning  Environment  using  a  mixed  design”  in
                          collaboration with UP Open University, Manila,  Philippines

                      51]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[C.3 Another collaborative activity of the College of Nursing is an International

                      webinar entitled “How Do Health Care Professionals Correct Misinformation in
                      Social Media”


                                This is  a  joined project  of  Cavite  State University-College  of  Nursing  in
                      collaboration with Beta Nu Delta Nursing Society for Humanity and Filipino  Nursing

                      Diaspora Network (FiND) for Humanity entitled “How Do Health Care Professionals
                      Correct Misinformation in Social Media”.   The main objective of this webinar is to
                      counter COVID-19 misinformation in social media and strengthen media and digital

                      literacy capacities in the field of health care system (Figure 62).































                      Figure  71.  The  international  webinar  entitled  “How  do  Health  Care  Professional
                          Correct Misinformation in Social Media” was conducted live and streamed via
                          Cisco Webex and attended by a hundred of participants on August 29, 2020 at
                          10:00 in the morning.























                      52]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[Figure 72. The University  President Dr. Hernando D.  Robles  have delivered  his
                             inspirational  message  during  the  international  webinar  entitled  “How  do
                             Health Care Professional Correct Misinformation in Social Media”


                      C.4 The second partnership of the Cavite State University College of Nursing
                      with  the  Filipino  Nursing  Diaspora  Network  (FiND  Network)  is  another
                      International  Webinar  focusing  on  the  Evidenced-Based  Community

                      Interventions for Filipinos in the Global Fora.
                               This  webinar  entitled  “Evidenced  based  Community  Interventions  for

                      Diabetes and Hypertension among Filipino Americans: Global implications, was held
                           th
                      on 27  February 2021 via zoom. It was attended by more than 150 nurses, nursing
                      students and other participants coming from various hospital and health facilities,

                      community health centers, educational sectors and companies employing nurses in
                      the Philippines among others.


                               A seasoned  Professor Dr.  Maria Danet  Lapiz Bluhm  was invited  as  the
                      resource speaker in this webinar and the  focal point of her presentation was  the

                      current data and statistics of Filipino living in America, particularly those residents in
                      California  who  were  afflicted  with  Diabetes  and  Hypertension  (Figure  64).
                      Furthermore,  Dr.  Bluhm  reiterated  the  importance  of  disease  awareness  and

                      educating people in the community regarding the effects of these disabling illness.
                      Questions from the participants and other attendees were addressed accordingly by
                      the resource speaker.










                      53]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[Figure 73. Professor Dr. Maria Danet Lapiz Bluhm is the resource speaker in the
                            international webinar entitled “Evidenced based Community Interventions for
                            Diabetes  and  Hypertension  among  Filipino  Americans:  Global  implications
                            held on 27  February 2021 via zoom .
                                      th

                               This webinar commenced at around 10:00 AM and ended past 12:00 NN.
                      Right after the activity, a  post evaluation was done  and a brief dialogue  between
                      FiND the representative in the US, Mr. Jerome Babate and the College of Nursing,

                      Cavite State University as the partner host in this webinar and discussed matters
                      pertaining  to  next  series  of  webinar  on  April  16,  2021.  The  memorandum  of

                      understanding was written between the College of Nursing and the Filipino Nursing
                      Diaspora Network (FiND Network).

                      C.5 The third partnership of the Cavite State University College of Nursing

                      with the Filipino Nursing Diaspora Network (FiND Network) is another
                      International Webinar focusing on the Perils of Predatory Publishing: How

                      can nurse Researchers lead the way?

                      This webinar entitled “Perils of Predatory Publishing: How can nurse Researchers

                                                         th
                      lead the way? This was held on 16  April 2021 via zoom. It was attended by more
                      than  180  nurses,  nursing  students  and  other  participants  coming  from  various

                      hospital and  health  facilities,  community health  centers,  educational  sectors  and
                      companies employing nurses in the Philippines, among others.


                      An  experienced  Professor  Dr.  Leodoro  Labrague  was  invited  as  the  resource
                      speaker in this webinar and the focal point of his presentation was the current “ Perils

                      of Predatory Publishing: How can nurse Researchers lead the way?“. (Figure 65).
                      54]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[He has published more 70 articles in high impact journals of nursing including, Nurse

                      Education Today, Journal of Nursing Scholarship, Journal of Clinical Nursing, and
                      Journal of Nursing Management. Recently, his name was  also included in the Top
                      2% Scientist in the World in 2020, based on the report by Stanford University. His

                      research interests included simulation, nurse practice environment, toxic leadership,
                      caring sciences, disaster nursing.

                      Furthermore, Dr. Labrague reiterated the importance of recognition and educating

                      nursing  researchers  the  risks  of  Predatory  Publishing.  Questions  from  the
                      participants  and  other  attendees  were  addressed  accordingly  by  the  resource

                      speaker.
































                      Figure 74. Professor Leodoro Labrague is the resource speaker in the international

                      webinar entitled “Perils of Predatory Publishing: How can nurse researchers lead the
                      way?” held on 16th April 2021 via zoom. The reaction on how nurses can lead the

                      way was given by Prof. Nenita B. Panaligan, faculty of CvSU CON and as the current
                      Philippine Nursing Research Society Cavite Cell President.











                      55]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[1.2.3. EXTENSION LINKAGES



                                   Conduct of extension to local communities has always been a practice of
                      CON as well as with other stakeholders. The college was able to address the specific
                      needs  of  the  community  through  extension  programs,  projects,  and  activities  in

                      collaboration with other agencies and linkages that can be of help in the resolution.
                      With this endeavor of the college, the students were able to know different concerns

                      and needs in which they can help to the best that they can. In the process they will
                      become good  professional,  better  and  responsible person.  When  the  College  of
                      Nursing faculty members conduct extension activities in the adapted communities,

                      the  students  are  enjoined  to  participate  in  various  health  promotion  and  health
                      education  activities.  In  line  with  this  mandate,  the  College  is  in  the  process  of
                      strengthening  not  only  in  terms  of  research  but  also  the  local,  regional  and

                      international linkages in extension services.


                      A.  Local


                                 To make the College responsive to  the demands of a changing  society,
                      particularly of health needs of the populace, and the research for national identity and

                      quality  nursing  education,  the  College  of  Nursing  has  built-  in  mechanism  on  a
                      continuous  self-  assessment  through  local  extension  services  capabilities  and
                      program thrusts.



                               This linkage in extension was started by a  Memorandum of Agreement of
                      Extension  Services  between  Indang  LGU,  Brgy.  Kayquit    III,  Indang  Cavite    and
                      College of Nursing , Cavite State University signed by Dr. Hernando D. Robles and

                      Municipal Mayor Hon. Perfecto V. Fidel.(Figure 66).
























                      56]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[Figure  75.  The  Memorandum  of  Agreement  of  Extension  Services  between
                             Indang LGU, Brgy. Kayquit  III, Indang Cavite  and College of Nursing , Cavite
                             State  University  signed  by  Dr.  Hernando  D.  Robles  and  Municipal  Mayor
                             Hon. Perfecto V. Fidel.



                               Approved Communication Letter from Director Extension Unit and    CvSU
                      University President, was facilitated by the college. The Term of References of Faculty
                      Members for Extension ARUGA Project was approved on September 12, 2018 (Figure

                      76).
































                           Figure  76.  The  approved  letter  of  ARUGA  Project  under  CoN  CARES  was
                               approved on September 12, 2018



                               Figure 68 shows that the College of Nursing is continuously conducting
                        extension activities as part of the partnerships between CoN and the community
                      57]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[of Kayquit, Indang, Cavite for many years. Initial meetings done on September

                        13, 2018 with Barangay Health Workers and Officials, Committee on Health and
                        Nutrition,  (L-R)  Prof.  Panaligan  Project  Leader,  Prof.  Ferrera  Extension
                        Coordinator  and  Ms.  Mary  Antoniette  Viray  –  faculty  extensionist  /  GAD  with

                        Kagawad. Fernando Feranil and Kagawad. Nelson Suarez and Secretary Lilian
                        Tiglao, September 13, 2018.





























                       Figure 77. the meetings were conducted with barangay kayquit iii officials in the
                          planning and implementation of the project.

                               The group has a regular visit  in Kayquit explaining the project and  the
                        conceptual framework of the ARUGA Child Care Program. Planning about the

                        project was deliberated by  the attendees and all  suggestions were taken  into
                        consideration in the proposal based on the children’s needs and assessments.


                               Figure  69  shows  Prof.  Nenita  B.  Panaligan  and  Mrs.  SJ  Tiglao,  the
                        Barangay  Health  Worker  assigned  in  Purok  4  Barangay  Kayquit  3,  worked
                        together for the retrieval of health data on existing child health programs, and

                        some  health  information  most  common  illnesses  among  the  0  -5  years  old
                        children in the  barangay. Subsequently,  home visits were  done with  selected
                        volunteer students  BSN Level  2 for  VS monitoring,  weight, and  immunization

                        status and survey on most common illnesses in the last 3 months.












                      58]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[Figure 78.  Prof. Panaligan meeting with Mrs. SJ Tiglao, the Barangay Health
                            Worker  assigned  in  Purok  4  Barangay  Kayquit  3,  asking  some  health
                            information about most common illnesses among the 0-5 years old children
                            in the barangay.
































                      Figure 79. The project leader, Prof. Panaligan lead in the conduct of community
                            visit  (Home  visits)  with  selected  volunteer  students  BSN  Level  2  for  VS
                            monitoring, weight, and immunization status and survey on most common
                            illnesses in the last 3 months.


                               Meanwhile,  the  College  of  Nursing  Community  Advancement  through
                      Research  and        Extension  Services  (CON  CARES)  have  continue  another
                      program based on the needs assessment done among care of the elderly persons.

                      This activity orientation for BHW-Caregiver Training Seminar on Basic Caregiving

                      59]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[skills in caring elderly persons  (Figure 67) was facilitated  by Dr. Evelyn M.  Del

                      Mundo together with  Sunny Rose M. Ferrera, Jocelyn B. Dimayuga, Maribel Chua,
                      Phaebi B. Romen and Ernelito Chua last March 5, 2020.
































                      Figure 80.  Dr.  Evelyn  del Mundo  during  the  orientation on  the  beneficiaries  of
                            training on Basic Caregiving Skills at Kayquit, Indang Cavite.































                      Figure 81. The College of Nursing in collaboration with the Cavite State University
                                    Multipurpose Cooperative organized a medical mission to Senior Citizen of
                                    Brgy Buna Cerca, Indang Cavite last December 15, 2017.  Our College
                                    Professor Dr. Annie Ramos was invited as medical doctor for consultation
                                    with our Nursing Alumni Dr. Emilio Gabriel Santiago who is a Resident
                                    Physician in the College of Nursing base hospital, General Emilio Aguinaldo
                                    Memorial Hospital. The Level III  nursing students helps our college to

                      60]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[facilitate   client’s assessment and orderliness of the said event.
























                      Figure 82. Photos showing faculty from the College of Nursing conducting
                                  assessments and ECG procedures on patients during a medical mission. In
                                  addition, the Cavite State University Multipurpose  Cooperative officers also
                                  attended together with the College of Nursing Faculty extensionist.















































                       Figure 83.  The copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between Cavite State
                                  University  Multipurpose Cooperative and Cavite State University, College of
                                  Nursing.

                      61]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[C. University Wide Research and Extension Activities


                               The participation of the College of Nursing in the university wide activities
                      in research and extension  week is one  strategy of CoN  to strengthen the  quality

                      performance towards excellence. The attendees of the College are the following: Dr.
                      Evelyn M. Del Mundo – Dean, Nenita Panaligan – Quality Assurance  Committee,
                      Rolando  Antonio  –  Research  Coordinator,  Sunny  Rose  Ferrera  –  Extension

                      Coordinator, and Phaebi Romen – Extensionist. Aside from celebration, this event
                      provides a wide range of information to enhance the knowledge and skills when it
                      comes to this aspect. The three days’ program held last September 4  – 6, 2018

                      attended by different people of this University and also the guest from the adapted
                      communities.



























                      Figure 84. The speakers: Prof. Ronald U. Mendoza – Dean of Ateneo Manila, and
                          Dr. Custer C. Deocaris – Head, Reasearch Management of CHED  together with
                          the   College  Dean  Dr.  Evelyn Del  Mundo,  College  Guidance  Counselor  ,Dr.
                          Bernadette Sapinoso and the College  Secretary Phaebi Romen, Sunny Rose
                          Ferrera and College Extension Coordinator as participants from the College


                      B.  Regional/National

                        B.1. Cavite State University, College of Nursing have joined efforts and

                        partnership  with  the  Philippine  Red  Cross.  -  Cavite  Blood  Council,
                        Provincial Government of Cavite for a Blood Letting Activity.

                              The  college  has  been  continuously  providing  unwavering  support  and

                        contribution  to  provide  safe,  accessible  and  adequate  blood  supply  for  the
                        province through the promotion of voluntary blood donation in the University. HIV

                        Awareness seminar was conducted simultaneously with bloodletting activity the
                      62]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[Resource Speaker is one of the CON faculty member. This was attended by

                        students,  faculty,  staff  of  CoN  as  well  as  students  from  different  colleges,
                        community people from Kayquit and different barangays of Indang Cavite. They
                        are all voluntarily donating blood (Figure 73).

                               The Bloodletting program in collaboration with the Philippine Red Cross has

                      been done yearly. The college accepted the joint activities with the Red Cross Youth,
                      Pledge 25, Blood Donation Drive since 2019.






























                         Figure 85. Registration and vital signs taking prior to screening of possible blood
                             donors then Blood Screening followed by collection of blood in a designated
                             area for extraction.


                               From the time the College of Nursing collaborated with Red Cross Youth,
                        Pledge  25,  Blood  Donation  Drive,  the  college  have  won  the  following  awards:
                        Champion Pledge 25: Blood Olympics 2019, Champion, Bayanihan Award: Most

                        Organized Mobile Blood Drive, Award: School with the Number of Blood Donors
                        yielding 267 Blood Units given by the Philippine Red Cross on January 11, 2020

                        at City Mall Anabu Event and Activity Center, Imus Cavite (Figure 74).




















                      63]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[Figure 150.   The College of Nursing won the following awards: Champion Pledge
                     25:  Blood  Olympics  2019,  Champion,  Bayanihan  Award:  Most  Organized  Mobile
                      Figure 86.  The plaque and awards of the College of Nursing from  Pledge 25:
                     Blood  Drive,  Award:  School  with  the  Number  of  Blood  Donors  yielding  267  Blood
                     Units  given  by  the  Philippine  Red  Cross  on  January  11,  2020  at  City  Mall  Anabu
                            Blood Olympics 2019,  given by  the Philippine  Red Cross  on January  11,
                     Event and Activity Center, Imus Cavite.

                            2020 at City Mall Anabu Event and Activity Center, Imus Cavite.



                      C.  2. Another extension activity that the College have done continuously for

                          many years is the Seminar on HIV Awareness and “Bloodletting”
                               The  CoN  conducted  a  Seminar  on  HIV  Awareness  and  Bloodletting
                      simultaneously and has been a substantial part of extension. of Nursing, Midwifery

                      and Medical Technology Department (Figure 75). CoN Students have been active
                      partakers since the beginning of the activity. In recognition of this, the college was
                                                                                      nd
                      hailed Champion in Blood Olympics in 2011, received award as 2 place in Blood
                      Olympics in 2012, given Kabalikat Award in 2014, recognized as Best Performing
                      University in 2015.


























                      Figure 87. The  staff, BHW and  Barangay officials of  Indang RHU and  Barangay
                            Kayquit 3, Indang  Cavite together with  the CON faculty  members and  staff
                            during the Seminar on HIV  Awareness

                      64]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[B.3.  The  Cavite  State  University,  College  of  Nursing  signed  a  Memorandum  of

                      Agreement with the Philippine Nurses Association- Cavite Chapter on November 21,
                      2019. This MOA (Figure 72) was the start of collaborative activities such as General

                      Assembly, election of officers, seminars, webinars, conferences, gift-giving activities
                      during  the  volcanic  eruption,  donation  drives  for  the  victims,  frontliners  faculty
                      members, staff and other stakeholders in the Region and other places in the country.


                               B.3.1.  The  Philippine  Nurses  Association-  Cavite  Chapter  Annual
                      Conference  and  General  Assembly  in  collaboration  with  Cavite  State

                      University- College of Nursing
                               This partnership was conducted on  November 23, 2019. Cavite  Chapter

                      Officers with the guest speakers Professional Regulatory Commission (PRC) Board
                      of Nursing ,  Zeny Concepcion and  Dr. Lorenza Serafica , Nurse V from Department
                      of Health (DOH) Regional Office  during the First Scientific Nursing Conference and

                      PNA General Assembly in the SM Rolle Hall, CvSU, Main Campus (Figure 76).





































                      Figure 88.  Copy of the approved Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU -
                            College of Nursing and  PNA-Cavite Chapter.










                      65]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[Figure  89.  College  of  Nursing  Faculty  and  also  the  current  Philippine  Nurse
                            Association officers during the 1  Scientific Conference and PNA General
                                                           st
                            Assembly

                      B.3.2. Christmas Love Gift “Distribution of Dental and Hygiene Kit to Brgy. San
                      Juan, Ternate Kids conducted by the College of Nursing in collaboration with

                      The Philippine Nurses Association Cavite Chapter last December 20, 2019.


                               As  part  of  the  linkages  between  Philippine  Nurses  Association-  Cavite
                      Chapter and  the Cavite State University - College of Nursing,  a Love Project was
                      conducted for the Children residing nearby the coastal seaside of  Sitio Aplaya at

                      Brgy San Juan 1, Ternate Cavite. Two typhoons have hit this purok (Typhoon Tisoy
                      and  Ursula)  last  November  2019  and  December  2019,  as  well  as  strong  wind
                      (Habagat and  Amihan) which bring about to devastation of some nipa houses put

                      up by mostly of migrant residents and some native of Brgy. San Juan.
                               The  distribution  of  Love  Project  was  initiated  by  the  College  of  Nursing
                      Faculty and PNA Cavite Chapter President Prof.  Nenita B. Panaligan. Together with

                      the former Dean of  CvSU, College of Nursing  and also a previous    PNA  Cavite
                      Chapter President  Prof.    Lenila  A.  De  Vera,  she is  also  the  current      House  of

                      Delegates  officer  of  PNA  Cavite  Chapter.    There  were  also      Ms.  Jocelyn  B.
                      Dimayuga, CvSU faculty too and currently a member of PNA   Board of Directors
                      together with Dr. Annalyn Nazareno, the Chief Nurse of City of General Trias Doctors

                      Medical Center and also, Board of Directors, officer too of PNA Cavite Chapter and
                      Ms. Tess  Magante, the  Chief  Nurse of  Maragondon  Community Hospital,  a  PNA

                      Cavite Chapter Auditor.






                      66]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[Figure 90. Faculty from the College of Nursing Professor Nenita B. Panaligan and
                            Ms. Jocelyn B. Dimayuga along with former  College Dean Lenila De Vera and
                            other  members of  PNA Cavite Chapter while  distributing love gift to the school
                            children at sea side at Brgy. San Juan 2, Ternate ,Cavite





























                      Figure 91.  CvSU faculty with PNA Cavite Chapter Officers and the recipients  of
                          love gifts at Brgy San Juan 2, Ternate Cavite.



                      B.3.3. CvSU - College of Nursing In collaboration with PNA Cavite Chapter and
                      PCHRD
                               Cavite State University-  College of  Nursing Faculty  members and  CON-

                      Student Council in cooperation with Philippine Nurses Association- Cavite Chapter
                      joined hand in hand in helping the victims, evacuees   and families affected by the



                      67]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[Taal volcano eruption such as evacuation centers in Alfonso, Magallanes, Ternate,

                      and Indang, Cavite.

































                      Figure 92. Cavite State University- College of Nursing Faculty and CON- Student
                            Council  in  cooperation  with  PNA-  Cavite  Chapter  while  distributing  relief
                            goods to affected victims of the Taal eruption such as evacuation centers in
                            Alfonso, Magallanes, Ternate, and Indang, Cavite
































                       Figure 93.  CvSU students and faculty during distribution of relief goods to the
                             beneficiaries.






                      68]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[D.  College  of  Nursing  “COVID-19  Projects  for  Cavite  Nurses  Welfare”–
                          Reaching  out  the  Frontliners  and  other  stakeholders  in  different

                          institutions


                               College of Nursing, COVID-19 Projects for Cavite Nurses Welfare includes
                      the distribution of washable face mask, face shield, food packs and water to different
                      hospitals in Cavite including some front liners in different LGU’s of Cavite last March,

                      April, May 2020.



























                       Figure 94.  The distribution of washable face mask, face shield was facilitated by
                               the College of Nursing Faculty and SC adviser, Mr. Louis Carlos Roderos.



























                       Figure 95.  The distribution of washable face mask, face shield, food packs and
                             water to different private and government hospitals of Cavite and  our alumni
                             who are currently working as  COVID 19 frontliners..




                      69]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[C.1.  COVID  19  Projects  for  Cavite  Nurses  Welfare,  Philippine  Nurses
                      Association, Cavite Chapter in collaboration with CVSU - College of Nursing

                      and some personal donations
                               C.1.1. The distribution of PPEs such as washable face mask, face shield

                      and gowns was also done by the PNA Cavite and CvSU - College of Nursing officers
                      and members. Ms. Marissa Datuin, has given a personal donation in collaboration
                      with PNA Cavite who donated food packs and water to different hospitals in Cavite

                      and some frontliners in different LGU’s of Cavite last March, April, May 2020 (Figure
                      84).

























                      Figure 96. Ms. Marissa Datuin, has given a personal donation in collaboration with
                            PNA Cavite who donated food packs and water to different hospitals in Cavite





































                      70]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[Figure 97.  Some  of  the beneficiaries  who  had  receive the  food  donations,  face
                          shields  and  facemasks.  Words  of  appreciation  was  posted  also  by  the
                          recipients.

                               C.1.2. Mr. Ivan Derek V. Wycoco donated blood in the Blood Donation
                      Program  conducted  by  the  Philippine  National  Red  Cross,  Dasmarinas

                      Chapter






























                      Figure 98. This action of the faculty member in doing voluntary blood donation is in
                                line with the call of more blood donors needed for COVID-19 patients and Non
                                COVID - 19 patients of the CoN partner organization, Philippine National Red
                                Cross last April 25,2020. The recipient of his donated blood is a cancer patient
                                in the hospital.





                      71]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[C.1.3. Mr. Ivan Derek Wycoco one of the faculty from the College of
                      Nursing personally distributed 205 food  packs for front liners and  Nursing

                      Service Office in different hospitals.























































                      Figure 99.  Mr. Ivan  Derek  Wycoco distributed  101 food  packs  for front  liners  in
                            General Trias Doctors Medical Center last April 18, 2020.  He also given 104
                            food packs for front liners in GentriMed Hospital, M.V. Santiago Medical Center
                            in Trece Martires City.,Cavite and General Emilio Aguinaldo Memorial Hospital
                            (CvSU base  hospital)      in  Trece  Martires  City,  Cavite  and  their  respective
                            Nursing Service Offices last April 24, 2020.









                      72]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[1.3 SYSTEMATIC AND EFFECTIVE PROCEDURES


                                               College of Nursing Academic Services

















































                            Figure 100. The general process flow of academic and clinical linkages




                               Figure  87  illustrates  the  general  process  flow  of  academic  and  clinical
                      linkages  implementation.  It  serves  as  a  general  guide  in  the  implementation  of

                      linkages thru different accredited institutions/partner agencies. A successful nursing
                      affiliation starts with the internal evaluation followed by assessment and approval of

                      the  university  legal  adviser.  All  partner  institutions  conduct  MOA/MOU  signing
                      ceremony after careful review, deliberation and plotting of several clinical areas for
                      rotation and   institutional orientation to both faculty and students. Memorandum of

                      agreement or  memorandum  of  understanding (MOA/MOU)  shall  be  executed  for
                      clinical affiliation from various institutions.



                      73]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[College of Nursing Research Services




























































                       Figure 101. The general process flow of the College of Nursing research linkages

                               Figure  85  shows  the  general  process  flow  of  research  linkages

                      implementation. It serves as a general guide in the implementation of a research
                      project.  Proposals  shall  come  from  the  faculty  member/researcher  of  the

                      departments of  the  College.  All  research projects  shall  be  properly  endorsed  by
                      concerned  office  or  authority.  Memorandum  of  agreement  or  memorandum  of
                      understanding  (MOA/MOU)  shall  be  executed  for  projects  involving  external

                      partners.  Proposals  as  well  as  research  project  outputs  may  be  required  to  be
                      presented during agency in-house review and evaluation.

                      74]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[College of Nursing Extension Services




































                      Figure 102. The general process flow of the College of Nursing Extension Services
                                     to Funding agency/partner for subsequent MOA/MOU



                                Figure 102 indicates the general process flow of research and extension
                      program implementation. It serves  as a general guide  in the implementation of  a

                      research  or  extension  project.  Proposals  shall  come  from  the  faculty
                      member/researcher  of  the  departments  of  the  College.  All  research/extension
                      projects shall be properly endorsed by concerned office or authority. Memorandum

                      of agreement or memorandum of understanding (MOA/MOU) shall be executed for
                      projects involving external partners. Proposals as well as research/extension project
                      outputs  may  be  required  to  be  presented  during  agency  in-house  review  and

                      evaluation.














                      75]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[Table 2. REASONABLE BUDGET




                            DESCRIPTION                  PERIOD         AMOUNT        SOURCE OF
                                                          COVER                         BUDGET


                    Renewal Fee For Organization         2021-2022      150,00.00       Fund 164
                    Membership , MOA/MOU


                    Webinars, seminars, fora,            2021-2022      150,00.00       Fund 164
                    conferences meetings and other
                    linkages activities including

                    honorarium, accommodation,
                    certificates, tokens and plaques

                    Communication Fee                    2021-2022      30,000.00       Fund 164


                    School supplies, ICT materials,      2021-2022      70,000.00       Fund 164
                    and equipment


                    TRANSPORTATION                       2021-2022      50,000.00       Fund 164
                    SERVICES

                    TOTAL                                                   Php

                                                                        450,000.00



























                      76]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[COLLEGE OF NURSING LINKAGES FUTURE DIRECTIONS





































                             Figure 103. The future and directions of the College of Nursing Linkages


                               The  figure  shows  that  the  College  of  Nursing  develop  a  road  map  and
                      served as the main vehicle to build alliance with foreign institutions and established

                      mutual partnership. Likewise, this roadmap was designed as the specific pathway
                      that would direct and guide the College in achieving the goals and objectives in the

                      implementation of its strategic planning.
                               As shown in the diagram above, the road passing the first step with red
                      thumb signifies the active participation of the faculty and students in local, regional,

                      national  and  international  professional  organizations,  and  through  regular
                      attendance in conferences and research fora. The second step is represented by
                      yellow thumb that will encompass the College capacity building through an in-depth

                      collaborative  research  both  local  and  foreign,  and  expanding  linkages  with  other
                      prospective  organizations  that  may  leading  to  more  engagement  in  conducting
                      funded research.

                               The third step with blue thumb going to the right direction, indicates that the
                      college will be  more creative in  utilizing assets  and resources of  CvSU, and  will

                      mobilize its alumni to be more proactive in the college. On the other hand, the fourth
                      step with lavender thumb moving  to the left direction  implies that there would  be


                      77]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[further agreement between the faculty and students in a form of exchange as well

                      as in hosting and co-hosting.
                               Finally,  the  fifth  step  with  blue  thumb  passing  to  the  right  direction  will
                      encapsulates  an  efficient  and  long-lasting  partnership  between  the  College  of

                      Nursing and its international linkages that may lead to globalization, ensuring that
                      more international linkages would be sustained and maintained.
                               In visioning for global milestones, the College of Nursing is in its continuous

                      efforts  on  establishing  partnerships  and  collaborations  with  local,  national  and
                      international stakeholders for academic and curricular exchanges, collaborative and
                      multidisciplinary research partnerships and sustained extension programs which is

                      contributory and relevant to the society’s development.































































                      78]]></page></pages></Search>