<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="164"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[TABLE OF CONTENTS



                                                                                                         Page

                             1. INSTRUCTION…………………………………………….……………5

                             1.1 WELL DEFINED OBJECTIVES…………………………….……...5

                             1.2 ADEQUATE AND RELEVANT PROJECTS

                             /ACTIVITIES TO ACHIEVE OBJECTIVES …………………………….11


                                      1.2.1. Updating of curriculum to maintain local.

                              and global relevance of    instruction……………………………………13

                                      1.2.2 Acquisition of state-of-the-art facilities for

                             teaching and learning activities……………………………………………15

                                      1.2.3. Continuous faculty and staff development…………….25


                                      1.2.3.1. Attendance of faculty and staff to …………………….26

                             various conferences, seminars, workshops, and trainings

                                      1.2.3.2. Continuing education through on-line learning………28

                                      1.2.3.3. Faculty development through graduate education….30

                                      1.2.4. Student Development Activities………………………….31


                                      1.2.4.1 Learning through research and extension…………….34

                                      1.2.5. Benchmarking and adoption of globally
                              relevant practices for learning…………………………………………….43


                                      1.2.6. Subjecting the BS Nursing Program

                             to evaluation and accreditation…………………………………………….53


                                                                                                            1]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[Page
                               1.2.7. Establishment, development and strengthening.


                               of linkages with various institutions for overall

                               improvement of instruction………………………………………………57

                                1.2.8. Conduct of open topic seminars/ talks…………………………79



                        1.3 SYSTEMATIC AND EFFECTIVE PROCEDURES ……………………..82




                               1.3.1 Periodic Review of Curriculum………………………………….82


                        The Bachelor of Science in Nursing program has undergone.


                                1.3.2. Continuous Updating of Syllabi…………………………………84

                               1.3.3. Use of Relevant Teaching Strategies and

                        Development of Instructional Materials……………………………………….87



                        PROGRAM DESCRIPTION


                                1.3.4 Administrative Support for Effective

                         Instruction and Enhancement of Learning……………………………………95

                               1.3.5. Assessment of Academic Performance

                               of Students……………………………………………………………….107

                               1.3.6. Assessment of Graduates………………………………………114

                                      1.3.6.1. Performance in the Philippine Nursing

                                       Licensure Examination…………….……………………….…..116




                                                                                                            2]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[Page
                                          1.3.6.2 Employability of graduates and
                          employers’ feedback………………………………………………..…….121


                          1.4 REASONABLE BUDGET ……………………………………….….139

                        1.5 PROVISION OF MATERIALS AND OTHER RESOURCES…….140


                                1.5.1. Human Resources…………………………………………140


                                1.5.2. Physical Resources………………………………………...141




                        1.6. PARTICIPATION OF SIGNIFICANT NUMBER OF


                        FACULTY/STAFF IN MAJOR PROJECTS/ ACTIVITIES…………….144

                        1.7. AWARDS OF DISTINCTION AND ACHIEVEMENT

                        AND GRANTS OF THE BS NURSING PROGRAM…………………...146



























                                                                                                            3]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[PROGRAM DESCRIPTION





                                The  Bachelor  of  Science  in  Nursing  (BSN)  is  a  four-year  program


                        consisting of general education and professional courses. Professional courses

                        are threaded from the first year through the fourth year with emphasis on the


                        nursing concepts with corresponding Related Learning Experiences (RLE). The

                        BSN program provides an intensive nursing practicum that will refine further the


                        nursing competencies to ensure achievement of the BSN program outcomes

                        required of an entry level nurse.


                                To ensure the quality of the nursing graduate, the degree is conferred

                        upon  completion  of  at  least  four-year  BSN  program  offered  by  a  college,


                        professional  institution  or  university  duly  recognized  by  the  Commission  on

                        Higher Education. In the Philippines, the BSN degree is equivalent to level 6 in

                        the Philippine Qualifications Framework.




                        THE FOUR KEY ASSESSMENT AREAS:




                                1.   Instruction


                                2.   Linkages



                                3.   Extension


                                4.   Faculty Development











                                                                                                            4]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[1.INSTRUCTION



                       1.1    WELL DEFINED OBJECTIVES



                                By virtue of BOR Resolution No. 57, s. 2001, the Bachelor of Science in

                        Nursing (BSN) program was first offered under the Department of Biological


                        Sciences, College of Arts and Sciences (CAS), Cavite State University (CvSU).

                        The establishment of the Nursing Department in CAS which was approved as


                                                                  th
                        **excerpts  from  the  minutes  of  the  14 regular  meeting  of  the  Cavite  State
                        University  Board  of  Regents  held  on  December  6,  2001  at  the  CHED


                        conference  room  DAP  Building,  Pasig  City.  The  college  was  afterwards

                        converted  into  its  present  name,  the  College  of  Nursing  (CON)  was  then

                        separated from the College of Arts and Sciences.


                                The University Vision is to be “The premier University in historic Cavite

                        recognized  for  excellence  in  the  development  of  globally  competitive  and


                        morally upright individuals.” Its mission is to “provide excellent, equitable and

                        relevant educational opportunities in the arts, sciences, and technology through


                        quality  instruction  and  responsive  research  and  development  activities  to

                        produce  professional,  skilled  and  morally  upright  individuals  for  global


                        competitiveness.”

                                 For the CMO 14 series 2009, in accordance with pertinent provisions


                        of Republic Act (RA) No. 7722, otherwise known as the Higher Education Act

                        of 1994 and pursuant to Commission en Banc Resolution No. 170 dated April

                        19, 2009 and for the purpose of rationalizing Nursing Education in the country


                        in  order  to  provide  relevant  and  quality  health  services  locally  and


                                                                                                            5]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[internationally, policies and standards for Bachelor of Science in Nursing (BSN)

                        program are hereby adopted and promulgated by the Commission. It aims to


                        produce  a  fully  functioning  nurse  who  can  perform  the  competencies  under

                        each of the Key Areas of Responsibility as enumerated in Article IV Section 5


                        herein. Graduates of this program as beginning nurse practitioner may pursue

                        the following career paths but not limited to: Clinical Nursing, Community Health


                        Nursing, Private-duty Nursing, Occupational Health Nursing, School Nursing,

                        Military Nursing, Health Education, and Research.


                        Entrepreneurship and other allied programs.


                                 Presently, the college is having the new CMO No. 15 series 2017, it is

                        also in accordance with pertinent provisions of Republic Act (RA) No. 7722,


                        otherwise known as the “Higher Education Act of 1994”  in pursuance of  an

                        outcomes-based quality assurance system as advocated under CMO No. 46


                        series 2012 entitled “Policy Standards to Enhance Quality Assurance (QA) in

                        Philippine Higher Education Through an Outcome-Based and Typology-Based


                        QA,” and by virtue  of Commission  en Banc Resolution No. 231-2017  dated

                        March 28, 2017, there are policies, standards, and guidelines (PSGs) adopted

                        and promulgated by the Commission.


                                 This new BSN program aims to develop a professional nurse who is

                        able to assume entry level positions in health facilities or community settings.


                        The  professional  nurse  is  capable  of  providing  safe,  humane,  quality  and

                        holistic  care  to  individuals  in  varying  age,  gender  and  health-illness  status;


                        healthy  or  at-risk  families;  population  groups;  and  community;  singly  or  in




                                                                                                            6]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[collaboration  with  health  care  providers  to  promote  health,  prevent  illness,

                        restore health, alleviate suffering and provide end of life care.


                                 The  CMO  No.  15  series  2017,  program  outcomes  are  the  sets  of

                        competencies the related knowledge, skills, and attitudes that all learners are


                        expected  to  demonstrate  upon  graduation.  The  minimum  standards  for  the

                        BSN Nursing program are expressed in specific learning outcomes based on


                        14  core  competencies:  1)  apply  knowledge  of  physical,  social,  natural  and

                        health  sciences  and  humanities  in  the  practice  of  nursing;  2)  provide  safe


                        appropriate, and  holistic care to individuals, families, population  groups and

                        community  utilizing  nursing  process;  3)  apply  guidelines  and  principles  of


                        evidence-based  practice  in  the  delivery  of  care;  4)  practice  nursing  in

                        accordance  with  existing  laws,  legal,  ethical  and  moral  principles;  5)

                        communicate effectively in speaking, writing, and presenting using culturally


                        appropriate language; 6) document to include reporting up-to-date client care

                        accurately and comprehensively; 7) work effectively in collaboration with inter,


                        intra-and  multi-disciplinary  and  multi-cultural  teams;  8)  practice  beginning

                        management and leadership skills in the delivery of client care using a systems


                        approach; 9) conduct research with an experienced researcher; 10) engage in

                        lifelong  learning  with  a  passion  to  keep  current  with  national  and  global


                        developments in general, nursing and health developments in particular; 11)

                        demonstrate responsible citizenship  and  pride of being a Filipino;  12) apply


                        techno – intelligent care systems and processes in health care delivery; 13)








                                                                                                            7]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[adopt the nursing core values in the practice of the profession; and 14) apply

                        entrepreneurial skills in the delivery of nursing care.


                                 In terms of CHED’s horizontal typology, the BSN curriculum is based

                        on the functional differentiation of HEIs vis-avis their service to the nation. Being


                        one of the state university in the country, CvSU has a function of contributing

                        top nation building by providing highly specialized educational experiences to


                        train experts in the various technical, discipline and areas by emphasizing the

                        development of new knowledge and skills through research and development.


                        Universities contribute to nation building by producing experts, knowledge, and

                        technological  innovations  that  can  be  used  as  resources  for  long-term


                        development  processes  in  a  globalized  context  (CMO  No.  15  series  2017).

                        Graduates  of  state  universities  and  colleges  must,  in  addition,  have  the

                        competencies to support the national, regional, and local development plans.


                                 The College of Nursing set the following goals:


                                      1. Produce technically and scientifically oriented graduate imbued


                                        with  a  deep  sense  of  professionalism;  possess  strong  social

                                        consciousness and guided by positive values and high ethical

                                        standard.


                                      2. Conduct  evidence-based  research  and  extension  services

                                        towards the provision of safe, holistic and quality nursing care.


                                      3. Implement  effective  training  and  outreach  programs  that

                                        emphasize self-help, critical thinking, and lifelong learning.








                                                                                                            8]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[4. Establish  strong  linkage  with  non-  governmental  organization,

                                        other  government  entities  and  the  community  at  large  for  the


                                        realization of the common goals.


                                 With the same bases, and in line with the above-mentioned goals of

                          the  college,  the  Bachelor  of  Science  in  Nursing  program  (BSN)  aims  to


                          produce nurses who:

                                       1. Gainfully employed in various health care facilities.


                                       2. Can apply acquired knowledge and skills in various areas of


                                          specialization in nursing utilizing the nursing process, critical

                                          thinking, research which is guided by ethico-moral standard


                                          of nursing practice.

                                       3. Are  engaged  in  evidence-based  practice  research  for  the


                                          advancement of Nursing Profession.

                                       4. Able  to  speak  with  ease  and  confidence  at  all  levels  of


                                          communication within and outside the organization.

                                       5. Are engaged in various trainings, seminars, conferences, and


                                          graduate programs as a tool for career advancement; and

                                       6. Demonstrate safe nursing practice, commitment to service,

                                          that  is  gender  sensitive,  just  and  humane  with  social


                                          responsibility  to  the  needs  of  both  men  and  women  in  all


                                          settings across the lifespan.









                                                                                                            9]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[Figure  1.  The  Cavite  State  University  BS  Nursing  students  and  their  set  of
                         uniforms during their academic journey embodying the mission, vision , goals
                         and objectives of the college and the university.






                                                                                                           10]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[1.2. ADEQUATE AND RELEVANT PROJECTS /ACTIVITIES TO ACHIEVE
                       OBJECTIVES




                              The  College  of  Nursing  undertake  various  activities  in  instruction,

                         research, and extension in collaboration with various stakeholders. Alongside


                         with  these  is  the  continuous  development  of  the  faculty  for  the  quality

                         instruction and delivery of an effective curriculum. All these areas are regularly


                         intensified  to  achieve  the  objectives  of  the  program,  the  college,  and  the

                         university.



                               Relevant  activities  include  the  continuous  update  of  curriculum,


                          acquisition  of  state  of  the  art  facilities,  continuous  faculty  development,

                          student  development  activities,  adoption  of  globally  relevant  practices  for


                          learning,  accreditation  and  quality  assurance  activities,  establishing  and

                          strengthening linkages and conduct of varied learning opportunities all for

                          the realization of the program, college and university goals.




























                                                                                                           11]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[Figure  2.  The  university  vision  and  mission  and  quality  policy  as
                         overshadowing the college goals and objectives.








                                                                                                           12]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[Cavite State University Performance
                                            Philippine Nursing Licensure Examination

                                                              2016-2019



                          100%       95%                91%                                   89.09%
                                                                          76.92%
                           80%

                           60%                                                                     55.20%
                                         47.73%             45.65%
                                                                                39.98%
                           40%

                           20%


                            0%
                                                              CvSU   National

                              Figure 3. The Cavite State University overall performance on the Philippine
                              Nursing Licensure Examination Results   from 2016 -2019.


                        1.2.1. Updating of curriculum to maintain local and global relevance of
                        instruction.

                                The  Bachelor  of  Science  in  Nursing  program  has  undergone  three

                         revisions since it was first offered under the College of Arts and Sciences. By


                         virtue of BOR Resolution No. 57, series of 2001 approved on December 6, 2001,

                         the BSN curriculum CMO 30 at CvSU was offered. The College of Nursing was


                         separated from the College of Arts of Sciences on October 18, 2005 by virtue of

                         BOR Resolution No 48, s 2005. In year 2007, the incorporation of Associate in


                         Science  Health  Education  (ASHE),  a  general  nursing  curriculum  was

                         materialized.

                               The  second  revision  was  done  in  2009.  The  purpose  to  rationalize  the


                       nursing education in the country to provide relevant and quality health services

                       locally and internationally started the implementation of BSN curriculum CMO 14



                                                                                                           13]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[Series of 2009  pursuant to Commission en Banc Resolution No. 170 dated April

                       19, 2009.


                              The third Revision was in pursuant to the outcome-based quality education.

                       The  CHED Memorandum Order No. 15 Series of 2017 by virtue of Commission


                       en Banc Resolution No. 231-2017 dated March 28, 2017 was implemented.




























                              Figure 4. The curriculum review on the Bachelor of Science in Nursing
                              program held last July 25,2017 at the CON Arts Laboratory.


                                        Review and revision in curriculum are regularly undertaken to
                                enhance further the student learning, experiences, engagement, and

                                outcomes of the BSN program.  The revisions are carefully studied,
                                approved prior to its implementation




                          .

















                                                                                                           14]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[Figure  5.  The  curriculum  review  was  attended  by  the  faculty,  staff,
                              students,  alumni,  program  coordinators,  chief  nurses,  hospital
                              administrators, parents, and other stakeholders from the health sector
                              and the academe.




                       1.2.2      Acquisition of state-of-the-art facilities for teaching and learning

                       activities.


                                    The  college  has  been  consistent  with  its  aim  to  gain  global

                               relevance by acquiring up to date technology for the establishment of
                               the state-of-the-art facilities such  as the METTI MAN human patient

                               simulator model and Gaumard model, a simulator that can be utilized

                               in the Nursing simulation classes.


                                Since its conversion to College of Nursing in 2005, the college has been

                        consistent  with  its  aim  to  gain  global  relevance  by  acquiring  state-of-the-art


                        equipment  for  the  establishment  of  state-of-the-art  facilities.  This  aims  to

                        provide a venue for skills training to students to keep them globally competitive.

                        The first facility established was the Nursing Arts Laboratory in 2005 which is






                                                                                                           15]]></page><page Index="17"><![CDATA[the  first  to  be  established  component  of  the  Simulation  Area  for  students

                        Related Learning Experiences (RLE).


                               The nursing skills laboratory simulates major areas in hospital setting

                        and equipped with basic instruments,  equipment, and supplies to aid in the


                        development of the competencies in performing nursing procedures. There are

                        outcomes expected to be achieved at the end of every level.


                               At  the  end  of  the  first  year,  given  a  simulated  situation  in  selected

                        settings, the learners demonstrate basic nursing skills in rendering safe and


                        appropriate nursing care utilizing the nursing process.

























                              Figure 6. The BSN Level I students demonstrate basic nursing skills
                              of wearing sterile gloves in rendering safe and appropriate nursing care
                              inside the Nursing Arts Laboratory that is similar to the major areas in
                              hospital setting and equipped with basic instruments, equipment and
                              supplies to aid in the development of the competencies in performing
                              nursing procedures.
















                                                                                                           16]]></page><page Index="18"><![CDATA[Figure 7. The BSN Level 1 male student demonstrates the handwashing
                              technique under the supervision of his clinical instructor in the College of
                              Nursing.

                               At the end of second level, given a  normal  and  high-risk mother  and

                        newborn, child, family, communities and population groups in any health care


                        setting, the learners demonstrate safe, appropriate, and holistic care utilizing

                        the nursing process.


























                              Figure 8. The BSN Level II students are having their Maternal and
                              Child Health Nursing class in the Nursing Arts Laboratory using the
                              existing  equipment,  dummies,  and  models  with  their  clinical
                              instructors in the College of Nursing.












                                                                                                           17]]></page><page Index="19"><![CDATA[Figure 9. The BSN Level II students and clinical instructors are having
                              their demonstration and return demonstration of different procedures
                              in the Nursing Arts Laboratory using the different models of dummies
                              and its body parts.

























                              Figure 10. The BSN Level II students and clinical instructors during their
                              exposure to the community setting.

                               At the end of third level, given individuals, families, population groups,

                        and  communities  with  physiologic  and  psycho-social  health  problems,  and


                        maladaptive patterns of behavior in varied health care settings, the learners







                                                                                                           18]]></page><page Index="20"><![CDATA[demonstrate safe, appropriate, and holistic care utilizing the nursing process

                        and applying research and evidence-based practice.


























                             Figure  11.  The  BSN  Level  III  students  are  having  their  re-
                              demonstration of different nursing skills in labor and delivery for them
                              to be ready in their Related Learning Experience in varied health care
                              settings.

























                              Figure  12.  The  BSN  Level  III  students  are  having  their  re
                              demonstration  of  nursing  skills  in  performing  intramuscular  and
                              intradermal  administration  for  them  to  be  ready  in  their  Related
                              Learning Experience in varied health care settings.










                                                                                                           19]]></page><page Index="21"><![CDATA[Figure  13.  The  additional  instruments  and  materials  needed  by
                              BSN  students  in  their  training  before  their  actual  exposure  to
                              different areas in hospitals, and other health care settings.


                               At the end of fourth level, given groups of clients (individuals, families,

                        population groups, and communities) with health problems and special needs,


                        the  learners  demonstrate  safe,  appropriate,  and  holistic  care  utilizing  the

                        nursing  process  and  can  assume  first  level  entry  positions  in  any  field  of


                        nursing.
























                              Figure 14. The BSN Level IV students are having their Related Learning
                              Experiences in the special areas like OR and wards in the hospital.




                                                                                                           20]]></page><page Index="22"><![CDATA[Figure 15. METTI MAN model and Gaumard model housed inside the
                             Nursing Arts Laboratory for the simulation for the learning experiences
                             of the students.

                                The procurement of Mettiman in 2014, renovation and improvement in the


                         construction of Nursing Arts Laboratory (Fig. 14- 15) where nursing skills were

                         being  taught  and  enhanced,  are  some  of  the  globally  relevant  acquisitions


                         adopted by the college as a result of the benchmarking. One of the college best

                         practices is to send faculty members to different trainings and workshops  for


                         them to observe the nursing schools and agencies that will give the college new

                         ideas and updates for faculty/ students’ teaching and learning (Fig. 16- 18).












                                                                                                           21]]></page><page Index="23"><![CDATA[Figure  16.  The  Nursing  Arts  Laboratory  with  the  Metti  Man  Model
                              alongside side with medical apparatus being utilized for the simulation
                              activities of the students.

























                             Figure 17. The Nursing Arts Laboratory has the double-sided mirror for
                             the  faculty  who  will  program  the  Mettiman  Model  and  observed  the
                             students while they were doing the simulation activities.



                               In 2015, the college, with the support of the administration, was very

                        fortunate to receive a ₱8.2 million high tech mannequin model named Mr. Metti

                        Man, the talking, crying, blinking, and can be programmed to different emotional


                        states.  This  led  to  the  influx  of  more  equipment  for  the  College  of  Nursing,




                                                                                                           22]]></page><page Index="24"><![CDATA[benefiting students and faculty members. With the existing equipment then, the

                        faculty members and staff of the college has undergone training in the use of


                        different models, equipment, and apparatus.
























                              Figure 18 The figure shows the trainings attended by faculty members
                              of the College of Nursing. Short training course on how to program Metti
                              Man  model  conducted  at  the  Cavite  State  University,  College  of
                              Nursing, Nursing Arts Lab for faculty and staff conducted on June 2019.

























                              Figure 19. The trainings attended by faculty members of the College
                              of  Nursing  were  utilized  in  teaching  their  students  with  the  use  of
                              Metti Man model at the College of Nursing, Nursing Arts Lab.








                                                                                                           23]]></page><page Index="25"><![CDATA[Figure  20  The  College  of  Nursing  strives  to  give  its  students  the  best
                              nursing  education  by  providing  learning  with  the  use  of  up-to-date
                              technology.






























                           Figure 21. A human torso model being utilized for human anatomy classes.















                                                                                                           24]]></page><page Index="26"><![CDATA[Figure 22. The continuous acquisition of modern equipment for the teaching and
                         learning activity.

                        1.2.3. Continuous faculty and staff development


                                   The faculty and staff have development program that acknowledge the


                         advances in the nursing education and healthcare delivery. It allows professional

                         development  among  faculty  members  to  continuously  deliver  effective

                         instruction. It includes career development that allows the faculty and staff to


                         prepare for career advancement. Some of the opportunities include scholarship

                         grants  to  full  time  faculty  members,  attendance  to  continuing  education


                         programs,  conferences,  professional  and  scientific  meetings.  In  addition,

                         personal development that caters on the interpersonal and communication skills


                         and mental health was also being provided.



















                                                                                                           25]]></page><page Index="27"><![CDATA[1.2.3.1. Attendance of faculty and staff to various conferences, seminars,

                               workshops, and trainings




                                 Quality  instruction  is  ensured  by  the  continuous  faculty  and  staff

                         attendance  to  various  seminars,  trainings,  workshops,  and  other  activities


                         that provide updates, trends, and development in the field of nursing and its

                         specialties.



                                The list of seminars, trainings, workshops, and other activities attended

                       by  faculty  in  the  last  five  (5)  years.  The  table  for  the  attendance  of  faculty


                       members  of  the  College  of  Nursing  to  various  conferences,  seminars,

                       workshops, and trainings from 2016 to present is provided in Appendix A.






























                        Figure 23.  An international conference on Medical Pluralism held last March 11-
                         14, 2019.It was hosted by the Cavite State University and was jointly facilitated
                         by the College of Nursing. It was attended by participants from institutions local
                         and abroad.





                                                                                                           26]]></page><page Index="28"><![CDATA[Figure 24. The College of Nursing, Overall Clinical Coordinator, Jocelyn B.
                         Dimayuga, RN, MAN together with the participants during “Innovative Do it
                         yourself Moulage Workshop” last May 13, 2017 facilitated by Dr.  Mohammad
                         Naszrul  Suaidi in DLSU, College of Nursing. The electives of this activity is
                         to increase realism and fidelity in simulation, and to create moulage using
                         cost effective materials in the clinical setting.
























                        Figure 25. The Health and Wellness Webinar entitled “Strengthening Employees
                         Mental Health “held on November 19,2020 via CISCO WEBEX. It was sponsored
                         by the Office of the CvSU Human Resource Development Office and participated
                         by all faculty and staff.  Dr. Louiziela Masana , Ms. Carmel Villar and Dr. Rainier
                         Umali  are  the  invited  guest  speakers  catering  their  field  on  psychology,
                         spirituality and depression respectively.







                                                                                                           27]]></page><page Index="29"><![CDATA[1.2.3.2.      Continuing education through on-line learning



                                  The professional education supports the use of interactive learning


                          environment.  In  keeping  at  paced  with  the  latest  modalities  of  learning,

                          faculty members have taken on-line courses. In the realization of the shift of

                          technology,  online  courses  can  be  of  great  contribution  their  present


                          teaching –learning formats.







                                The  list  of  the  On-line  trainings  and  courses  taken  by  CON  faculty

                        members sponsored by CvSU is provided in Appendix B.



































                        Figure  26.  Prof.  Nenita  B.  Panaligan  and  Ms.  Lei  Anne  B.  Rupido  as  they
                        participate  in  the  online  training  course  on  Designing  Flexible  Learning  in
                        Nursing  conducted  by  the  University  of  the  Philippines-Manila  College  of
                        Nursing last January 19,2021- February 10,2021.





                                                                                                           28]]></page><page Index="30"><![CDATA[Figure  27  .  Copies  of  the  certificates  from  the  seminars,  conferences  and
                        trainings attended by the faculty.











                                                                                                           29]]></page><page Index="31"><![CDATA[1.2.3.3. Faculty development through graduate education


                                   The faculty members of the college  continuously improve in their


                          craft. They strive for further education to provide up to date knowledge to

                          their students. Majority of the regular faculty members are into their PhD


                          education.  The  faculty  members  are  enrolled  in  CHED  recognized

                          institutions  like  University  of  the  Philippines,  De  La  Salle  University,  Our


                          Lady of Fatima University and Trinity University of Asia.





                                For many years, the college has been following a Faculty Development


                        plan which aims to enhance instruction by building expertise in various fields of

                        nursing and allied fields. The list of faculty members with scholarships from


                        CHED,  and  currently  enrolled  in  post  graduate  programs  is  provided  in

                        Appendix C.

























                        Figure 28. The faculty members of the College of Nursing while attending their
                        Doctor of Philosophy in Nursing online class. Prof. Jane A. Rona, Prof Sunny S.
                        Ferrera, Prof Ederlyn P. Destura, Prof Mary Antoinette D. Viray, Prof Jocelyn B.
                        Dimayuga , and Prof Louis Carlos O. Roderos are enrolled in Our Lady of
                        Fatima University, Valenzuela, A CHED recognized Institution.



                                                                                                           30]]></page><page Index="32"><![CDATA[Figure 29. Prof. Shezel Jheane Matel with her classmates in Master of Arts in
                         Nursing at the University of the Philippines Manila. Prof Matel is also an
                         alumnus of Cavite State University College of Nursing Class of 2012.





                        1.2.4. Student Development Activities


                               The CvSU College of Nursing provides opportunities to help students


                          develop  a  responsible,  well-rounded,  self-reliant  individuals  and  leaders.

                          Campus activities and student organizations promote student engagement.


                          The university embrace students’ involvement through various partnerships

                          that cultivate growth.




















                        Figure  30.  The  BS  Nursing  students  during  the  health  education  and
                        Campaign Drive for the Blood Donation Project of CVSU College of Nursing in
                        collaboration with the Philippine Red Cross .









                                                                                                           31]]></page><page Index="33"><![CDATA[Figure  31.  Ms.  Balbina  Borneo  RN,RM,MAN  ,  former  MCNAP  National
                        President as the resource speaker for the Nursing and Midwifery Capping and
                        Pinning Ceremony held last  February 20,2019 at SM Rolle Hall , Cavite State
                        University ,Indang Cavite. Ms. Borneo has shared valuable insights and her
                        journey for the aspiring nurses and midwives.
























                        Figure 32 . The College of Nursing students were able to develop holistically
                        through the conduct of students' developmental activities such as “CON Night”
                        where they can showcase their talents and other abilities.



                                                                                                           32]]></page><page Index="34"><![CDATA[Figure 33. The College of Nursing students were able to display their talents in
                        sports  activities  during  the  University  Games.  Students  of  the  BS  Nursing
                        program get the chance to compete with other students in the university.







































                                                                                                           33]]></page><page Index="35"><![CDATA[1.2.4.1. Learning through research and extension


                                 Research and Extension has been a part and parcel of the success


                          of the university. As part of the instruction students conduct research where

                          they  systematically  collect  and  analyze  data  to  illuminate  and  explain  new


                          facts and relationships. Students developed specialized knowledge and skills

                          through research. They have great intellectual understanding in certain fields

                          of nursing in which they want to know more and are interested with. In the


                          process,  they  will  be  able  to  learn  skills  in  doing  data  gathering  and


                          experiment.  The  Appendix  D  shows  the  BS  Nursing  students’  completed

                          research prior to graduation.

































                        Figure 34. The thesis defense of BSN Level IV students was done via Zoom with
                         the group of CON faculty researchers and Research Coordinator as the panel
                         during the defense.







                                                                                                           34]]></page><page Index="36"><![CDATA[Figure 35 . The students of the CvSU BS Nursing are trained and supervised in
                         the conduct of their researches  that are relevant in the nursing profession.



























                        Figure 36.  The Research Center In-House Review entitled “Navigating the New
                         Normal:    Effective  Research  Methods  Amidst  the  Pandemic  held  online  last
                         November 3 & 4 2020. It was attended by students and faculty as part of research
                         activities during the pandemic.















                                                                                                           35]]></page><page Index="37"><![CDATA[Figure  37.  The  thesis  entitled  Lived  experience  of  the  Individual  Living  with
                         Human Immuno-Deficiency Virus Ages 18-30 in Dasmarinas City, Cavite (2019)
                         was published   in Journal of Infectious Diseases and Medical Microbiology.

















                                                                                                           36]]></page><page Index="38"><![CDATA[Figure 38 .  Mr. Alwie A. Torrente of CvSU  BSN Batch 2017 winning the Best
                         Gender and Development Research Paper last June 14,2018 at the CvSU  3rd
                         Gender and Development Research Conference .


                        1.2.4.2 Learning through extension


                                    Conduct of extension to local communities has always been a


                          practice  of  CON  as  well  as  other  stakeholders.  The  college  was  able  to

                          address the specific  needs of the community through  extension  programs,


                          projects, and activities in collaboration with other agencies and linkages that

                          can be of help in the resolution. With this endeavor of the college, the students

                          were able to know different concerns and needs in which they can help to the


                          best that they can. In the process they will become good professional, better


                          and  responsible  person.  When  the  College  of  Nursing  faculty  members

                          conduct  extension  activities  in  the  adapted  communities,  the  students  are

                          enjoined  to  participate  in  various  health  promotion  and  health  education


                          activities.





                                                                                                           37]]></page><page Index="39"><![CDATA[Figure 39. Approved Communication Letter from Director Extension Unit and
                           CvSU University President, The Term of References of Faculty Members for
                           Extension ARUGA Project September 12, 2018

























                           Figure 40. The meetings conducted with Barangay Kayquit III Officials in the
                           planning and implementation of the project.


                                The figure shows that the College of Nursing is continuously conducting
                        extension activities for many years. Initial meetings done on September 13,

                        2018 with Barangay Health Workers and Officials, Committee on Health and
                        Nutrition,  (L-R)  Prof.  Panaligan  Project  Leader,  Prof.  Ferrera  Extension

                        Coordinator and Ms. Mary Antoniette Viray – faculty extensionist / GAD with
                        Kagawad. Fernando Feranil and Kagawad. Nelson Suarez and Secretary Lilian

                        Tiglao, September 13, 2018.




                                                                                                           38]]></page><page Index="40"><![CDATA[The group has a regular visit in Kayquit explaining the project and the

                        conceptual framework of the ARUGA Child Care Program. Planning about the


                        project was deliberated by the attendees and all suggestions were taken into

                        consideration in the proposal based on the children’s needs and assessments.
























                              Figure  41.  Prof.  Panaligan  meeting  with  Mrs.  SJ  Tiglao,  the  Barangay
                              Health Worker assigned in Purok 4 Barangay Kayquit 3, asking some health
                              information about most common illnesses among the 0-5 years old children
                              in the barangay.


                                 Prof. Nenita B. Panaligan and Mrs. SJ Tiglao, the Barangay Health

                        Worker  assigned  in  Purok  4  Barangay  Kayquit  3,  worked  together  for  the


                        retrieval  of  health  data  on  existing  child  health  programs,  and  some  health

                        information most common illnesses among the 0 -5 years old children in the


                        barangay.  Subsequently,  home  visits  were  done  with  selected  volunteer

                        students BSN Level 2 for VS monitoring, weight, and immunization status and


                        survey on most common illnesses in the last 3 months.














                                                                                                           39]]></page><page Index="41"><![CDATA[Figure  42.  The  project  leader,  Prof.  Panaligan  lead  in  the  conduct  of
                        community visit (Home visits) with selected volunteer students BSN Level 2 for
                        VS monitoring, weight, and immunization status and survey on most common
                        illnesses in the last 3 months.






























                        Figure 43. Dr. Evelyn del Mundo during the orientation on the beneficiaries of
                        training on Basic Caregiving Skills at Kayquit, Indang Cavite last March 5, 2020.








                                                                                                           40]]></page><page Index="42"><![CDATA[Another extension activity that the College have done continuously for

                        many years is the Seminar on HIV Awareness and “Bloodletting” conducted


                        simultaneously, and which has been a substantial part of extension. Nursing,

                        Midwifery and Medical Technology students have been active partakers since


                        the  beginning  of  the  activity.  In  recognition  of  this,  the  college  was  hailed

                        Champion in Blood Olympics in 2011, received award as 2          nd  place in Blood


                        Olympics  in  2012,  given  Kabalikat  Award  in  2014,  recognized  as  Best

                        Performing University in 2015. These were awarded by Cavite Blood Council,


                        Provincial Government of Cavite, Philippine Red Cross. All these were the fruit

                        of the joined efforts of the students, faculty and staff. The college has been


                        continuously providing  unwavering support and  contribution to provide safe,

                        accessible and adequate blood supply for the province through the promotion

                        of  voluntary  blood  donation  in  the  University.  HIV  Awareness  seminar  was


                        conducted simultaneously with  bloodletting activity the Resource Speaker is

                        one of the CON faculty member. This was attended by students, faculty, staff,


                        from our adoptive community and people from different barangays of Indang

                        Cavite.





















                                                                                                           41]]></page><page Index="43"><![CDATA[Figure 44. The staff, BHW and Barangay officials of Indang RHU and Barangay
                         Kayquit 3, Indang Cavite together with the CON faculty members and staff during the
                         Seminar on HIV Awareness.




















                        Figure 45. Registration and vital signs taking prior to screening of possible
                        blood  donors  then  Blood  Screening  followed  by  collection  of  blood  in  a
                        designated area for extraction. Students from different colleges, from the
                        College  of  Nursing,  community  people  from  Indang  and  from  CON’s
                        adoptive community are voluntarily donating blood.






                                                                                                           42]]></page><page Index="44"><![CDATA[Figure 46. An extension activity for the Persons with Disability of Indang Cavite.
                         The College of Nursing faculty members Ms. Mary Antoniette D. Viray, Dr. Annie
                         M. Ramos , Ms. Lei Anne B. Rupido, Ria Marisse D. Matel and Ms. Charmaine
                         V.  Rosales    participated  with  the  “Health  Monitoring  of  Members  of  Indang
                         Association of Persons with Disability” last July 26, 2018 held at the International
                         House , CvSU Indang Cavite.

                        1.2.5. Benchmarking and adoption of globally relevant practices for
                        learning

                                  The Collegeof  Nursing Faculty Members take every   chance           to
                       undertake benchmarking in every opportunity they must go outside of the country

                       be it for their paper presentation, trainings, or seminars. For the same global vision
                       of the university and the college, to be one of the nation’s leading nursing institution

                       in  providing  excellent  instruction  and  opportunities  for  research,  practice,  and

                       service.



















                                                                                                           43]]></page><page Index="45"><![CDATA[Figure 47. Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo presented their research paper
                              entittled “Adventure Relaxation And Theatrical Therapy Among Older
                              Persons With Depression In Selected Barangays Of Dasmariñas City,
                              Cavite”  authored  by  Andrea  Mariz  Baliguat,  Kimberly  Cyrelle  Anne
                              Enage Allysa Toni Marie Salud and Dr. Evelyn Del Mundo (adviser) in
                              SEAAIR2016 , Suan Dusit Rajabhat University, Bangkok, Thailand.
















                              Figure 48. Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo was able to meet the President,
                              director and Guest speaker of SEAAIR2016 in Suan Dusit Rajabhat
                              University, Bangkok, Thailand.
























                                                                                                           44]]></page><page Index="46"><![CDATA[Figure 49. The College of Nursing makes sure that they get something out of
                         the meetings with people be it sharing of experiences, knowledge, or possible
                         partnership.























                        Figure  50.  Professor  Nenita  B.  Panaligan  during  her  oral  presentation
                        entitled “Lived Experiences of Mangyan Mothers on Infant Care at Home:
                        Phenomenological  Study”  .  The  research  presentation  was  held  at  the
                        Association  of  Pacific  Rim  Universities  APRU  Global  Health  Workshop,
                        Osaka, Japan dated October 31- November 2, 2015.



                                                                                                           45]]></page><page Index="47"><![CDATA[Figure  51.  It  shows  the  relevance  of  international  travels  of  Associate
                         Professor  Nenita  B.  Panaligan,  a  faculty  member  of  the  college,  with  some
                         places she visited and the people she met. The further enhancement of skills
                         in  attending  international  research  presentation  and  seminars  will  give  new
                         ideas for innovations and improvement.


























                        Figure 52. The new faculty members from the College of Nursing are also
                        given  the  opportunity  to  attend  workshops,  seminars  and  conferences  in
                        different parts of the country and abroad to determine the best practices of
                        different universities that can be adopted for the betterment of CON.

                               The College of Nursing takes every opportunity they can get by sending


                        faculty members, Prof. Nenita B. Panaligan, Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo, Ms.




                                                                                                           46]]></page><page Index="48"><![CDATA[Caridad Lintao and Mr. Jay Louie S. Madlangbayan and other faculty members

                        in different parts of the country and abroad to determine the best practices of


                        different universities that can be adopted for the betterment of CON.


                               The procurement of Mettiman in 2014, renovation and improvement in


                        the construction of Nursing Arts  Laboratory where nursing skills were being

                        taught and enhanced, are some of the globally relevant acquisitions adopted


                        by the college because of the benchmarking. One of the college best practices

                        is to send faculty members to different trainings and workshops  for them to

                        observe the nursing schools and agencies that will give the college new ideas


                        and updates for faculty/ students’ teaching and learning.



























                         Figure 53. The Nursing Arts Laboratory with the Metti Man Model alongside
                         side with medical apparatus being utilized for the simulation activities of the
                         students.












                                                                                                           47]]></page><page Index="49"><![CDATA[Figure 54. The Nursing Arts Laboratory has the double sided mirror for the
                          faculty who will program the Mettiman Model and observed the students
                          while they were doing the simulation activities.

























                        Figure 55. The participants and the facilitator Prof . Md Khairulamin A.S.
                        and  Chaoyan  Dong  during  workshop  of  “Using  the  Flipped  Classroom
                        Model in Healthcare Simulation”.




                                      The  best  practice  the  college  was  able  to  observe  from  this


                             workshop was the introduction of flipped classroom model and the way

                             how  this  can  be  integrated  into  health  care  simulation.  The  flipped


                             classroom  model  involves  the  teacher  delivering  the  'taught'  element




                                                                                                           48]]></page><page Index="50"><![CDATA[outside  of  the  classroom.  Students  complete  this  element  of  their

                             learning prior to attending the lesson. The CON has been employing a


                             simple 'flipped classroom' model for years, setting reading or research

                             homework prior to the delivery of a topic. The positive outcome of this


                             innovative  learner  centered  approach  to  flip  simulation  training  to

                             enhance  education  allows  the  instructors  to  spend  more  time  with


                             students  in  lessons  consolidating  their  learning  and  allowing  them  to

                             progress  to  more  challenging  tasks  quicker.  This  resulted  to  self-


                             regulated  learning  or  the  self-directed  learning  and  social

                             connectedness  which  became  successful  in  making  significant


                             improvements among students exposed to this type of strategy.




































                        Figure  56.  The  College  of  Nursing  benchmarking  activity  was  done
                        through  the  yearly  Lakbay  Aral  to  different  Universities  and  Schools  of
                        Nursing in Baguio and other places.



                                                                                                           49]]></page><page Index="51"><![CDATA[Figure 57. Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo, the dean of the CON and Ms. Jocelyn
                         B. Dimayuga, the College Overall Clinical Coordinator and a faculty members
                         attended the OBE syllabus making for BSN Curriculum hosted by ADPCN last
                         April 5-7, 2019 at Matamihik St. University of the Philippines Quezon City.









                                                                                                           50]]></page><page Index="52"><![CDATA[Figure 58.  The Paper Oral Research Presentation entitled: “ It Takes
                              Two  to  Learn:  Self-Regulated  Learning  and  Clinical  Learning
                              Environment  using  a  mixed  design”  at  the  Clinical  Learning
                              Environment and Supervision (CLES) Symposium held in Chieti, Italy
                              on September 24-25, 2018. Assoc. Prof. Nenita B. Panaligan is a co-
                              author of this research paper in collaboration with UP Open University,
                              Manila, Philippines with other co-authors namely: Asst. Prof. Rita C.
                              Ramos, Jolly Balila, PhD, Mary Joanne Therese V. Kourdache, Ma.
                              Elma L. Mirandilla and Lenila A. de Vera, RN, MAN

                                   The  participation  to  trainings  and  seminar/  workshops  of  faculty

                             members  where  they  can  meet  the  different  nursing  leaders  of  many
                             schools and universities are a form of benchmarking the practices of their

                             institutions.  The  new  information  gathered,  sharing  of  resources  and
                             innovations were all gearing to improvement of the CON.. The figures show

                             benchmarking through the college yearly Lakbay Aral activity  to different

                             Universities and Schools of Nursing in Baguio, Laguna, Quezon and other
                             places.





                                                                                                           51]]></page><page Index="53"><![CDATA[Figure  59.    Faculty  members  continuously  pursue  professional  education
                       through trainings to improve their field of specialization. Prof. Jane A. Rona,
                       Ms.  Lei  Anne  B.  Rupido  and  Ms.  Phaebi  B.  Romen  who  are  also  registered
                       nurses  and  midwives  are  designated  to  handle  Maternal  and  Child  Nursing
                       course subjects of the program.




























                        Figure  60. The  College  of  Nursing  Clinical  Instructor,  Sir  Jay  Louie  S.
                         Madlangbayan, a Cardio-vascular Surgery Nurse who works in the De La
                         Salle  University  Medical  Center  have  shared  his  expertise  in  coronary
                         care and chemotherapy with the students at the College of Nursing. He
                         became an expert in his field with the aid of all the advance equipment,
                         apparatus, and models of mannequins that the college used as reference
                         for acquisition.




                                                                                                           52]]></page><page Index="54"><![CDATA[1.2.6. Subjecting the BS Nursing Program to evaluation and accreditation


                                 Undeniably,  the  humble  beginnings  led  the  program  to  a  prestige


                          standing  as  being  one  of  the  biggest  in  the  school  community.  The  BS

                          Nursing Program was one of the first in the history of the university to receive

                          the Certificate of Program Compliance. The College of Nursing continued to


                          advance  its  quality  of  education  for  the  Bachelor  of  Science  in  Nursing

                          program by providing all the facilities for the purpose of competent research


                          and guidelines for the students as well as the faculty members, employing

                          highly  qualified  faculty  members  with  high-attainment  education,  and


                          forming  good  and  strong  associations  with  various  government,  private

                          hospitals, and health centers.





                        1.2.6.1 AACUP Accrediting Agency of Chartered Colleges and Universities
                         in the Philippines

                                 Having  its  first  BS  Nursing  graduates  in  the  year  2006,  the  college


                        prepared  for  its  first  accreditation  of  BS  Nursing  program  for  AACCUP

                        Preliminary  survey  last  2007.  Self-survey  of  the  program  was  conducted  in


                        November 2007. The first formal visit was conducted last 2010 and the program

                        of BS in Nursing attained the higher-level quality and was awarded a Level I re-


                        accredited status. Dated on 2013, the said accredited program was then set for

                        a  second  survey  visit  and  met  the  standards  and  was  awarded  LEVEL  II


                        reaccredited  status.  After  passing  a  higher-level  standard  of  quality,  the




                                                                                                           53]]></page><page Index="55"><![CDATA[program  of  BS  in  Nursing  was  entitled  for  an  application  for  LEVEL  III

                        accreditation .


































                              Figure  61.  The  very  satisfactory  result  (4.23)  of  AACCUP  Technical
                              Review and Board Action confirmed that the college passed the Phase 1
                              in the 3 Survey Visit.
                                      rd

                        1.2.6. 2 ISO International Organization for Standardization


                              The  College  of  Nursing  is  being  subjected  to  audit  under  the  ISO

                         9001:2015. International Organization for Standardization has set standards for

                         organizations. This is one way to improve quality and customer satisfaction. The


                         management of learning of the undergraduate program of BS Nursing is being

                         evaluated and given remarks for improvement.















                                                                                                           54]]></page><page Index="56"><![CDATA[Figure  62.  The  Audit  findings  report  on  the  management  of  learning
                              processes of the College of Nursing.








                                                                                                           55]]></page><page Index="57"><![CDATA[1.2.6. 3   CHED Commission on Higher Education COPC







































































                              Figure  63.  The  awarded  Certificate  of  Program  Compliance  from  the
                              Commission on Higher Education



                                                                                                           56]]></page><page Index="58"><![CDATA[1.2.7. Establishment, development and strengthening of linkages with
                               various institutions for overall improvement of instruction.




                                 The  College  of  Nursing  strive  to  progressively  link  with  other


                          institutions to provide human and physical resources for the development in

                          curriculum  and  instruction.  The  Bachelor  of  Science  in  Nursing  program


                          strives for students to reach competitive performance both with the aspect

                          of theoretical and clinical by strengthening the affiliations with neighboring

                          Hospitals.  The  establishment,  development  and  strengthening  of  CON’s


                          linkages resulted to overall improvement of instruction in the BSN program.



                                In terms of academic linkages, the Cavite State University, College of

                        Nursing was able to establish linkages in various hospital for students’ related


                        learning  experiences.  The  general  guidelines  for  the  affiliation  of  nursing

                        students are provided in the Joint Administrative Order of DOH No. 2013-0034


                        and CHED CMO No. 35 s. 2013 entitled

                        “Policies and Guidelines on the affiliation of Higher Education Institutions with


                        Hospitals  and  Other  Health  facilities  for  the  training  of  students  in  Health

                        Profession Educations. In CHED CMO No. 14 s. 2009 and CMO No. 15 s. 2017,


                        the students shall be given opportunities to be exposed to the various levels of

                        health care with various client groups (individual, family, population groups and


                        community) in various settings (hospital, community).



                              The  CvSU  College  of  Nursing  has  a  list  of  partner  agencies  and

                        institutions  with  Memorandum  of  Agreement  between  CvSU  and  different




                                                                                                           57]]></page><page Index="59"><![CDATA[hospitals  such  as  General  Emilio  Aguinaldo  Memorial  Hospital,  Korea-

                        Friendship  Hospital,  and  City  of  General  Trias  Doctors  Medical  Center,  MV


                        Santiago  Hospital,  Barangays  in  Ternate,  Indang  and  Rural  Health  Units  in

                        adjacent towns where the university is situated. On top of these institutions,


                        nursing  students  are  also  being  trained  at  Cavite  Center  for  Mental  Health,

                        Philippine Orthopedic Center and San Lazaro Hospital in Manila. The list of


                        partner agencies and nature of linkages is provided in Appendix F.


                       List of partner agencies and nature of linkages

                       A. Local/ Province

                       General Emilio Aguinaldo Memorial Hospital


























                              Figure 64. The General Emilio Aguinaldo Memorial  Hospital (GEAMH)
                              has a 350 bed capacity government hospital in Cavite. It is the Mother
                              hospital  of  the  Cavite  State  University,  College  of  Nursing  established
                              linkages through MOA since 2005 up to present.












                                                                                                           58]]></page><page Index="60"><![CDATA[Figure 65. The copy of the MOA between CvSU CON and GEAMH.
                              Korea-Philippines Friendship Hospital






















                              Figure 66. The Korea- Philippines Friendship Hospital located in Trece
                              Martirez City, Cavite  is a multi-specialty hospital in Cavite .





                                                                                                           59]]></page><page Index="61"><![CDATA[Figure  67.  The  strong  linkage  developed  with  Korean  Philippines
                              Friendship  Hospital  through  the  exposure  of  nursing  students  in
                              different areas while rendering care to patients. This collaboration and
                              partnership gave the CON students to apply what they have learned
                              from theory to practice in the real hospital setting.












                                                                                                           60]]></page><page Index="62"><![CDATA[Manuel V. Santiago Medical Center



































































                              Figure 68. During the hospital orientation of Level II Nursing students in
                              MV Santiago Medical Center and a copy of the Memorandum of
                              Agreement between CvSU -College of Nursing and M.V. Santiago Medical
                              Center.



                                                                                                           61]]></page><page Index="63"><![CDATA[City of General Trias Doctors Medical Center











































                        Figure 69. The level II BS Nursing students together with Mr. Ivan Wycoco in
                         CGTDMC and a Copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU
                         College of Nursing and City of Gen Tri Doctors Medical Center at Gen. Trias
                         City, Cavite




















                                                                                                           62]]></page><page Index="64"><![CDATA[Indang Rural Health Unit












































                        Figure 70. The Level II BS Nursing students at Indang Rural Health Unit and a
                         copy of the Memorandum of Agreement between CvSU College of Nursing and
                         Municipality of Indang RHU.




















                                                                                                           63]]></page><page Index="65"><![CDATA[Brgy. Kayquit, Indang, Cavite
























                              Figure 71. The Level III BS Nursing students at Barangay Kaquit III during
                           their community health nursing exposure.

















                                                             Figure  72.  A  copy  of  the  Memorandum  of
                                                             Agreement between the Indang LGU Barangay
                                                             Kayquit  II  and  the  CvSU  College  of  Nursing
                                                             signed  by  Dr.  Hernando  D.  Robles  and
                                                             Municipal  Mayor  Hon.  Perfecto  V.  Fidel.  The
                                                             Barangy Kayquit II is one of the affiliations where
                                                             students  are  trained  during  their  Community
                                                             Health Nursing exposure. It is also a venue for
                                                             extension  activities  catering  to  the  different
                                                             population of the barangay.





                                                                                                           64]]></page><page Index="66"><![CDATA[Tanza Rural Health Unit




























                          Figure 73. The Level III BS Nursing students at Tanza Rural Health Unit during
                          their community health nursing exposure.





























                        Figure 74. Copy of MOU of CvSU –College of Nursing and Tanza Rural Health
                        Unit










                                                                                                           65]]></page><page Index="67"><![CDATA[NAIC Rural Health Unit

























                        Figure 75. A copy of MOU of CvSU –College of Nursing and Naic Rural Health

                         Unit






































                        Figure 76. Level I BS Nursing students with Prof. Maribel L. Chua at Naic Rural

                         Health Unit.





                                                                                                           66]]></page><page Index="68"><![CDATA[Ternate Rural Health Unit


































                       Figure 77. The Level III BS Nursing students at Ternate Rural Health Unit during
                       their community health nursing exposure.

                                Strengthening  of  linkages  not  only  with  government  hospitals  and


                        institutions but also to private hospitals like the Manuel V. Santiago Medical

                        Center,  an  83-bed  capacity  secondary  hospital  that  delivers  continuously


                        improving quality health care services, its patients have known over the years.

                        However,  the  City  of  General  Trias  Doctors  Medical  Center  formerly  Gentri

                        Doctors  Medical  Center.  is  a  100-bed  capacity  hospital  that  serves  as  an


                        affiliating  hospital  of  CvSU  CON.  Nursing  students  get  to  rotate  to  different

                        special  and  non-special  areas  such  as  Medical  Ward,  Intensive  Care  Unit,


                        Operation  Room,  and  Emergency  Department  with  the  supervision  of  their

                        Clinical Instructors as stipulate in the MOA.








                                                                                                           67]]></page><page Index="69"><![CDATA[Clinical Instructors who are well-trained on their area of specialization

                        supervised the nursing students. They were able to learn and experience the


                        real-life  situations  in  the  clinical  setting.  The  students  get  the  chance  to

                        enhance  their  skills  with  the  use  of  techno-intelligent  systems  in  terms  of


                        machine and equipment in the hospital.


                                 The  linkage  between  CvSU  and  the  different  regional  and  national

                        institutions is becoming stronger as evidenced by both institutions are reaching


                        out to work together for the betterment of outcome-based nursing program for

                        the  students  and  faculty  members.  As  shown  in  Figure  67,  Dr.  Camilo  A.


                        Polinga, the Vice President of Academic Affairs and the dean of the College of

                        Nursing are present during the signing ceremony of the Contract of Agreement


                        relating to Nursing student’s affiliation for the A.Y. 2019-2020, This ceremony

                        was also attended by the different officials of San Lazaro Hospital and other


                        affiliated Universities and Schools of Nursing in the Philippines. The college felt

                        the sense of belonging that resulted to more conducive learning environment


                        of CvSU nursing students (Fig.68).





















                              Figure 78. The contract of agreement signed by both parties resulted to
                              more conducive learning environment of CvSU nursing students.


                                                                                                           68]]></page><page Index="70"><![CDATA[Figure 79. Dr. Camilo A. Polinga and Dean Evelyn M. Del Mundo were
                         present during the signing ceremony of the Contract of Agreement relating
                         to Nursing students’ affiliation for the A.Y. 2019-2020, together with
                         Dr.  Edmundo  B.  Lopez,  Medical  Center  Chief  II  and  Dr.  Virginia  O.
                         Dimapilis, the Hospital Chief Training Officer assisted by Nursing Service
                         Training  Office  headed  by  Ms.  Rose  Mendoza,  Training  Officer  for  the
                         student’s affiliation.

                       Regional

                       Cavite Center for Mental Health
































                              Figure  80.  Copy  of  the  Memorandum  of  Agreement  between  CvSU
                              College of Nursing and Cavite Center for Mental Health.


                                                                                                           69]]></page><page Index="71"><![CDATA[Batangas Medical Center formerly known as Batangas Regional Hospital




































































                             Figure 81. Copy of the MOU between CVSU - College of Nursing and

                              Batangas Medical Center.




                                                                                                           70]]></page><page Index="72"><![CDATA[National

                       San Lazaro Hospital






























































                                              th
                              Figure 82.    5  Ceremonial signing of contract of affiliation at
                              San Lazaro Hospital attended by Dr. Camilo A. Polinga, CvSU -
                              Vice President for Academic affairs and Dean of the College of
                              Nursing,  Dr.  Evelyn  M.  Del  Mundo  with  Prof.  Jocelyn  B.
                              Dimayuga – CON Overall Clinical Coordinator




                                                                                                           71]]></page><page Index="73"><![CDATA[The ceremonial signing of the Contract of Affiliation was attended by the

                         Vice President for Academic Affairs, Dr. Camilo A. Polinga and Dean Evelyn M.


                         Del Mundo together with Dr. Edmundo B. Lopez, Medical Center Chief II and Dr.

                         Virginia  O.  Dimapilis  the  Hospital  Chief  Training  Officer  assisted  by  Nursing


                         Service Training Office headed by Ms. Rose Mendoza, Training Officer for the

                         student’s affiliation for student’s affiliation for the A.Y. 2019-2020 and renewed


                         annually.

















































                              Figure 83. Preceptorship Training at San Lazaro Hospital last February
                              26,27,28 & March 1, 2019




                                                                                                           72]]></page><page Index="74"><![CDATA[Prof.. Sunny Rose Ferrera and Ms. Phaebi Romen, faculty members from

                         the College of Nursing completed preceptorship training at San Lazaro Hospital,


                         Manila last February 26,2019 until March 1, 2019 as part of the hospital training

                         program for the faculty members who will handle nursing students in the clinical


                         exposure to their institution.

































                              Figure 84. Mr. Sunny Rose Ferrera and Ms. Phaebi Romen with other
                              Clinical Instructors from other affiliating schools during the preceptorship
                              training.

























                                                                                                           73]]></page><page Index="75"><![CDATA[Figure 85. The CvSU BSN Level 4 Students was able to join the
                              celebration of the National Nurse’s Week last May 6 – 10, 2019 at San
                              Lazaro Hospital Manila.























                                                                                                           74]]></page><page Index="76"><![CDATA[Philippine Orthopedic Center

































































                              Figure 86. CvSU students with Prof. Ivan Wycoco at the Philippine
                              Orthopedic Center.











                                                                                                           75]]></page><page Index="77"><![CDATA[Figure 87. CvSU students with Prof. Ivan Wycoco at the Philippine
                              Orthopedic Center.

                                 For the overall improvement of instruction, the orientation program is

                          an important part of the nursing students RLE to hospitals and other affiliated

                          institutions. To prepare the students for a successful clinical placement and


                          to  maximize  learning  experience  the  hospitals  have  developed  a  nursing

                          student  orientation  program.  This  program  is  usually  done  by  the  Training


                          Officer, but in some hospitals by the Infection Control Nurse who will introduce

                          to students the important principles of clinical care and specific policies and


                          procedures followed in the institution. This program is required prior to the

                          start of nursing student’s clinical duties. It is one of the best practices of the


                          College of Nursing to conduct a general orientation in the classroom followed

                          by an orientation on the unit, department, and special areas in the hospitals


                          where  they  will  be  exposed  in  a  semester.  The  students  will  be  grouped

                          according to their sections based on the schedule of RLE duties .






                                                                                                           76]]></page><page Index="78"><![CDATA[Figure 88 The College of Nursing students during the orientation as
                              they  listen  with  Ms.  Michelle  Barit,  Chief  Nurse  of  MVSMC  on
                              February 28, 2020 and Ms. Ruthie Armijo the training officer of the
                              General Emilio Aguinaldo Hospital in Trece Martirez City Cavite on
                              February 17, 2020.



























                                                                                                           77]]></page><page Index="79"><![CDATA[Clinical  nursing  application  is  a  major  component  of  nursing

                          education. Students’ exposure to clinical learning environment is one of the

                          most  important  factors  affecting  the  teaching-learning  process  in  clinical


                          settings. Identifying challenges of nursing students in the clinical learning

                          environment could improve training and enhance the quality of its planning


                          and promotion of the students.

                                   Nursing students are given opportunities to learn from all fields of


                          nursing  and  its  specialties.  Conducive  clinical  areas  are  explored  and

                          learning  are  optimized  guided  by  the  skilled  clinical  instructors  who  are


                          expert in their fields of assignments.




                                  It is also vital that the instructors prepare students with a specific focus


                        on  their  communication  and  psychological  needs.  Nursing  student’s

                        participation and the degree of involvement in essential nursing activities during


                        their clinical practice in hospital settings is very important factor in blending with

                        the culture of the organization. Empowerment of nursing students to develop


                        clinical competencies and socialization in the nursing profession. Recognition

                        and awards received by nursing students in a clinical environment can have a

                        positive effect in their overall improvement.

















                                                                                                           78]]></page><page Index="80"><![CDATA[Figure 89. Nursing students received recognition during their participation in
                             the Nurses Week Celebration. Students was acknowledged for their talent
                             and active participation in the Quiz Bee activity.



                        1.2.8. Conduct of open topic seminars/ talks



                                It has been a practice of the college to invite experts and specialist in

                        their field to render open topic seminars. The topics covered are directly related


                        to the course subjects under the BS Nursing Program. There are also some

                        seminars  that  are  intended  to  orient  them  on  other  disciplines  and  other


                        relevant information that are essential in their holistic development in the ever-

                        changing  society.  The  list  of  some  of  the  most  recent  open  topic  seminars


                        conducted by CON is provided in Appendix G.


                                                                                                           79]]></page><page Index="81"><![CDATA[Figure 90. Ivan Derek V. Wycoco, RN, MAN was an Infection Prevention
                              and  Control  Nurse  and  a  Disease  Surveillance  Coordinator  of  City  of
                              General Trias Doctors Medical Center for two years and has been in the
                              clinical  practice  for  four  years  before  he  transferred  to  academe.  The
                              seminar was attended by several students from BSN Level II, III, and Level
                              IV.  CoN  Research  Coordinator,  Rolando  P.  Antonio,  RN,  Overall
                              Coordinator, Jocelyn B. Dimayuga, Professor Nenita Panaligan,RN, MAN,
                              Louis Carlos O. Roderos and Dr. Evelyn Del Mundo, dean of CON and
                              other faculty members and staff attended the seminar.


























                             Figure  91.  Prof.  Cecilia  Lorenzana,  Gender  and  Development
                             Coordinator  of  Cavite  State  University  Rosario  Campus,  the  guest
                             speaker  during  the  seminar  for  nursing  student  on  Gender  and
                             Development Orientation.



                                                                                                           80]]></page><page Index="82"><![CDATA[Figure 92. Louis Carlos O. Roderos, RN, MAN, the guest speaker on the
                             seminar about HIV AIDS Awareness to BSN Students.






































                                                                                                           81]]></page><page Index="83"><![CDATA[1.3.  SYSTEMATIC AND EFFECTIVE PROCEDURES



                             1.3.1. Periodic Review of Curriculum


                                 The  Bachelor  of  Science  in  Nursing  program  has  undergone  three

                          revisions since it was first offered under the College of Arts and Sciences.

                               By  virtue  of  BOR  Resolution  No.  57,  series  of  2001  approved  on
                        December 6, 2001, the BSN curriculum CMO 30  at CvSU was offered. The

                        College  of  Nursing  was  separated  from  the  College  of  Arts  of  Sciences  on

                        October 18, 2005 by virtue of BOR Resolution No 48, s 2005. In year 2007, the
                        incorporation  of  Associate  in  Science  Health  Education  (ASHE),  a  general

                        nursing curriculum was materialized.
                                  The second revision was done in 2009. The purpose to rationalize the

                          nursing education in the country to provide relevant and quality health services
                          locally and internationally started the implementation of BSN curriculum CMO

                          14  Series of 2009  pursuant to Commission en Banc Resolution No. 170 dated

                          April 19, 2009.
                               The  third  Revision  was  in  pursuant  to  the  outcome-based  quality

                        education. The  CHED Memorandum Order No. 15 Series of 2017 by virtue of
                        Commission  en  Banc  Resolution  No.  231-2017  dated  March  28,  2017  was

                        implemented.




                                 It is stated in the University Manual of Operation dated 2001 that if the


                        new program is designed to replace an existing curriculum, the implementation

                        should start from the incoming freshmen only and the old curriculum should


                        end with the graduation of the current students taking it. In addition to the CHED

                        requirements, the number of courses in revised or proposed program should


                        conform  to  the  course  numbering  system  being  adopted  by  the  University.

                        However,  unless  the  revision  or  introduction  of  new  required  course  is  a


                                                                                                           82]]></page><page Index="84"><![CDATA[mandatory  requirement  by  CHED,  no  revision  on  any  curriculum  of  the

                        University shall be made within five (5) years of its implementation.



                               Bachelor of Science in Nursing (BSN) CMO 15 s 2017 of the Cavite State

                        University,  College  of  Nursing  was  presented  by  Mr.  Joinito  A.  Ofracio,  the


                        college registrar and Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo, dean of the College of Nursing

                        during  the  Administrative  Council  Meeting  on  July  10,  2018  at  Lasap  Hall,

                        CvSU-Main Campus. Present during the presentation includes: the University


                        President, Dr. Hernando D. Robles, Vice President for Academic Affairs, Dr.

                        Camilo A. Polinga, the members of the University Academic Council, Directors,


                        Deans of the different colleges and faculty members.




























                        Figure  93.  The  BSN  curriculum  of  the  CvSU,  CON  was  presented  by  Mr.
                        Joinito A. Ofracio, the college registrar and Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo, dean of
                        the College of Nursing during the Administrative Council Meeting on July 10,
                        2018 at Lasap Hall, CvSU.













                                                                                                           83]]></page><page Index="85"><![CDATA[Figure 94. The College Academic Council review the academic policies for the
                          implementation of the of the present curriculum.




























                        Figure 95. The review of policies of  the College of Nursing was conducted
                        periodically and attended by faculty members and staff of the college with the
                        presence of different stakeholders.




                        1.3.2. Continuous Updating of Syllabus



                                Review of syllabi is done regularly by the faculty members handling the

                        courses. In the last two years of CMO 14 series 2008, the faculty members


                        have been modifying the course content to be more Competency-Based. In the



                                                                                                           84]]></page><page Index="86"><![CDATA[preparation for the implementation of CHED CMO No. 15, s. 2017 which is the

                        new PSG for the BSN program, the faculty members have been modifying the


                        course syllabi to make them more Outcomes-Based education. This curriculum

                        also  provides  ample  space  for  the  college  BS  Nursing  program  to  innovate


                        some strategies in the curriculum in line with the assessment of how best to

                        achieve learning outcomes according to the university mission statement. It has


                        been an ongoing exercise to review and identify the needs and the skills that

                        must be learned by the students. The current knowledge and practices learned


                        by the faculty members in the trainings, seminars, workshops, and conventions

                        they attended, as well as those that they gained personally. The syllabi were


                        updated and applied in teaching.




































                            Figure 96. Continuous updating of course syllabi by the faculty members
                            handling the subjects and the College Academic Council.




                                                                                                           85]]></page><page Index="87"><![CDATA[Figure  97.  The  College  of  Nursing  is  assigned  to  revise  the  course
                             syllabi of different subjects in CMO 15 S 2017 of BSN program offered
                             in the first semester 20202021.


                                    In preparation for the new normal in HEIs which will be implemented this

                         coming First Semester SY 2020-2021. Cavite State University through the effort


                         of the Office of the Vice President for Academic Affairs required all Program

                         Coordinators of the main campus to attend the 2-day seminar workshop on the


                         revision of course syllabus in line with the adoption of Flexible Learning System

                         which was facilitated by the College of Education last August 2020.



                                 The Office of the Vice President for Academic Affairs Memorandum

                        No. 19-01 s 2020 stated that in line with preparation for the opening of classes


                        for First Semester, AY 2020– 2021, the College of Nursing is assigned to revise

                        the  course  syllabi  was  enumerated.  The  template  includes  the  components


                        required in course syllabus which is intended to serve as the faculty guide as

                        they  prepare  course  syllabus  in  accordance  with  the  CvSU  policies  to  be



                                                                                                           86]]></page><page Index="88"><![CDATA[provided  for  all  CON  students.  All  faculty  members  must  provide  a  copy  of

                        syllabus  on the first day of class.

































                              Figure 98. The revised course syllabus and leaning guide of NURS 90
                              A (Nursing Leadership and Management) subject in CMO 15 S 2017 of
                              BSN program offered in the first semester 2020-2021.




                        1.3.3. Use of Relevant Teaching Strategies and Development of
                        Instructional Materials




                                The BS Nursing education has been Outcomes-Based, especially for

                        most  of  the  courses  that  have  a  Related  Learning  Experience  (RLE)  and


                        laboratory  part,  faculty  members  are  encouraged  to  adopt  more  teaching

                        strategies  other  than  what  has  been  traditionally  done.  They  are  also

                        encouraged to come up with innovative or “out-of-the-box” strategies that they


                        think would significantly help in the learning process.






                                                                                                           87]]></page><page Index="89"><![CDATA[Figure 99.   A moving exam for nursing students. A strategy that enable
                        nursing students to master hospital instruments, equipment and supplies .






























                               Figure  100.    The  nutrition  class  where  students  were  given  the
                              opportunity to apply the concepts they have learned in the class. These
                              learning opportunities for students to be relevant , intentional and creative
                                    st
                              as 21  century learners.







                                                                                                           88]]></page><page Index="90"><![CDATA[Figure 101. The BS Nursing students are provided community exposure for the
                              community and organization and development . This














































                                Figure 102. The BSN Level 2 students collaborating with each other for
                        their Health Education class presentation. Collective ideas are generated and
                        applied to make meaningful learning activities.






                                                                                                           89]]></page><page Index="91"><![CDATA[Figure  103.  Collaborative  learning  and  activities  are  encouraged  to
                        promote innovative and creative activities among the nursing students. A photo
                        of their output presentation for the informatics subject.

































                       Figure  104  .  Demonstration  and  learning  demonstration  is  one  the  most
                       important teaching strategy where an authentic measurement f learning can be
                       identified.












                                                                                                           90]]></page><page Index="92"><![CDATA[Figure 105.   The students of BS Nursing program are exposed to real
                               world  nursing  updates  by  collaborating  to  government  and  private
                               healthcare  organizations.  The  Asian  Hospital  and  Medical  Center
                               facilitated virtual orientation for the Level III and Level IV students as part
                               of  the  activity  in  their  Nursing  and  Leadership  Management  course
                               subject.



                                                                                                           91]]></page><page Index="93"><![CDATA[Instructional materials are aids to instruction. The utilization of varied

                          learning  materials  is  encouraged  among  faculty  members.  The  learner

                          centered  teaching  strategies  are  employed  to  foster  engagement  and


                          cooperation among students.  Activities that promote collaboration, critical

                          thinking and problem solving skills among students are encouraged.




                                Faculty  members  are  encouraged  to  formulate  their  own  learning

                        materials.  These  learning  materials  are  screened  and  reviewed  by  the

                        University  Textbook  Board  and  must  be  approved  prior  to  implementation.


                        Instructional materials are prepared  and utilized by concerned teachers and

                        reviewed and approved by the concerned authority. Student centeredness is


                        given  much  consideration  in  the  development  of  teaching  strategies  and

                        instructional materials.




                                Faculty members are also encouraged to source out and use various


                        instructional materials such as printed references and textbooks, as well  as

                        other materials such  as computer software and human models/replacement


                        that can aid in the delivery of instruction and in the learning process. This is

                        being  pursued  now  more  than  ever  as  academic  institutions  are  gearing

                        towards  outcome-based  teaching.  This  is  also  to  retain  global  relevance  of


                        nursing education.

                                Faculty  members  are  also  encouraged  to  produce  their  own  printed


                        instructional materials such as lecture books and laboratory manuals, guides,





                                                                                                           92]]></page><page Index="94"><![CDATA[and modules, and submit them to the University Textbook board for evaluation.

                        They are also strongly encouraged to come up with other materials such as


                        computer-based        tools    and      human      models/replacements.        The

                        models/replacements  are  usually  student  projects  to  assess  their


                        understanding of some principles and, at the same time, their creativity and

                        resourcefulness.


                                The  college  is  conducting  a  regular  academic  audit  on  instructional

                        resources such as syllabi, textbooks, modules, audiovisual materials, and other


                        references to maintain a high standard of instruction utilizing appropriate and

                        updated references and instructional methods in the module presentation and


                        evaluation  of  faculty  members.  Panel  of  evaluators  from  the  Instructional

                        Materials  Committee  reviewed  and  evaluated  the  materials  developed  by

                        faculty members.





























                                            nd
                        Figure 106. The 2 day of Webinar series with the title of Navigating Faculty
                         Knowledge  on  writing  Learning  Resource  Module  into  Guided  Hands-on
                         Module Writing and Embedding in the CvSU Evaluation Process has three
                         invited guest speakers from Nursing field.


                                                                                                           93]]></page><page Index="95"><![CDATA[Figure 107. The College of Nursing conducted a Webinar series proposed
                              by  Prof.  Nenita  B.  Panaligan  titled  navigating  Faculty  Knowledge  on
                              writing Learning Resource Module into Guided Hands-on Module Writing
                              and Embedding in the CvSU Evaluation Process.

























                              Figure 108. A photo during the closing ceremony with the organizers and
                              participants from various schools of nursing who successfully completed
                              the 8-week course on Designing Flexible Learning in Nursing facilitated
                              by the  College of Nursing , University of the Philippines Manila


                                                                                                           94]]></page><page Index="96"><![CDATA[Figure 109. A copy of the faculty assignment on course syllabus making
                              for the first semester of the Academic Year 2020-2021.

                        1.3.4. Administrative Support for Effective Instruction and Enhancement
                        of Learning



                                 The university administration headed by Dr. Hernando D. Robles, CEO

                        VI, with its dream of becoming a global university, has been very supportive of

                        the efforts of the college to enhance its capability of delivering effective and


                        relevant  instruction.  A  very  tangible  evidence  aside  from  the  Government


                        Recognition is the Certificate of Program Compliance (COPC) gained by the

                        college  on  September  17.  2018.  This  complies  to  the  CHED-RQAT

                        requirements as well as the compliance to AACCUP recommendations. The


                        establishment of facilities such as the Clinical Skills Laboratory are some of the

                        very significant evidence of the support that the administration extends to the





                                                                                                           95]]></page><page Index="97"><![CDATA[college.  The  administration  ensures  that  the  minimum  number  of  faculty

                        required  by  the  DVM  PSG  set  by  CHED  are  met  by  allotting  nine


                        permanent/temporary  plantilla  (Instructor  I  (7);  Instructor  II  (2)  to  those

                        deserving faculty members who have proven to be the best and the brightest


                        in the university. This makes CON one of the colleges in the university that has

                        90% to 100% board rating results in Nursing Licensure examinations


                                 The  University  Administration  headed  by  the  Office  of  the  Vice

                        President  of  Academic  Affairs  conducted  this  webinar  series  for  Flexible


                        Learning to enhance and support the management of learning during the global

                        health crisis of 2020 .























                              Figure  110.  The  College  of  Nursing  approved  recommendation  of  re-
                                                                                          st
                              hiring of faculty members who will be working for the 1 semester A Y
                              2020-2021.

                              During the pandemic, the faculty members were given flexible working

                       arrangement. A skeletal workforce report physically during office hours while


                       all  faculty  and  staff  made  themselves  readily  available  with  open  line

                       communication  for  work  purposes.  They  conduct  online  classes  at  the


                       comfort of their homes.



                                                                                                           96]]></page><page Index="98"><![CDATA[Figure  111. The Cavite State university adopted a learning management
                         system . The CvSU E learning platform has complete set of features that promote
                         effective  delivery  of  instruction  and  enhance  collaborative  learning  that  is
                         convenient and adaptable not only to the students but the facilitators of learning.
























                                                                                                           97]]></page><page Index="99"><![CDATA[Figure 112. Photos from class proceedings using video conferencing
                              for synchronous classes.























                                                                                                           98]]></page><page Index="100"><![CDATA[Figure 113. Photos from class proceedings using video conferencing
                              for synchronous classes.



























                              Figure  114.  Sample  learning  guide  for  nursing  research  subject
                              formulated by faculty members.













                                                                                                           99]]></page><page Index="101"><![CDATA[Figure 115 .  Learning modules created by nursing faculty members
                              for the course subject Healthcare Ethics.














                                                                                                          100]]></page><page Index="102"><![CDATA[Figure 116.   A learning module created by nursing faculty members
                              on the course subject Nursing Research.








                                                                                                          101]]></page><page Index="103"><![CDATA[Figure  117.  A  copy  of  the  approved  letter  for  the  schedule  of  flexible
                              working arrangement for faculty members.



















                                                                                                          102]]></page><page Index="104"><![CDATA[Figure  118.  This  webinar  series  and  e-mentoring  conducted  by  the
                        university administration in collaboration with different colleges, helps the
                        College of Nursing faculty members to enhance its capability of delivering
                        effective and relevant instruction.



                                 Collaboration in the workplace is included in the best practices in the


                        college  wherein  groups  of  faculty  members  from  other  department  work

                        together through idea sharing and thinking to accomplish a common goal. It is


                        simply teamwork taken to a higher level, joining together to accomplish a task.

                        With  the  changes  and  advancements  in  technology,  such  as  high-speed


                        Internet,  web-based  programs,  file  sharing,  email  and  videoconferencing,

                        collaboration has become a more productive way of doing things.



                                 The  College  of  Nursing  faculty  and  staff  collaborated  with  other


                        organization  like  Philippine  Nurses  Association,  Filipino  Nursing  Diaspora

                        Network, and other   government and private hospitals, community and industry


                        to  incorporate  different  perspectives  and  expertise  like  putting  our  heads

                        together'  to  raise  awareness  and  provide  professional  development  to  all




                                                                                                          103]]></page><page Index="105"><![CDATA[nurses  and  other  members  of  the  health  care  team  and  the  community  in

                        general.  Treating  everyone  as  equals  when  collaborating  can  open


                        communication  and  encourage  ideas  from  all  levels  of  the  college  or

                        department and it promotes a strong sense of purpose.























































                              Figure 119. Series of webinar were conducted in collaboration with the
                              Filipino Nursing Diaspora Network to gain advantage on the current trends
                              and  issues  in  nursing  practice.  The  most  recent  was  the  webinar
                              conducted  last  April  16,2021  with  the  theme  “  Perils  of  Predatory
                              Publishing  :  How  can  nurse  researchers  lead  the  way?”  and  “How  do
                              Healthcare  Professionals  Correct  Misinformation  in  Social  Media  last
                              August 29,2020.


                                                                                                          104]]></page><page Index="106"><![CDATA[Figure 104. Consultation and Peer mentoring commence before, during
                             and after each semester in the College of Nursing.


























                             Figure 120. The Faculty members and staff of the Cavite State University,
                             College of Nursing AY 2020-2021.



















                                                                                                          105]]></page><page Index="107"><![CDATA[Figure 121. The proposals and requests for the conduct of activities for the
                             students,  faculty  members  and  staff  of  the  College  of  Nursing  for  effective
                             Instruction and enhancement of learning are always being approved by the
                             administration.






























                             Figure  122.  The  establishment  of  facilities  such  as  the  Clinical  Skills
                             Laboratory are some of the very significant evidence of the support that the
                             administration extends to the College of Nursing.




                                                                                                          106]]></page><page Index="108"><![CDATA[Figure 123. Dr. Hernando D. Robles, the fast and serious with Malasakit -
                             CvSU President is an inspiration to the College of Nursing. Dr. Robles has
                             been very supportive of the efforts of the college to enhance its capability of
                             delivering effective and relevant instruction.







                        1.3.5. Assessment of Academic Performance of Students



                                It is made clear to faculty members that what they are assessing, with

                        regards to the performance of the students in class, is what they have learned


                        and not necessarily their mental capacity. The BSN program aims to produce

                        a fully functioning nurse who can perform the competencies under each of the


                        Key  Areas  of  Responsibility.  With  this,  the  faculty  members  are  strongly

                        encouraged  to  supplement  their  pen  and  paper  assessment  with  more


                        outcomes-based  assessment  schemes.  In  the  practical  courses,  they  are

                        encouraged to adopt more skills-based assessment methods. Alongside with

                        the traditional pen and paper methods, various outcomes-based assessment




                                                                                                          107]]></page><page Index="109"><![CDATA[is  also  being  adopted  by  the  faculty  members.  It  includes  the  different

                        evaluation  tools  intended  for  specific  learned  skills  demonstrated  by  the


                        students  and  was  graded  by  the  instructor  and  duly  signed.  The  learners

                        acknowledged their progress of learning by signing on the tools.



























                             Figure 124. This shows the different evaluation tools intended for specific
                             learned  skills  demonstrated  by  the  students  and  was  graded  by  the
                             instructor and duly signed. The learners acknowledged their progress of
                             learning by signing on the tools.



                                In line with the theoretical assessment of faculty, the students shall be

                        given opportunities to be exposed to the various levels of health care (health


                        promotion,  disease  prevention,  risk  reduction,  curative,  and  restoration  of

                        health)  with  various  client  groups  (individual,  family,  population  groups  and


                        community) in various settings (hospital, community). These opportunities shall

                        be given in graduated experiences to ensure that the competencies per course,

                        per  level  and  for  the  whole  program  are  developed.  Before  graduation,  the


                        student shall approximate the competencies of a professional nurse as they






                                                                                                          108]]></page><page Index="110"><![CDATA[assume  the  various  roles  and  responsibilities  after  passing  their  licensure

                        examination.


                                There are objectives that should be achieved for each year level. At the

                        end of the first year, the students shall have acquired an understanding and


                        awareness of themselves as an individual and as a member of the family, the

                        community,  and  the  world  with  emphasis  on  personal,  societal,  and


                        professional  values  responsibilities,  rights,  and  an  awareness  of  physical,

                        social,  and  cultural  milieu.  The  student  shall  have  an  awareness  of  the


                        competency-based  approach  in  the  curriculum  and  the  core  competencies

                        under  the  11  key  areas  of  responsibility:  safe  and  quality  nursing  care,


                        communication,  collaboration  and  teamwork,  health  education,  legal

                        responsibility,  ethico-moral  responsibility,  personal  and  professional

                        development, quality improvement, research, management of resources and


                        environment, and record management.

                                At  the  end  of  the  second  year,  the  student  shall  have  acquired  the


                        holistic  understanding  of  the  human  person  as  a  bio-psycho  cultural  being

                        focusing on the concept of health and illness as it is related to the care of the


                        mother and child in varied settings. The student shall be able to demonstrate

                        the competencies in the following key areas of responsibility such as safe and


                        quality  nursing  care,  communication,  collaboration  and  teamwork,  health

                        education,  legal  responsibility,  ethico-moral  responsibility,  personal  and


                        professional  development,  quality  improvement,  research,  management  of

                        resources and environment, and record management.





                                                                                                          109]]></page><page Index="111"><![CDATA[Figure 125. The BS Nursing Level II student and their clinical instructors
                            during their exposure in the community



                                At the end of the third year, given actual clients/situation with various

                        physiologic  and  psychosocial  alterations,  the  student  shall  be  able  to


                        demonstrate the competencies in the following key areas of responsibility such

                        as safe and quality nursing care, communication, collaboration and teamwork,


                        health education, legal responsibility, ethico-moral responsibility, personal and

                        professional  development,  quality  improvement,  research,  management  of


                        resources and environment, and record management.

                                At the end of the 4th year, given actual clients/situation the student shall


                        be able to demonstrate competencies in all the key areas of responsibility such

                        as safe and quality nursing care, communication, collaboration and teamwork,


                        health education, legal responsibility, ethico-moral responsibility, personal and




                                                                                                          110]]></page><page Index="112"><![CDATA[professional  development,  quality  improvement,  research,  management  of

                        resources and environment, and record management .




























                              Figure  126.  The  BSN  4th  year  students  exposed  in  the  actual
                              clients/situation  to  be  able  to  demonstrate  competencies  in  all  the  key
                              areas of responsibility.


































                              Figure 127. A copy of accomplished checklist of performance in
                              Immediate newborn care of BS Nursing student.




                                                                                                          111]]></page><page Index="113"><![CDATA[Figure 128. A copy of accomplished clinical requirements of BS Nursing
                              students signed by their supervising clinical instructors.





                                                                                                          112]]></page><page Index="114"><![CDATA[Some of the best practices of the CvSU BSN program is
                               the grounding and preparation of its nursing students to be globally

                               competitive nurses. The CvSU BS Nursing program has academic
                               policies for the admission, retention, and promotion of students.

                               Highschool  graduates  are  required  to  undergo  the  university
                               qualifying exam for admission. Those who successfully qualified

                               into the program undergo a medical exam and an interview prior

                               to the admission to ensure that they are mental and physically able
                               to complete the program. A CvSU BS Nursing student is expected

                               to maintain a general weighted average of at least 2.25 to advance
                               and continue with the succeeding levels of the program.



                                      Students are made aware and encourage to perform in their
                               academic requirements with satisfactory remarks. No student can

                               be promoted unless the academic requirements of each level are
                               satisfied.  In addition, the CvSU BSN students are subjected to

                               battery exam and achievement test prior to the promotion to the

                                 rd
                                         th
                               3  and 4  level. Peer tutoring is highly encouraged and practiced
                               among students.  All these are some of the best practices of the
                               CvSU BS Nursing program in preparing students to be competitive
                               nurses  after  graduation.  These  practices  serve  as  one  of  their

                               training  ground  for  their  national  licensure  examinations,  all  of
                               which  contribute  to  the  high  passing  rate  in  nursing  licensure

                               examinations.

















                                                                                                          113]]></page><page Index="115"><![CDATA[Figure 129. The BSN students graduated with the competencies of
                              a  beginning  nurse  as  they  assume  the  various  roles  and
                              responsibilities of a professional nurse after passing their licensure
                              examination.


                        1.3.6. Assessment of Graduates





                               The graduates of the BS Nursing program are continuously assessed

                          through  monitoring  of  their  performances  in  the  licensure  examinations,

                          regular  tracer  studies  conducted  by  the  college  job  placement  unit  and


                          maintaining  linkages  with  the  alumni.  Faculty  members  provide  assistance

                          support during the conduct of their licensure examinations to boost the morale


                          of the graduates while taking their nursing licensure examination. The various

                          achievements of the graduates in their careers are acknowledged not only by


                          their employers but the university.


                         .


                                                                                                          114]]></page><page Index="116"><![CDATA[Figure  130 . Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo , the Dean of the College of Nursing and
                         Ms. Jocelyn M. Dimayuga ,the clinical coordinator and Prof. Nenita B. Panaligan,
                         the  quality  assurance  coordinator  as  they    provide  emotional  support  to
                         graduates during the conduct of licensure examination.



                                                                                                          115]]></page><page Index="117"><![CDATA[1.3.6.1. Performance in the Nursing Licensure Examination





                                The performance of BSN graduates of the CvSU College of Nursing in

                         the national licensure examinations has been consistently above the national

                         passing average The BS Nursing program has produced a board topnotcher,


                                                                     th
                         Ms. April Lynelle Dayto, bagging the   9  place in November 2014 Nursing
                         Licensure Examination.


                                Moreover, the CvSU Nursing Licensure Examination results are even

                         exemplified with actual ratings compared to the national passing rates. The


                         difference  of  the  of  the  CvSU  graduate’s  performance  in  contrast  to  the

                         national passing rate recorded as high as 47.27% above the national passing


                         percentage.  The  statistics  shows  that  the  CvSU  BS  Nursing  graduates

                         performance  have  an  average  of  28.48  %  for  the  licensure  examinations


                         covered from the year 2016-2019.

                                The outstanding  performances to the national licensure examinations

                         has proven the quality and competence of the graduates of CvSU BS Nursing


                         program.

                                According to the certification released by the Professional Regulation


                         Commission, the Cavite State University graduates who took the PRC Nursing

                         Licensure Examination were able to pass at the first attempt with the passing


                         percentage averaging at   94.41%   from 2016-2019. The results are carefully

                         deliberated to further improve the curriculum and the outcomes of the national


                         licensure examination.




                                                                                                          116]]></page><page Index="118"><![CDATA[th
                                Figure 131. CvSU graduate Ms. April Lynelle Dayto ranked as 9  place
                         in the November 2014 nursing licensure examination as recognized by the
                         Professional Regulations Commission.
































                             Figure 132. Performance of CON graduates in the Bachelor of Science in
                             Nursing licensure examination from 2014 to 2019.










                                                                                                          117]]></page><page Index="119"><![CDATA[Figure  133.  Batch  2016  performed  well  in  the  Bachelor  of  Science  in
                              Nursing licensure examination with the rating of 94% for the first timers
                              over the national passing average of 47.73%.





























                              Figure 134. Batch 2017 garnered 100% rating in the Bachelor of Science
                              0in  Nursing  licensure  examination  for  the  first  timers  over  the  national
                              passing average of 45.65%.



                                                                                                          118]]></page><page Index="120"><![CDATA[ANALYSIS OF THE NURSES LICENSURE EXAMINATION RESULTS OF
                               THE BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN NURSING OF CAVITE STATE
                                                            UNIVERSITY


                            Table 1 shows the overall results of the nurse licensure examination of the
                    Bachelor of Science in Nursing of Cavite State University, Main Campus, Indang,

                    Cavite.  The  College  of  Nursing  graduates  obtained  a  100%  passing  percentage
                    among first time takers which was above the national passing rate in three years. In

                    June 2019, with 52.20 national passing percentage (NP), while in November 2017

                    with NP of 45.65 and in May 2015 with 54.26 national passing percentage.
                            Meanwhile  in  November  2014  to  November  2019,  the  CON  graduates

                    obtained the NLE results ranging from 93. 88% to 94.74% which were above the
                    national  passing  average  ranging  from  39.99%  to  57.31%.  The  NLE  results  of

                    November 2016 got the highest score of  94.74 % (NP 47.73), while 94.00% (NP
                    39.99) in November 2019, then 93.86% (NP 49.26) in November 2014 and 92.86%

                    (NP 49.26) in November 2015.

                            However, in June 2012, the College of Nursing graduates obtained 87.12%
                    with NP percentage of 45.69%, followed by 83.33% each in June 2016 (NP 43.60)

                    and November 2018 (NP 39.99), respectively. In addition, there was 80% (NP 30.94)

                    in December 2013.
                               In May 2014, the CON graduates were able to have a 66.67% (NP 38.46)

                    and  60.87%  (NP  42.81)  in  June  2013.  In  December  2011  and  2012,  the  CON
                    graduates obtained the NLE results ranging from 55. 56% to 58.97% which were

                    above the national passing average ranging from 33. 92% to 34.46%, respectively.
                    There were no takers in June 2017 and June 2018.

                               This indicate that all the results of the Nurses Licensure Examination of

                    the Bachelor of Science in Nursing of Cavite State University, Main Campus, Indang,
                    Cavite  among  first  time  takers  were  all  above  the  national  passing  rate  from

                    December 2011 to November 2019.








                                                                                                          119]]></page><page Index="121"><![CDATA[NAT’L  Difference
                               FIRST TIME        TOTAL    CvSu   REPEATERS   TOTAL   CvSu     OVER   PASSING
                                TAKERS                    CON                        CON      ALL     %     CvSU
                                                                                                            CON
                                                          Passing %                  Passing %              Vs
                                                                                                            Nat’l
                                                                                                           Passing
                                                                                                             %
                              Passed   Failed   Cond            Passed   Failed
                     Nov       47       3     0    50     94.00    2     3    5      40.00   89.09   55.20   +33.89
                      2019
                      June     1        0     0     1    100.00    0     1    1      0.00    50.00   52.20   -2.5
                      2019
                      Nov      10       2     0    12     83.33    0     1    1      0.00    76.92   39.99   +36.89
                      2018
                      June     0        0     0     0     0.00     2     1    3      66.67   66.67   43.82   +22.85
                      2018
                      Nov      21       0     0    21    100.00    0     2    2      0.00    91.30   45.65   +45.65
                      2017
                      June     0        0     0     0     0.00     1     1    2      50.00   50.00   34.74   +15.26
                      2017
                      Nov      18       1     0    19     94.74    1     0    1      100.00   95.00   47.73   +47.27
                      2016
                      June     5        1     0     6     83.33    4     2    6      66.67   75.00   43.60   +31.4
                      2016
                      Nov      26       2     0    28     92,86    7     0    7      100.00   94.29   49.26   +45.03
                      2015
                      May      1        0     0     1    100.00    2     1    3      66.67   75.00   54.26   +20.74
                      2015
                      Nov      46       3     0    49     93.88    4     4    8      50.00   87.72   57.31   +30.41
                      2014
                      May      2        1     0     3     66.67    3     8    11     27.27   35.71   38.46   -2.75
                      2014
                      Dec      4        1     0     5     80.00    10    14   24     41.67   48.28   30.94   +17.34
                      2013
                      June     42      27     0    69     60.87    5     6    11     45.45   58.75   42.81   +15.94
                      2013
                      Dec      5        4     0     9     55.56    9     14   23     39.13   43.75   34.46   +9.29
                      2012
                      June     115     16     1    13     87.12    12    6    18     66.67   84.67   45.69   +38.98
                      2012                          2
                      Dec      23      16     0    39     58.97    8     8    16     50.00   56.36   33.92   +22.44
                      2011

                       Table I. The Nurses Licensure Examination Results of the Bachelor of Science in
                       Nursing of Cavite State University, Main Campus, Indang, Cavite.




























                                                                                                          120]]></page><page Index="122"><![CDATA[Figure 135. The CvSU CON batch 2019 graduate nurses as they take
                              their oath for their chosen profession of nursing. They are now the new
                              registered nurses of the Philippines with high passing rate (94%) in the
                              Nursing  national  licensure  examination.  They  are  all  employed  in  the
                              hospitals as frontlines in this COVID 19 pandemic period.







                        1.3.6.2. Employability of Graduates and Employers’ Feedback




                                The graduates of the CvSU Bachelor of Science in Nursing are highly


                        employable. Based on the regular tracer study being conducted by the College

                        of  Nursing  in  coordination  with  the  Job  Placement  Unit  of  the  Office  of  the

                        Student Affairs, majority of the graduates are employed in the public and private


                        hospitals local and abroad, national government agencies, local government

                        units, academic institutions, and the armed forces, among others.











                                                                                                          121]]></page><page Index="123"><![CDATA[The CvSU BSN graduates are not only highly employable but are


                          recognized  for  their  excellence  and  leadership.  CvSU  BSN  graduates

                          occupies top positions in their respective public and private institutions.  The


                          CvSU BS Nursing graduates are employed in the Department of Health and

                          Local  Government  Units  as  the  program  coordinators,  health  education


                          program  officer,  head  nurses  in  public  and  private  hospitals,  Dean,  and

                          Instructors in the schools of nursing and on top of that as officers  in various


                          nursing  organizations  such  as  Philippine  Nurses  Association,  Operating

                          Room  Nurses  Association,  and  Philippine  Nursing  Research  Society  Inc.


                          and Toxicology Nurses Association of the Philippines among others.





                                 In the past 5 years, majority of the graduates were hired immediately


                        after passing the board exams. Most of the employment facilities are the nearby

                        hospitals  while  several  graduates  were  also  able  to  secure  positions  in  the

                        biggest hospitals in the country namely Asian Hospital and Medical Center and


                        St. Luke’s Medical Center, among others.


                                The shortage of nurses in the local and international settings    makes it


                        easier for the graduates to secure entry positions at various facilities.  As they

                        grow into the profession, they acquire significant positions that showcase their


                        leadership abilities.  The growing turnover rate of nurses in the hospitals are

                        manifestations of the dire need to produce more of the quality and employable


                        graduate nurses.




                                                                                                          122]]></page><page Index="124"><![CDATA[Figure 136 . Ms. Annalyn C. Barrientos ,   Neonatal Intensive Care Unit
                              Nurse at a  Maternity and Pediatric Hospital in Bisha, Kingdom of Saudi
                              Arabia. Ms Barrientos is from CvSU BSN Batch 2017.


































                              Figure 137. Mr. Jess Christian Jade B. Dycoco , a BSN graduate from
                              Batch 2009 is currently working as a psychiatric nurse at Carmel Clarke
                              Medical Center , West Virginia in USA.




                                                                                                          123]]></page><page Index="125"><![CDATA[There has also been good feedback from employers of the graduates of

                        the  College  of  Nursing,  their  usual  comments  are  that  CvSU  graduates  are


                        excellent and is ranked higher than other entry level nurses from other private

                        schools. CvSU graduate nurses have the distinct dedication to the service and


                        are clinically equipped with the necessary skills as entry level nurses. Most of

                        the  supervisory  positions  in  the  hospital  within  the  province  of  Cavite  are


                        occupied by the CvSU, CON graduate nurses. Many of the graduates are also

                        doing good with their respective workplace abroad. They were able to pass and


                        qualify with the positions in the different institutions abroad. Favorable feedback

                        was noted from their employers.


                                         2017 BSN Graduates Employment Rate


                                                                 0 0







                                                              21, 100%





                                                 Employed   Note Employed  Not Tracked


                        Figure 138. Employment rate of Batch 2017 BS Nursing graduates



                              The figure shows the rating of the BS Nursing graduates of the College of

                        Nursing  that  are  employed.  The  Bachelor  of  Science  in  Nursing  graduates’


                        batch 2017 gained 100% employment rating 2 years after graduation covering

                        all 21 graduates.   Majority of them gained employment in various hospitals


                        within Cavite province.


                                                                                                          124]]></page><page Index="126"><![CDATA[2016 BSN Graduates Employment Rate

                                                             1, 5%
                                                      1, 5%







                                                                       17, 90%







                                                   Employed   Unemployed   Not Tracked


                        Figure 139. Employment rate of Batch 2016 BS Nursing graduates


                              The Bachelor of Science in Nursing Batch 2016 gained 90%


                        employment rate covering the 17 graduates out of 19. The remaining 5%

                        accounts to a foreign student who went back to his home country and the


                        other 5% to a BSN graduate who is now a full time Medicine student.




                                          2015 BSN Graduates Employment Rate


                                                    3, 8%
                                                               3, 8%





                                                                        31, 84%







                                                   Employed   Unemployed   Not Tracked


                       Figure 140 . Employment rate of Batch 2015 BS Nursing graduates







                                                                                                          125]]></page><page Index="127"><![CDATA[The Bachelor of Scince in Nursing Batch 2015 graduate gained an 84%

                        employment rate while the 8% accounts to the unemployed who are in further


                        study and migration to other countries as the were married to foreign nationals.





                                                  Employability Status of CvSU
                                                             BSN Graduates
                                                                 2015-2018



























                                                  Employed   Unemployed   Not Tracked


                        Figure 141. Majority of the graduates of the BS Nursing Batch 2015-2018 are
                        employed  immediately  after  graduation.  Based  on  the  short  tracer  study
                        conducted by the Office of the Student Affairs and the College of Nursing. 89%
                        of  the  graduates  are  employed  in  various  sectors  while  there  are  2  %
                        unemployed  due  to  further  studies  and  personal  reasons.  Some  of  the
                        graduates at about   9% are left untracked due to no response to the study
                        while others belong to the foreign graduates that have returned to their home
                        country.















                                                                                                          126]]></page><page Index="128"><![CDATA[Sector of Employment




















                                                     Private  Government  Overseas


                        Figure  142  The  CvSU  BSN  graduates  are  employed  in  various  sectors.
                        Majority of the employed graduates, 77.2 % of Batch 2015-2018 are employed
                        in the private hospital and healthcare facilities, while the 13.9 % are employed
                        in government hospitals , national agencies and local government units and
                        there were also  8.9 % with  overseas employment.



                              Based on the feedback of employers including the top hospitals  in the

                        country,  the  CvSU  BS  Nursing  graduates  are  well  motivated  in  performing


                        assigned  tasks,  responsive  to  workplace  challenges  and  enthusiastic  for

                        updates  and  professional  development.  The  CvSU  graduates  are  equipped


                        with the required knowledge and skills foe the positions. They are also able to

                        work well with coworkers and the management.























                                                                                                          127]]></page><page Index="129"><![CDATA[Figure 143. Mr. Alwie A. Torrente (right) member of the BS Nursing Class of
                          2017 was a former student council president and is now employed in De La
                          Salle University Medical Center at the same time one of CON part time clinical
                          instructor.
































                          Figure 144. Ms. Trixie Loise H. Icaza of Batch 2019, currently employed at
                          Divine  Grace  Medical  Center  in  General  Trias  City  Cavite.  She  was
                          immediately  hired  after  the  release  of  the  Philippine  Nursing  Licensure
                          Examination  last December  2019. She proudly represents  the  CvSU BSN
                          Batch of 2019.



                                                                                                          128]]></page><page Index="130"><![CDATA[The alumni of the BS Nursing program of Cavite State University are

                          not only employable but are productive in their field of specialties. CvSU BS


                          Nursing  alumni  are  deployed  in  the  local  and  national  government  units

                          holding significant positions. Alumni are recognized for their hard work and


                          contribution on their various workplaces.



















































                            Figure 145. Mr. Ralph Lawrence Figueroa of the Batch 2008 and Mr. Jay
                            Louie S. Madlangbayan of Batch 2016 both alumni of the CvSU College of
                            Nursing became the  panelist/ speaker in the recent Webinar series of the
                            College of Nursing in collaboration with the Philippine Nurses Association-
                            Cavite chapter and PCHRD Consortium Inc. last August 8, 2020 via Cisco
                            Webex.



                                                                                                          129]]></page><page Index="131"><![CDATA[Figure 146. CON BS Nursing graduates and Alumni are recognized for their
                        excellent performances at their workplaces.




                                                                                                          130]]></page><page Index="132"><![CDATA[Figure 147. CON alumnus Alwie  Torrente, RN, presented research paper
                          entitled  “Unravelling  the  Life  of  Incarcerated  Pregnancy  Women”  in  3   rd
                                                                                         st
                          Gender and Development Research Conference and won 1 Place last June
                          14,2018 at International House I , CvSU Indang Cavite . He also presented
                          the same paper as entry of CvSU GAD in Nueva Ecija with the College GAD
                          Coordinator, Ms. Antoniette D. Viray.RN, MAN.



                               The overwhelming words from alumni of the College of Nursing is special.


                        They remembered an affinity shared among students, staff, and faculty. Many

                        of them verbalized their gratitude to all of the professors and clinical instructors

                        in  the  college  for  encouraging  them  to  excel.  The  college  prepared,  guide


                        students and motivated them to meet challenges in working as a nurse in our

                        country and in international arena. Mr.Junjun Dualan, who belongs to the 1        st



                                                                                                          131]]></page><page Index="133"><![CDATA[batch of BSN in 2006, told that during his time at CvSU, CON, has was exposed

                        to  many  challenges  and  opportunities  from  the  initial  days  up  to  .  time  he


                        graduated.  He  was  now  confident  presenting  his  own  work  to  the  nursing

                        community and grateful enough for the transformative opportunity to study at


                        Cavite State        University. CvSU prepared him to be one of the best  in

                        his  field of specialization.




























                           Figure 148. Alumni of the College  of Nursing who  are working abroad in
                                   different special areas like operating room, emergency rooms and
                                   with other type of cultures.






























                                                                                                          132]]></page><page Index="134"><![CDATA[Figure  149.  Mr.  Junjun  Dualan,  RN,  MAN  is  presently  working  in  Rashid
                           Hospital Burn Unit in Dubai. Mr. Junjun Dualan  presented his research paper
                           in  an  international  conference  in  Dubai,  Burn  Management  Conference  in
                           Movenpick Grand Al Bustan Dubai. He was also able to publish his research
                           paper  in  the  Philippine  Journal  of  Nursing  Education  and  internationally
                           through  Journal  of  Burn  Care  and  Research  and  Wound  ,  Ostomy  and
                           Continence Nurses Society.





















                                                                                                          133]]></page><page Index="135"><![CDATA[Figure 150. Mr. Junjun Dualan, RN, MAN received his plaque of being the
                         Guest speaker in an international conference in Dubai from the Gulf Health
                         Council in 2018.




























                             Figure 151. Ms. Jezza Crucena-Aclan, an alumnus of the CvSU College
                             of Nursing Batch working in the Department of Health, Philippines
                             became the representative of the country in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia













                                                                                                          134]]></page><page Index="136"><![CDATA[Figure 132.  Ms. Jezza Crucena -
                                                                                Aclan is with the Department of
                                                                                Health Epidemiology Bureau with
                                                                                support from the World Health
                                                                                Organization conducted last May
                                                                                17-20,2016 the second batch of
                                                                                the training on Data for Action:
                                                                                Assessing Risk and Responding to
                                                                                Polio Outbreaks .Regional
                                                                                Epidemiology and Surveillance
                                                                                Unit (RESU) Officers from eight
                                                                                regions participated in the training
                                                                                held at City State Tower Hotel
                                                                                Manila































                              Figure 152. Ms Jezza Jonah  Crucena-Aclan was chosen to be one of the
                              Best Alumni in  the Grand Alumni Celebration in 2017.


















                                                                                                          135]]></page><page Index="137"><![CDATA[Figure 153 . Mr. Son Michel Mariano , RN, MPH is a graduate of CvSU
                              BSN Batch of 2012. He is staff nurse in the Philippine General Hospital
                              trauma ward with clinical rotations in emergency department and other
                              surgical  areas.    He  is  currently  taking  his  second  Post  Baccalaureate
                              degree  in  Master  in  Hospital  Administration  at  the  University  of  the
                              Philippines Manila where he also finished his Master of Public Health in
                              2017. He is the founding and current president of the Toxicology Nurses
                              Association of the Philippines.




























                              Figure  154.  Mr.  Louis  Carlos  O.  Roderos,  Instructor  and  the  Student
                              Council Adviser   at the College of Nursing of Cavite State University. Mr.
                              Roderos is from CvSU BSN  Batch 2012.







                                                                                                          136]]></page><page Index="138"><![CDATA[Figure 155.  Mr. Jomelle Mojica , Nurse V &  Dengue Prevention and
                              Control Program Coordinator at Department of Health- Center for Health
                              Development Region 4A. Mr. Mojica is from































                              Figure  156    Mr.  Ralph  Lawrence  A.  Figueroa,  the  Health  Education
                              Program Officer of Cavite Provincial Health Office . Mr. Figueroa belongs
                              to the CvSU BSN Batch 2008.




                                                                                                          137]]></page><page Index="139"><![CDATA[Figure 157. Ms. Geneva C. Calanog , Nurse III from the Department of
                              Health Region 4A. Ms. Calanog is from CvSU BSN Batch 2009.






























                              Figure 158.  Mr. Reymart B.  Bolagao is the Dean of the School of
                              Nursing and the Director for Academic Affairs of St. Jude College
                              Dasmarinas City, Cavite. He is a BS Nursing graduate of Batch 2013.












                                                                                                          138]]></page><page Index="140"><![CDATA[Figure  159.  Mr  Jay  Louie  S  Madlangbayan  ,  Cardiovascular  Surgery
                              Nurse and  the current Clinical Nurse Training Development Officer at De
                              La Salle University Medical Center. He is an NLE review lecturer and the
                              current  President  of  the  Operation  Room  Nurses  Association  of  the
                              Philippines Cavite Chapter. Mr. Madlangbayan belongs the CvSU BSN
                              Batch 2016.



                       1.4.   REASONABLE BUDGET



                                The  university  administration  recognizes  the  needs  of  the  college


                        through the allotment of reasonable budget for its operations and development.

                        Being  a  college  that  have  three  curriculum  programs  and  many  enrolled


                        students, recommendations from the assessment made by the CHED RQAT

                        and AACUP visits are well taken. The number of projects is planned according


                        to these considerations and are submitted to the administration for approval.

                        The administration has been very supportive with every relative projects of the


                        college.








                                                                                                          139]]></page><page Index="141"><![CDATA[Figure 160. The Copy of the Supply, Delivery and Installation of Laboratory
                             Supplies and Equipment for College of Nursing.

                       1.5.  PROVISION OF MATERIALS AND OTHER RESOURCES



                        1.5.1. Human Resources





                                     The  college  has  adopted  various  strategies  to  provide  the  best

                              human  resources.  The  aim  is  to  comply  with  the  minimum  number  of


                              faculty set by CHED but foremost, to form a team with the expertise and

                              the  shared  vision.  The  college  also  hired  support  personnel  for  key


                                                                                                          140]]></page><page Index="142"><![CDATA[functions especially for the research and teaching laboratory and clinic, as

                              well as administrative support. Shown in the table is the list of the college.


                              The list of the current faculty and staff College Designated officials of the

                              CON and their Position is provided in Appendix H.

































                        Figure 161. All Faculty members and staff of the College of Nursing







                       1.5.2. Physical Resources


                                The  college  is  well  supported  by  the  university  when  it  comes  in


                        providing global responsive nursing education. Nursing Arts Laboratory are not

                        only  equipped  with  the  requirements  set  by  the  Commission  on  Higher

                        Education but also provide a level of development that is at par with the best


                        universities  providing  nursing  education.  It  is  certain  that  these  physical

                        resources are well utilized in the enhancement of student’s clinical skills. The





                                                                                                          141]]></page><page Index="143"><![CDATA[college acquired the Meti Man Human Patient Simulator Model last 2014 that

                        has been very facilitative in the simulation of different medical scenarios for the


                        nursing students.


                               There was an audit conducted last September 3, 2020 by the Internal


                        Quality Audit Team comprises of two members. The audit team have checked

                        on the Management of Learning of CON and physical visit was also done to


                        every parts of the building.













































                              Figure 162. Meti Man , the human patient simulator inside the Nursing
                              Arts Laboratory with the nursing students during their clinical simulation
                              activities while being observed by the Clinical Instructor.





                                                                                                          142]]></page><page Index="144"><![CDATA[Figure 163. internal Quality Audit was conducted last September 3, 2020
                             by the Audit Team comprises of two members. They were able to check
                             the physical resources of CON.





                                                                                                          143]]></page><page Index="145"><![CDATA[1.6. PARTICIPATION OF SIGNIFICANT NUMBER OF FACULTY/STAFF IN
                        MAJOR PROJECTS/ ACTIVITIES



                                The faculty and staff have target activities per semester that is aligned


                        to  the  college  and  university’s  vision  and  mission.  Most  of  the  programs  is

                        purposively  planned to meet the objectives in the curriculum,  research, and


                        extension. The dean and the faculty members are engaged in research that

                        would yield applicable practices and products for the benefit of the university


                        and the community. This is a funded research from the Department of Interior

                        Local Government.




















































                                                                                                          144]]></page><page Index="146"><![CDATA[FOCUS GROUP DISCUSSION (FGD)


                                        (MUNICIPALITY OF ROSARIO, CAVITE)















                        Figure 164. CSIS Field Work Survey At Magallanes, Cavite last April 14 and
                        15,  2018.The  Brgy.  Captain  and  Brgy  Tanod  of  Tua  ,  Magallanes  ,  Cavite
                        together with the Field Supervisor’s Prof. Jocelyn B. Dimayuga from the College
                        of Nursing and Prof Susan along with Field Interviewer’s during courtesy call at
                        Brgy. Tua , Magallanes, Cavite. Dr. Evelyn M. Del Mundo, Dean of the College
                        of Nursing is the Project Leader of this CSIS in Municipality of Magallanes.















                                                                                                          145]]></page><page Index="147"><![CDATA[Figure 165. CSIS Field Work Survey At Magallanes, Cavite last April 14 and
                        15,  2018.The  Brgy.  Captain  and  Brgy  Tanod  of  Tua  ,  Magallanes  ,  Cavite
                        together with the Field Supervisor’s Prof. Jocelyn B. Dimayuga from the College
                        of Nursing and Prof Susan along with Field Interviewer’s during courtesy call at
                        Brgy. Tua , Magallanes, Cavite. Dr. Evelyn M. del Mundo, dean of the College
                        of Nursing is the Project Leader of this CSIS in Municipality of Magallanes.


                        1.7. AWARDS OF DISTINCTION AND ACHIEVEMENT AND GRANTS OF

                             THE BS NURSING PROGRAM



                                The  BS  Nursing  Program  have  been  recognized  for  the  meritorious

                        achievements.  The  program,  faculty,  students,  and  the  college  have  been


                        acknowledged  for  notable  efforts  and  excellent  performances.  All  these

                        citations become an inspiration to always strive for excellence.


                                The  quality  of  the  graduates  CvSU  BS  Nursing  graduates  can  be


                        reflected  with  the  performances  in  the  nursing  licensure  examination.  The

                        CvSU nursing licensure passing rate is consistently above the national passing


                                                                  th
                        rate. Ms. April Lynelle. Dayto ranked 9  place in the November 2014 Nursing
                        Licensure Examination.


                                                                                                          146]]></page><page Index="148"><![CDATA[Figure 166. Ms. April Lynelle Dayto of the Cavite State University BS Nursing
                                                    th
                         Batch  of  2014  ranked  9   place  in  the  November  2014  Philippine  Nursing
                         Licensure Examination.


                              The list of Awards of Distinction,   Achievement, and Grants Received by


                        Faculty Members of CvSU College of Nursing is provided in Appendix I, while


                        the list of Awards of Distinction, Achievement and Grants Received by Students

                        and Alumni of CvSU College of Nursing is provided in Appendix J.






















                                                                                                          147]]></page><page Index="149"><![CDATA[Figure  167.    The  College  of  Nursing  won  the  following  awards:  Champion
                         Pledge  25:  Blood  Olympics  2019,  Champion,  Bayanihan  Award:  Most
                         Organized  Mobile  Blood  Drive,  Award:  School  with  the  Number  of  Blood
                         Donors yielding 267 Blood Units given by the Philippine Red Cross on January
                         11, 2020 at City Mall Anabu Event and Activity Center, Imus Cavite.








                                                                                                          148]]></page><page Index="150"><![CDATA[Figure 168. Most Outstanding Alumnus 2019, Ivan Derek Wycoco from Our
                        Lady of Fatima University on January 18, 2020 at Shangrila, Makati Manila.















                                                                                                          149]]></page><page Index="151"><![CDATA[Figure 169. Mr. Alwie Torrente a faculty and an alumnus of the College of
                          Nursing presenting his research that won the Best Gender and Development
                          Research Paper at the Gender and Development Research Conference last
                          June 2018.












                                                                                                          150]]></page><page Index="152"><![CDATA[Figure 170 . Prof. Nenita B. Panaligan and Prof. Karen Louella R. Rint, both
                         from the College of Nursing were among the first interim officers of the first
                         PNRSI Philippine Nursing Research Society Inc. Cavite Chapter held during
                         the first General Assembly last October 9,2020.












                                                                                                          151]]></page><page Index="153"><![CDATA[The College of Nursing is very proud of its achievements in different

                         aspects of academic, research and extension. Our Alumni and students are


                         gaining awards and recognitions both in their workplaces and the important

                         social responsibilities are always in their heart. The College of Nursing best


                         practice of hiring faculty members and staff not only by their qualifications but

                         also by their good attitude is effective in achieving the VMGO of the college


                         and the University.






























                          Figure 171. Ms. Jezza Crucena-Aclan (at the center) recognized as the
                           Best Alumni of 2018 by the Cavite State University Alumni Association
                           awarded by Dr. Ruperto Sanggalang, the former University President and
                           CHED Commissioner.




















                                                                                                          152]]></page><page Index="154"><![CDATA[Figure 172 . Mr. Ralph Lawrence A. Figueroa, the Health Education Program
                         Officer  of  Cavite  Provincial  Health  Office  .He  has  been  recognized  for  his
                         quality service as a government employee by  the Civil Service Commission .
                         Mr. Figueroa belongs to the CvSU BSN Batch 2008.



                                                                                                          153]]></page><page Index="155"><![CDATA[Figure 173 .Mr. Lester Abad of the CvSU  BS Nursing  Batch 2012
                                   was granted a Diploma in International Health from the University of
                                   the Philippines Open University.




























                                   Figure 174. Mr. Wilfred B. Javier an alumnus of CvSU BS Nursing
                                                                                                          st
                                   Batch  2011  was  recognized  the  University  of  the  Philippines  1
                                   Virtual Commencement Exercises held last December 5, 2020. Mr.
                                   Javier is included as the Dean’s List for his Master of Arts in Nursing
                                   degree.





                                                                                                          154]]></page><page Index="156"><![CDATA[Figure 175 . Prof. Louis Carlos Roderos , faculty from the CvSU College of
                              Nursing in collaboration with the PNA Cavite Chapter  during the distribution
                              of the personal protective equipment at the height of PPE supplies shortage
                              . Food and other supplies were distributed   for the alumni of the college
                              who are deployed as frontlines at different hospitals and LGU during the
                              pandemic last March, April and May 2020.









                                                                                                          155]]></page><page Index="157"><![CDATA[Figure 176. Prof. Louis Carlos Roderos , faculty from the CvSU College of
                              Nursing in collaboration with the PNA Cavite Chapter  during the distribution
                              of the personal protective equipment at the height of PPE supplies shortage
                              . Food and other supplies were distributed   for the alumni of the college
                              who are deployed as frontlines at different hospitals and LGU during the
                              pandemic last March, April and May 2020.













                                                                                                          156]]></page><page Index="158"><![CDATA[At  present,  the  Cavite  State  university  BS  Nursing  graduates  are

                        deployed at various local, national and overseas hospitals. The relationship of


                        the  College  of  Nursing  with  the  Alumni  is  maintained  through  continuous

                        linkages and collaborations on special projects being conducted by the college


                        and the university.






























                          Figure 177. Prof. Louis Carlos Roderos , faculty from the CvSU College  of
                          Nursing in collaboration with the PNA Cavite Chapter  during the distribution of
                          the  personal  protective  equipment  at  the  height  of  PPE  supplies  shortage  .
                          Food and other supplies were distributed   for the alumni of the college who are
                          deployed as frontlines at different hospitals and LGU during the pandemic last
                          March, April and May 2020.























                                                                                                          157]]></page><page Index="159"><![CDATA[Figure 178. Postings of recognition from the institutions and the alumni for the
                         distribution of PPE’s conducted by the CvSU College of Nursing in collaboration
                         with the PNA Cavite Chapter.



































                        Figure 179 . Postings of recognition from the institutions and the alumni for the
                         distribution of PPE’s conducted by the CvSU College of Nursing in collaboration
                         with the PNA Cavite Chapter.



                                                                                                          158]]></page><page Index="160"><![CDATA[Figure 180. Postings of recognition from the institutions and the alumni for the
                         distribution of PPE’s conducted by the CvSU College of Nursing in collaboration
                         with the PNA Cavite Chapter.




























                              Figure 181. Postings of recognition from the institutions and the alumni for
                              the  distribution  of  PPE’s  conducted  by  the  CvSU  College  of  Nursing  in
                              collaboration with the PNA Cavite Chapter.








                                                                                                          159]]></page><page Index="161"><![CDATA[Figure 182. Postings of recognition from the institutions and the alumni for
                               the  distribution  of  PPE’s  conducted  by  the  CvSU  College  of  Nursing  in
                               collaboration with the PNA Cavite Chapter.


















                                                                                                          160]]></page><page Index="162"><![CDATA[Future Plan































                               Figure 183. The future plan of the College of Nursing.




                               The  Cavite  State  University  Bachelor  of  Science  in  Nursing  program


                       continuous  efforts  to  maintain  the  character  of  providing  quality  nursing

                       education  are  directed  towards  the  aspiration  to  be  one  of  the  Center  of


                       Excellence  or  Development  recognized  by  Commission  of  Higher  Education.

                       Moreover, the College of Nursing envision the offering of graduate program such


                       as  Master  of  Science  in  Nursing  to  cater  nurses  in  their  further  professional

                       development.


                                In the light of the ongoing changes, and in the face of the ongoing Covid-

                         19 pandemic, the motivation for nurses to pursue higher education is stronger


                         than ever. Technology is ever-present in the modern world of health care, and

                         the  pace  of  reliance  on  technology  has  continued  to  increase  during  the



                                                                                                          161]]></page><page Index="163"><![CDATA[pandemic  period.  The  world  population  is  becoming  increasingly  diverse.

                         Bilingualism is becoming increasingly valued as a skill for nurses to have. With


                         such strong evidence that more education leads to better patient outcomes and

                         nursing degrees trending upward, expect higher education to become the norm


                         for Registered Nurses moving into this year and beyond.





















































                              Figure  184.  The  College  of  Nursing  grounds  and  building  as  the  only
                              institution that offers free nursing in the province of Cavute in accordance
                              with RA 10931.





                                                                                                          162]]></page><page Index="164"><![CDATA[The Bachelor of Science in Nursing in Cavite State University remains to

                       be the most affordable nursing education in the province and the region.  CvSU


                       is the only state university in the province and one of the few from the region that

                       offer free tuition to all deserving students with the implementation of the Universal


                       Access to Quality Tertiary Education Act also known as the Republic Act 10931.

                              Internationalization of the College of Nursing education is expected to lead


                       to  greater  cross-cultural  understanding  and  improved  practices  in  workplaces

                       around the world. It is stated that exchange programs serve to develop cultural


                       competence,  like  an  increased  ability  as  nursing  students,  nursing  clinical

                       instructors, or as a nurse to care for patients from different cultures and work in


                       different countries. Furthermore, it is the future plan of the CoN for their students

                       to carry out part of their education abroad, considered that this experience had

                       contributed positively to their competence development such as communication,


                       leadership,  organization,  critical  thinking,  specific  situations,  and  stress

                       management.


                              The BS Nursing program is in transition citing the need for flexibility and

                       greater effectiveness. As we go forward, we ensure that our firm foundation of


                       excellence in curriculum will continue guided by the university’s mission and vision.




















                                                                                                          163]]></page></pages></Search>